<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Youtube</title><link>https://konrad.website/feeds/</link><description></description><item><title>Relatable Millennial Horror Story #monster #gaming #horror</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/jlb0wjEnn8Q</link><author>IcarusLIVES</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/jlb0wjEnn8Q?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:21:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgp_adxCQiesfxKYIqIE9yQ">IcarusLIVES</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Step away from the shelf and leave me at least one Mango Loco flavor Monster please. I need it to live.

Official ProtonVPN Partner - https://go.getproton.me/SH1mq

▬ Socials  ▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬
Twitch        ► www.twitch.tv/mr_icarus/
Bluesky        ► mistericarus.bsky.social
Patreon      ► www.patreon.com/MrIcarus
Bandcamp ► icarusliv3s.bandcamp.com/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Everything You Need to Know: Liquidators</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eF-KSUfnbhg</link><author>Megaprojects</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/eF-KSUfnbhg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:50:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0woBco6Dgcxt0h8SwyyOmw">Megaprojects</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get your copy of The Book: The Ultimate Guide to Rebuilding Civilization for yourself or as a Christmas gift for someone you love. Use my Promo Code MEGA10 for a special discount. Shop Now: https://bit.ly/44yTveO

Got a beard? Good. I've got something for you: http://beardblaze.com

Simon's Social Media:
Twitter: https://twitter.com/SimonWhistler
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/simonwhistler/

This video is #sponsored by Hungry Minds.

Love content? Check out Simon's other YouTube Channels:


Warfronts: https://www.youtube.com/@warographics643
SideProjects: https://www.youtube.com/@Sideprojects
Into The Shadows: https://www.youtube.com/@IntotheShadows
Today I Found Out: https://www.youtube.com/@TodayIFoundOut
Highlight History: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnb-VTwBHEV3gtiB9di9DZQ
Brain Blaze: https://www.youtube.com/@brainblaze6526
Casual Criminalist: https://www.youtube.com/@TheCasualCriminalist
Decoding the Unknown: https://www.youtube.com/@decodingtheunknown2373
Places: https://www.youtube.com/@Places302
Celestium: https://www.youtube.com/@astrographics-ve4yq
PoliticalFronts: http://www.youtube.com/@politicalfronts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We Found the Rarest Battle of Trafalgar Artefacts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K2DEBxvHcLs</link><author>History Hit</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/K2DEBxvHcLs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ">History Hit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Luke Tomes gets special access to a selection of incredible artefacts related to British hero Vice-Admiral Lord Horatio Nelson, including a part of the white ensign flown by HMS Victory at the Battle of Trafalgar in 1805, a lock of hair taken from his Nelson’s pigtail and presented to Captain Hardy, a front page newspaper headline ‘extraordinary’ reporting on the death of Nelson in 1805 and an original architectural plan of Nelson’s Column in Trafalgar Square dating to 1843.

Special thanks to Charles Miller Ltd. For more information about these and other items check out the Charles Miller Ltd website:  https://www.charlesmillerltd.com/ the auction takes place on Tuesday 20 January from 2pm GMT (UK time), you can follow the action here: 

https://www.charlesmillerltd.com/auction/search/?au=65

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world-renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.

Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ/join

#nelson #hmsvictory #trafalgar 

00:00 Introduction
00:59 Battle of Trafalgar Flag (White Ensign)
05:43 Nelson Death Letter
08:39 Newspaper Headline (Nelson Death)
11:47 Lord Nelson's Hair 
15:46 State Funeral Painting
19:37 Nelson's Column Architectural Designs]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What If You Keep Slowing Down?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P-4pbFcERnk</link><author>Veritasium</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/P-4pbFcERnk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:53:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA">Veritasium</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[What happens if you keep slowing down time? Sponsored by Hostinger - Make today your Day One and visit https://ve42.co/VE10. Use code VERITASIUM for an additional discount.

▀▀▀
0:00 How does a strobe work?
3:28 The Man Who Stopped Time
8:43 Spatial vs Temporal Resolution
13:09 1 Trillion FPS
16:56 Watching Light Move
19:04 The Straightest Building in the World
24:19 How to get 1 Quadrillion FPS
28:25 Seeing Electrons

▀▀▀
A huge thank you to Jim Bales, Kim Vandiver, Jamie Chelel and everyone at the MIT Edgerton Center for walking us through Edgerton’s demos - https://ve42.co/EdgertonC

Thank you to Tech Imaging for letting us use their Photron Nova S16 high-speed video camera - https://ve42.co/TechImg

A massive thank you Nikhil Behari, Ramesh Raskar and MIT’s Camera Culture Group for having us over - https://ve42.co/CameraCulture

Check out Prof Raskar’s original trillion FPS coke bottle video here - Visualizing video at the speed of light — one trillion frames per second

A big thank you to Anagh Malik and the University of Toronto Computational Imaging Group. 
Check out Anagh’s work here - https://ve42.co/Malik2024

Finally, a huge thank you to Aaron Groff, James Cryan and everyone at SLAC for letting us visit their electron accelerator - https://ve42.co/SLAC

The paper on the final charge density simulation is available here - https://ve42.co/Grell2023

Check out the AlphaPhoenix billion FPS camera here - https://youtu.be/IaXdSGkh8Ww

▀▀▀
References: https://ve42.co/StoppingTimeRefs

Visual References: 

Edgerton images courtesy of © 2010 MIT. Courtesy of MIT Museum - https://ve42.co/MITMus
Bullet Shadowgram available via CC-BY-SA-3.0 on Wikipedia - https://ve42.co/Shadowgram
Various SLAC shots via - https://www.youtube.com/@SLAC

▀▀▀
Special thanks to our Patreon supporters:

Adam Foreman, Albert Wenger, Alex Porter, Alexander Tamas, Anton Ragin, armedtoe, Balkrishna Heroor, Bertrand Serlet, Blake Byers, Bruce, Data Don, Dave Kircher, David Johnston, David Tseng, EJ Alexandra, Evgeny Skvortsov, Garrett Mueller, Gnare, gpoly, Hayden Christensen, Ibby Hadeed, Jeromy Johnson, Jesse Brandson, Jon Jamison, Juan Benet, KeyWestr, Kyi, Lee Redden, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Mark Heising, Marti  Paull, Meekay, meg noah, Michael Bush, Michael Krugman, Moebiusol - Cristian, Orlando Bassotto, Paul Peijzel, Richard Sundvall, Robson, Sam Lufti, Shalva Bukia, Sinan Taifour, Tj Steyn, Ubiquity Ventures, Vahe Andonians, wolfee

▀▀▀
Writers: Gregor Čavlović, Casper Mebius & Derek Muller
Producer & Director: Gregor Čavlović
Presenter: Gregor Čavlović
Editors: Jack Saxon, Peter Nelson & Trenton Oliver
Additional Editors: James Stuart & James Horsley
Animators: Mike Radjabov, Fabio Albertelli, Andrew Neet, Emma Wright & Rokas Viksraitis
Illustrators: Jakub Misiek, Kathryn Chan, Grace Nemanic, Nataly Zhuk & Isaac McRee
Camera Operators: Michael Cimpher, Jesse Chandler & Gregor Čavlović
Researcher: Aakash Singh Bagga & Gabe Strong
Thumbnail Designers: Abdallah Rabah, Ren Hurley & Ben Powell
Production Team: Josh Pitt, Matthew Cavanagh, Anna Milkovic, Gabe Strong, Sulli Yost & Katy Southwood
Executive Producers: Casper Mebius & Derek Muller

Additional video/photos supplied by Getty Images, Storyblocks
Music from Epidemic Sound]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Where Did the Hollywood “Silencer” Sound Effect Come From? 🎬🔫#MovieMyths #FilmSound #History</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/MbH3LQMbjps</link><author>Royal Armouries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/MbH3LQMbjps?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:52:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsMX-XuiEkBi4-GDrYuniWg">Royal Armouries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Where did the classic Hollywood “silencer” sound actually come from?

For decades, films trained audiences to expect the familiar pew-pew noise but watch as Jonathan and Star Wars Sound Designer Ben Burtt reveal all...

Taken from our 'The Origin of the Hollywood Silencer with Jonathan Ferguson & Star Wars Sound Designer Ben Burtt' What is this Weapon Episode.

#WhatIsThisWeapon #HollywoodHistory #SoundDesign #Suppressors #RoyalArmouries

Subscribe to our channel for more videos about arms and armour  

Help us bring history to life by supporting us here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/donations/

Sign up to our museum membership scheme here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/membership/ 

⚔Website: https://royalarmouries.org/home
⚔Blog: https://royalarmouries.org/stories/
⚔Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/RoyalArmouriesMuseum/
⚔Twitter: https://twitter.com/Royal_Armouries
⚔ Instagram: http://instagram.com/royalarmouriesmuseum

We are the Royal Armouries, the United Kingdom's national collection of arms and armour. Discover what goes on behind the scenes and watch our collection come to life. See combat demonstrations, experience jousting and meet our experts. 

Have a question about arms and armour? Feel free to leave us a comment and we'll do our best to answer it.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>CALL OF THE VOID GOT A MAP JAM - QUAKE MOD MADNESS LIVE</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aOedMRP-DRE</link><author>IcarusLIVES</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/aOedMRP-DRE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:44:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgp_adxCQiesfxKYIqIE9yQ">IcarusLIVES</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Mmm, Strogg flavoured.

Want to annoy Icarus? Luxury Harrasment options available @ tangia.co/mr_icarus

Official ProtonVPN Partner - https://go.getproton.me/SH1mq

Find me elsewhere on the net:
Twitch        ► twitch.tv/mr_icarus/
Bluesky        ► mistericarus.bsky.social
Patreon      ► patreon.com/MrIcarus
Bandcamp ► icarusliv3s.bandcamp.com/

#quake #quake2 #mods #modding #modded #gaming #games #recommended]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Serverless &amp; Agentic AI: Better Together • Prashanth HN • GOTO 2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FmmKRkUverw</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FmmKRkUverw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This presentation was recorded at GOTO Serverless 2025. #GOTOcon #GOTOserverless
https://conferences.gotopia.tech/goto-serverless-bengaluru-2025

Prashanth HN - CTO and Co-Founder at AntStack & AWS Serverless Hero

RESOURCES
https://www.linkedin.com/in/hnprashanth

ABSTRACT
Agents are changing the way GenAI applications are built and has become a fundamental building block between data & LLMs. With a widely accepted standard like MCP, it is set to take off exponentially in the coming months/years. Agents by design are event-driven and are naturally fit into Serverless architecture.

In this session we explore how Serverless can be a huge part of empowering the upcoming Agentic revolution & why this combination is such a killer! [...]

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
00:40 What is an agent?
04:26 Events
05:48 LLM inference
06:29 Agents/Tools/MCP
07:33 Data
08:46 Agentic RAG
10:06 Swarm
11:11 Agent orchestration
14:10 Outro

Download slides and read the full abstract here:
https://conferences.gotopia.tech/goto-serverless-bengaluru-2025/sessions/3847

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Peter Sbarski • Serverless Architectures on AWS • https://amzn.to/3hJzEUM
Michael Stack • Event-Driven Architecture in Golang • https://amzn.to/3G5e8ST
Ashley Peacock • Serverless Apps on Cloudflare • https://amzn.to/3EU7P85
Jeroen Mulder • Multi-Cloud Strategy for Cloud Architects • https://amzn.to/3FdNDOA

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#DevEx #Serverless #AWSServerless #AgenticAI #PrashanthHN #AWSBedrock #AWSSageMaker #LLMInference #TodayInTech #GOTO #AgenticRAG #RAG

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>CALL OF THE VOID GOT A MAP JAM - QUAKE MOD MADNESS LIVE</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w9WwbcLxe8w</link><author>IcarusLIVES</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/w9WwbcLxe8w?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:27:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgp_adxCQiesfxKYIqIE9yQ">IcarusLIVES</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Mmm, Strogg flavoured.

Want to annoy Icarus? Luxury Harrasment options available @ tangia.co/mr_icarus

Official ProtonVPN Partner - https://go.getproton.me/SH1mq

Find me elsewhere on the net:
Twitch        ► twitch.tv/mr_icarus/
Bluesky        ► mistericarus.bsky.social
Patreon      ► patreon.com/MrIcarus
Bandcamp ► icarusliv3s.bandcamp.com/

#quake #quake2 #mods #modding #modded #gaming #games #recommended]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>corrupt pardons corrode trust</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0ydymkrshVc</link><author>voidzilla</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0ydymkrshVc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 03:27:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC28n0tlcNSa1iPe5mettocg">voidzilla</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[bloomberg original story: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xq4x6uVNiM4&t=80s&pp=ygUXZWxpIHdlaW5zdGVpbiBibG9vbWJlcmc%3D
support: https://www.patreon.com/coffeezilla

disclaimer (updated May 2025): voidzilla is an opinion‑driven channel that comments on the news of the day under the satirical and rhetorically hyperbolic banner “CRIME IS LEGAL.” the phrase critiques what we see as a lax or uneven regulatory enforcement environment for fraud. unlike our affiliated channel Coffeezilla, which conducts detailed investigations and source‑document deep dives, and draws opinions from that, voidzilla offers rapid‑fire commentary and criticism on information already in the public domain. statements here reflect the host’s views at the moment of recording and may become outdated as facts evolve. references to “crime,” “fraud,” “scam,” or similar terms appear in a rhetorical hyperbolic context similar to “CRIME IS LEGAL.” unless we expressly state that a court has entered a final judgment, no segment should be read as a definitive finding of legal liability. viewers are urged to consult primary sources and form independent conclusions. production of this program is public‑interest commentary protected by the First Amendment and the Texas Citizens Participation Act (TCPA). 

anyone featured in this program who believes a material error has occured may contact our business email with supporting documentation under the SUBJECT: "CORRECTION REQUEST". we will promptly review substantiated notices and, where appropriate, issue corrections or updates.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>&quot;Will No One Rid Me of This Turbulent Priest?&quot;: Trump’s Fed War</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QXUQ7PzuIe0</link><author>Patrick Boyle</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/QXUQ7PzuIe0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 20:00:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCASM0cgfkJxQ1ICmRilfHLw">Patrick Boyle</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[If you are curious and want to try it yourself, Tailor Store is offering 25% off your order for my viewers. Use my link https://www.tailorstore.com/patrickboyle so you can take a look whenever it suits you.

In a highly unusual move - the Department of Justice has opened a criminal investigation into Federal Reserve chair Jerome Powell. As America faces a high-stakes standoff over the future of the Federal Reserve, the traditional independence of the nation’s central bank is under direct attack. This video explores the intensifying war between the White House and Fed Chair, over a $2.5 billion headquarters renovation. We break down why many experts believe this probe is a mere pretext intended to bully the Fed into slashing interest rates to rock-bottom levels, potentially putting the long-term stability of the U.S. economy at risk for short-term political gains.

We also take a closer look at the "agents of chaos" Bill Pulte, Judge Jeanine Pirro and the "shadow" economic strategies currently in play, from the FHFA’s controversial bond-buying programs to the proposed 10% cap on credit card interest rates. From the strategic blockade in the Senate by Senator Thom Tillis to the "Miran Limbo" on the Fed’s Board of Governors, we unpack the technical and political maneuvers being used to bypass Jerome Powell. Is the U.S. headed toward a "banana republic" risk premium, or can its institutional guardrails hold firm? Join us as we examine the true price of a political Fed and what it means for the future of the dollar.

Patrick's Books:
Statistics For The Trading Floor:  https://amzn.to/3eerLA0
Derivatives For The Trading Floor:  https://amzn.to/3cjsyPF
Corporate Finance:  https://amzn.to/3fn3rvC 

Ways To Support The Channel
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/PatrickBoyleOnFinance
Buy Me a Coffee: https://www.buymeacoffee.com/patrickboyle

Visit our website: https://www.onfinance.org
Follow Patrick on Twitter Here: https://bsky.app/profile/pboyle.bsky.social

Business Inquiries ➡️ sponsors@onfinance.org

Patrick Boyle On Finance Podcast:
Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/7uhrWlDvxzy9hLoW0EYf0b
Apple: https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/patrick-boyle-on-finance/id1547740313
Google Podcasts: https://tinyurl.com/62862nve

Join this channel to support making this content:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCASM0cgfkJxQ1ICmRilfHLw/join]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What the Minneapolis ICE Shooting Means for Law Enforcement</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/3r_Wl-rw8pU</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/3r_Wl-rw8pU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 18:00:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">The Wall Street Journal</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The surge of federal agents conducting immigration enforcement operations has sparked widespread resistance from local law enforcement and community groups. 

#Minneapolis #ICE #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Urban foraging for food - Fresh, tasty and free | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0CgDnsOBVm8</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0CgDnsOBVm8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:00:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[More and more city dwellers are collecting food in the asphalt jungle. They harvest herbs by the roadside and grow wild vegetables in cracks in the concrete. For these modern foragers and hunters, the food is free, tasty and more varied than in the supermarket.

Christian Amys is an urban foraging professional. He forages for fresh food in his hometown of Brighton. For him, the English coastal city is an urban Garden of Eden. Christian finds wild vegetables and herbs in places where most people would never expect to find food. The 42-year-old only spends a few pounds a week on food from the supermarket: "I want to be independent and don't like to rely on the supermarket. I like to forage on my doorstep because it's nice to know where my food comes from."

Christian Amys worked as a top chef for 20 years before becoming an urban forager. Today, he shows others where to find wild fennel, hogweed, pineapple weed and dandelion heads and how to use them in food preparation. Christian now even supplies top restaurants and cocktail bars with his wild delicacies.

Alexis Goertz also looks for her food on the roadside and in parks. The Canadian has lived in Berlin for over 10 years. She preserves what she collects using the centuries-old technique of fermentation. Whether it's evening primrose capers, wild garlic kimchi or goutweed sauerkraut - for Alexis, fermentation is about more than just preservation: "Above all, fermentation makes food tastier and easier to digest. And I've just become addicted to it."

Alexis regularly invites people to join her on urban herb walks and explains what’s edible - and what’s poisonous. The 33-year-old is all about rediscovering nature in the city: "Berlin is fantastic for foraging for food. The diversity is immense. Not just among the people, but also in nature."

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #urbanforaging #food 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Heated Rivalry’s sex scenes were made #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/guf03WQt7Q4</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/guf03WQt7Q4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:01:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Vox</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[If you’ve watched Heated Rivalry, you know how spicy the sex scenes get in the hockey player romance. 👀🥵 But how do these scenes come to be? The show’s intimacy coordinator, Chala Hunter, sat down with Explain It to Me host Jonquilyn Hill to discuss what went into filming the show’s most intimate moments.

For more of this episode of Explain It to Me, listen wherever you get your podcasts.

Subscribe to our channel and turn on notifications (🔔) so you don't miss any videos: http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on TikTok: http://tiktok.com/@voxdotcom
Check out our articles: https://www.vox.com/
Listen to our podcasts: https://www.vox.com/podcasts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>This Billionaire Ranks Life Scenarios Based on Luck or Skill | The WSJ Money Interview</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WH5WMwlGNQI</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/WH5WMwlGNQI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:00:50 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">The Wall Street Journal</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Getting laid off, starting a company, going viral — are these things driven by luck...or skill? Billionaire Kenn Ricci, the chairman of Flexjet, has had his fair share of ups and downs over the course of his career. In our first episode of The WSJ Money Interview, Gunjan Banerji put his business smarts to the test.

Chapters:
0:00 Selling a company
1:23 Why you terminated the deal to go public
2:42 Getting laid off
3:42 Marrying the right person
4:54 Going viral 
5:20 Getting a promotion at work 
6:03 Starting a successful business 

Subscribers get access to full-length episodes of WSJ’s The Money Interview, plus the chance to have their questions answered by our millionaire guest. Watch the full series here: https://on.wsj.com/3ZauOly 

WSJ The Money Interview
What can some of the world’s most interesting tycoons teach us about ambition and wealth? WSJ’s Gunjan Banerji sits down with highfliers for a candid conversation about how they made it.

#Wealth #Business #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Everything You Weren&apos;t Taught About Shakespeare</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9YgVk-O20Iw</link><author>Weird History</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9YgVk-O20Iw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCc-N24Y5OA0gqbjBwe1ttfA">Weird History</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[William Shakespeare’s plays have shaped the English language, defined genres, and given high-schoolers panic attacks over pop quizzes for centuries. Yet for a guy who invented, like, half the metaphors we use to flirt, we know shockingly little about his personal life. What do YOU know about William Shakespear? Let us know in the comments!

Be sure to subscribe to the Weird History Newsletter: https://bit.ly/WeirdHistoryNews

#shakespeare #williamshakespeare]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Can science create the perfect meal? | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/e9EdN4424Pg</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/e9EdN4424Pg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:01:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Mediterranean diet is known around the world for its health benefits and was acknowledged as an intangible cultural heritage in 2010 by UNESCO. This diet consists mainly of plant-based ingredients like vegetables, whole grains, nuts, and fruits with a moderate amount of fish and dairy products.  

The food we eat has a big influence on our health as it is one of the leading causes of chronic diseases. According to the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), nearly half of all American adults now live with diet-related chronic diseases.   

More than half the average diet in the U.S. now consists of ultra-processed food. But for some younger, lower-income communities, ultra-processed food can typically make up as much as 80% of their diet. 

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #mediterraneandiet 
______

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How the Girl Scouts of America were Accused of being Communists</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QvgEHc0iyoQ</link><author>The Cold War</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/QvgEHc0iyoQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCCGvq-qmjFmmMD4e-PLQqGg">The Cold War</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Our historical documentary series on the history of the Cold War continues with a video looking at the heightened anti-communist paranoia on the early 1950s and how it led to the Girl Scouts of America being accused of promoting communism.

ASALA, Armenia Secret Army: https://youtu.be/DFzIVfTNjH0
Amchitka Island Nuclear Test: https://youtu.be/Z89YnSS5RQA
Soviet Criminal Underworld: https://youtu.be/zEJrivfLKGc
Project Iceworm: Nukes Under the Ice: https://youtu.be/ePT8gp0LKsk
Haiti and the Dominican Republic: https://youtu.be/apgYxvtDFQY
Red Army Faction: https://youtu.be/wgYfTQJYCkI
Colonial Indochina to 1945: https://youtu.be/uijOG8oYHgo
First Indochina War pt. 1 GUERILLA: https://youtu.be/V9wSqx0W8h0
First Indochina War pt. 2 INTERNATIONALIZATION: https://youtu.be/58PAc7zAtSg
Alcohol Prohibition in the USSR https://youtu.be/kyPdGderIxk
Cocaine and Cartels: https://youtu.be/A9VA51N-Ug4
International Terrorism: https://youtu.be/VqHMjA35aLM
Liberation Theology: https://youtu.be/Dfu2I_LTKt4
Iranian Nuclear Program: https://youtu.be/ZrNNeS31lNg
Angela Davis: https://youtu.be/VMzpkYg6wOY
The School of the Americas: https://youtu.be/3tYwj-7b_jU
Birth of the Military Industrial Complex: https://youtu.be/8glmBbBENlk
America's Secret Nuclear Disaster: https://youtu.be/iXSSCdlTst4
How Nuclear Deterrence Theory developed: https://youtu.be/UHIsdbvsuOY
How the American Political Parties Switched Their Ideologies https://youtu.be/SdcreXEWzG0
How the RAND Corporation created American strategy: https://youtu.be/J1mH_O7MzJk
The Nuclear Wannabes: Sweden, Brazil and Argentina: https://youtu.be/1LpL6Q1s7TA
Israel: the Officially Unofficial Nuclear State: https://youtu.be/dcXSkpRDp2k
Taiwan Under the Kuomintang Dictatorship: https://youtu.be/nGYzXNpQclo
What Happened to the German and Japanese POWs?: https://youtu.be/JLK1xQV9B84
German Expulsions: https://youtu.be/zyWx4p4hiaY
Soviet Education System: https://youtu.be/AD_JwbivtMA
How Khrushchev Fed the Soviet People: https://youtu.be/qIZDa7ZcUhE

Support us on Patreon: http://www.patreon.com/TheColdWar, 
Youtube membership https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCCGvq-qmjFmmMD4e-PLQqGg/join

✔ Merch store ► https://teespring.com/stores/thecoldwar
✔ Patreon ► https://www.patreon.com/thecoldwar
✔ Facebook ► https://www.facebook.com/thecoldwartv
✔ Instagram ►http://www.instagram.com/thecoldwartv

#ColdWar #ColdWarHistory #History #ModernHistory #GirlScouts #Scouts #GirlscoutsUSA #Communism #mccarthyism #1950s 

**SOURCES**
https://www.loc.gov/exhibits/herblocks-history/fire.html
https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/1955/05/what-happened-to-the-girl-scouts/306925/
https://estes-kefauver.com/2025/02/10/red-and-green-dont-mix-when-the-american-legion-declared-war-on-the-girl-scouts
https://www.loc.gov/exhibits/herblocks-history/fire.html#:~:text=%22Stand%20fast%2C%20men%20,armed%20with%20marshmallows
https://perso.univ-lyon2.fr/~jkempf/girl_scouts.pdf
https://openlibrary.org/books/OL54439279M/Training_girls_for_needs_today
https://archive.org/details/girlscouthandboo0000juli
https://exhibits.tufts.edu/spotlight/girls-books/catalog/32-2375
https://daily.jstor.org/when-the-girl-scouts-were-accused-of-being-commies/
https://gshistory.com/2014/05/09/the-girl-scout-red-scare-part-two\
https://www2.gwu.edu/~erpapers/myday/displaydoc.cfm?_y=1954&_f=md002930
https://www.publishersweekly.com/9781469686837
https://www.cia.gov/readingroom/docs/CIA-RDP70-00058R000300020032-1.pdf
https://www.jstor.org/stable/pdf/community.41105793.pdf?acceptTC=true&coverpage=false&addFooter=false]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>they&apos;re literally covering up the epstein files</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wxszxvwOhtY</link><author>voidzilla</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wxszxvwOhtY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 07:06:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC28n0tlcNSa1iPe5mettocg">voidzilla</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[support: https://www.patreon.com/coffeezilla

disclaimer (updated May 2025): voidzilla is an opinion‑driven channel that comments on the news of the day under the satirical and rhetorically hyperbolic banner “CRIME IS LEGAL.” the phrase critiques what we see as a lax or uneven regulatory enforcement environment for fraud. unlike our affiliated channel Coffeezilla, which conducts detailed investigations and source‑document deep dives, and draws opinions from that, voidzilla offers rapid‑fire commentary and criticism on information already in the public domain. statements here reflect the host’s views at the moment of recording and may become outdated as facts evolve. references to “crime,” “fraud,” “scam,” or similar terms appear in a rhetorical hyperbolic context similar to “CRIME IS LEGAL.” unless we expressly state that a court has entered a final judgment, no segment should be read as a definitive finding of legal liability. viewers are urged to consult primary sources and form independent conclusions. production of this program is public‑interest commentary protected by the First Amendment and the Texas Citizens Participation Act (TCPA). 

anyone featured in this program who believes a material error has occured may contact our business email with supporting documentation under the SUBJECT: "CORRECTION REQUEST". we will promptly review substantiated notices and, where appropriate, issue corrections or updates.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>I Switched to French for This Episode (New Year Special) | How to make a creme frangipane</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PhgV3J4tDfU</link><author>French Cooking Academy</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/PhgV3J4tDfU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:09:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0lG3Ihe4LGV851lODRIS5g">French Cooking Academy</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Bonjour à tous les gourmands ! Pour bien démarrer l'année 2026, je vous propose un épisode spécial et 100% en français de la French Cooking Academy,  pour vous emmener dans l'univers de la pâtisserie française. Aujourd'hui, on s'attaque à un classique indémodable : la crème frangipane, le cœur de notre célèbre Galette des Rois ! 👑

🌟 Key Ingredients | Les Ingrédients Clés 🌟

🥛 For the Pastry Cream (Crème Pâtissière)
200 ml whole milk 🥛
2 egg yolks 🥚
50 g sugar
10 g cornstarch (Maïzena)
10 g plain flour
1/2 vanilla bean (or 1 tsp vanilla extract for ease!) ✨
Kirsch (optional, for that unique aromatic touch!) 🍒

🧈 For the Almond Cream (Crème d’Amande)
100 g soft butter (room temperature, like a pomade) 🧈
100 g sugar
100 g eggs (about 2 medium, room temperature) 🥚
100 g ground almonds / almond meal 🌰
A few drops of bitter almond extract (this stuff is potent, use sparingly!)
1 tsp flour (optional, for extra stability)

🌰 The Almond Cream Secrets | Les Secrets de la Crème d’Amande 🤫
3 Golden Rules for Perfection!
Temperature is Key! 🌡️ Make sure both your butter and eggs are at room temperature. This is crucial for a smooth emulsion!
Cream it Right! Start by creaming the soft butter until pale. Then, gradually beat in the sugar, followed by the eggs, little by little. Get ready for a beautifully smooth mix! 🥣
Fold Gently! Gently fold in your sifted almond meal and those precious drops of bitter almond extract. Don't overmix!
Chill Out! Pop it in the fridge to chill until you're ready to assemble. 

👑 Assembly & Baking | Assemblage & Cuisson 👑
It's time to bring it all together for your masterpiece!
Loosen Up! Take your cold pastry cream and loosen it with a splash of Kirsch. Then, gently fold it into your almond cream until everything is beautifully combined. Voilà, your frangipane is ready!
Fill & Seal! Grab your puff pastry, generously fill it with the frangipane (psst... don't forget the fève if you're making a real Galette des Rois! ). Then, seal those edges really well to keep all that deliciousness inside!

Final touches: 
 Give your creation a beautiful egg wash for that golden shine, decorate as you like, and then let it rest in the fridge for 20 minutes. This helps the pastry hold its shape! ✨
Bake to Perfection! Preheat your oven to a hot 200 °C / 390 °F and bake for 30–40 minutes until deeply golden brown and puffed up! Keep an eye on it! oven

Même si ma galette a eu un petit "accident" esthétique (trop généreux en crème !), le goût est DIVIN ! Ne vous inquiétez pas si la vôtre n'est pas parfaite, l'important c'est le plaisir ! 😋

00:00 Introduction to the episode in French.
03:03 Presentation of the necessary equipment.
04:01 Ingredients for the almond cream.
04:28 Ingredients for the pastry cream.
05:10 How to prepare the pastry cream.
09:18 Cooling of the pastry cream.
10:15 Preparation of the almond cream.
12:34 Incorporation of the almond powder.
13:36 Final assembly of the frangipane cream.
15:09 Dressing and baking of the cake.
20:18 Tasting and conclusion.


#galettedesrois #frangipane #recettefacile #patisseriefrancaise #cremedamande #cremepatissiere #faitmaison #frenchcookingacademy 


SUPPORT US ON PATREON ❤️
Your support helps us keep creating these free video lessons for everyone to enjoy. 
► https://www.patreon.com/frenchcookingacademy

STAY IN TOUCH ✉️
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/french_cooking_academy
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/FrenchCookingAcademy
We love hearing from you! If you have any questions about this recipe, please leave them in the comments below.

ABOUT THE FRENCH COOKING ACADEMY 👨‍🍳
We believe that the joys of French cuisine should be accessible to everyone. Our channel is dedicated to teaching classic recipes and foundational techniques in a clear and approachable way, so you can create restaurant-quality meals for your friends and family. Subscribe and join us on this delicious journey!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Martin Luther King Jr. - The Dream That Changed America Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5ED7aZBVhoE</link><author>The People Profiles</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5ED7aZBVhoE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 22:58:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCD6TPU-PvTMvqgzC_AM7_uA">The People Profiles</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[To purchase your copy of The Book, follow this link https://mdsh.io/peopleprofiles
to get a discount on your copy with our promo code PEOPLEPROFILES10.

Martin Luther King Jr. was one of the most important leaders in modern history. In this full biography documentary, we explore the life, legacy and assassination of Martin Luther King Jr., the most famous voice of the American civil rights movement. 

From his childhood in segregated America to his rise as a Baptist minister, civil rights leader and Nobel Peace Prize winner, this video tells the complete story of Martin Luther King Jr.
Discover how MLK led the Montgomery Bus Boycott, the Birmingham Campaign and the March on Washington, where he delivered the iconic “I Have a Dream” speech. We examine his philosophy of nonviolent protest, his relationship with other civil rights activists, and his battles against racism, segregation and injustice in the United States.

This Martin Luther King Jr. documentary also looks at the FBI surveillance of MLK, the events leading to his assassination in Memphis in 1968, and the impact of his death on American history and the global struggle for civil rights and equality.

If you’re interested in history documentaries, civil rights, Black history and the life of Martin Luther King Jr., this in-depth biography is for you.

Please subscribe here. https://www.youtube.com/@PeopleProfiles?sub_confirmation=1
Our second channel. https://www.youtube.com/@PeopleProfilesExtra
Follow us on Spotify. https://open.spotify.com/show/7fKALbrzEO9Q4VVvAwWHqL
Support us on Patreon https://patreon.com/thepeopleprofiles
Follow us on Twitter. https://twitter.com/tpprofiles

Thanks for watching! If you liked this video, check out our related videos below:
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLNwBhP0rWSz1EQOUiCo2hOzXogNU5psT8
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLNwBhP0rWSz0vPvWecG4EPQIWEIh34K-X
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLNwBhP0rWSz3l1yKTFKS6b3GPniSWVpmX

All footage, images and music used in People Profiles videos are sourced from free media websites or are purchased with commercial rights from online media archives.

All People Profiles scripts are researched and written by qualified Historians. The script for this video has been checked with Plagiarism and AI Detector software and scored 3% on Scribbr. In academia, a score of below 15% is considered good or acceptable. 

No AI is used during the writing process of People Profiles videos, which are narrated by human voice over artists. Please see the end credits of our videos for details and contact us for script references.

#peopleprofiles  #history  #biography]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Building Angkor | Cambodian History | Extra History Complete</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7GQC66Jtqs</link><author>Extra History</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/x7GQC66Jtqs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:29:54 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCCODtTcd5M1JavPCOr_Uydg">Extra History</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[📚  When you're done learning about Building Angkor, head over to the Angelarium store at https://angelarium.shop/ and get 20% off everything by using code 'EXTRAHISTORY'!

Angkor was once the largest city of the medieval world, home to nearly a million people, and at its center stood Angkor Wat, one of the most ambitious architectural projects in human history. In this episode, we explore how Angkor rose under kings like Suryavarman II and Jayavarman VII, how its vast temples, cities, and water systems were built, and what ultimately led to its collapse. From religious fusion and monumental engineering to climate disaster, invasion, and mythmaking, this is the story of how a thriving metropolis became one of the world’s most iconic ruins and a lasting symbol of Cambodia.

We really enjoyed revisiting this series and getting to implement the viewer feedback that Rob had previously only been able to address in Lies. Original Lies video here: https://youtu.be/dDH3TN5xdyY

* Watch Extra History ad-free & get 1-week early access on *NEBULA* https://go.nebula.tv/extrahistory 
* Suggest & Vote on our next episodes, get exclusive content & 24-hour early access on *PATREON* https://bit.ly/EHPatreon   
* Show off your fandom with *MERCH* from our store! http://extracredits.store/  
* Interested in sponsoring an episode?* Email us: extracredits@standard.tv 

https://twitter.com/extracreditz | https://www.facebook.com/ExtraCredits/ | http://instagram.com/extracredits | https://www.tiktok.com/@extracreditz
GAMING: https://www.youtube.com/@extracredits | http://www.twitch.tv/extracredits/
https://bsky.app/profile/extracredits.bsky.social 

CHAPTERS
00:00 - Building Angkor Wat
01:20 - Chapter 1: Monsoon Metropolis
10:24 - Chapter 2: Temple City
19:45 - Chapter 3: A Clash of Gods
28:41 - Chapter 4: A Drowning City 
38:25 - Chapter 5: The "Lost" City

Thanks for the high-quality conversations & for following our community guidelines here: https://bit.ly/ECFansRNice

Artist: Nick DeWitt  | Writer: Robert Rath | Showrunner & Narrator: Matthew Krol | Video Editor:  Devon House Creative | Audio Editor: Clean Waves | Studio Director: Geoffrey Zatkin | Social Media: Kat Rider | ♪ "Nokor Thom" by: Tiffany Roman

#ExtraHistory #Cambodia #History]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Flight MH17 - Anatomy of a crash | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gLduXlInW-0</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/gLduXlInW-0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:00:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In the summer of 2014, fields and coal mines in eastern Ukraine became a crime scene. The wreckage of Malaysia Airlines Flight 17 was scattered across 12 square kilometers. Evidence of a war crime that remains unpunished to this day.

On July 17, 2014, the Malaysian Boeing 777 with flight number MH17 was en route from Amsterdam to Kuala Lumpur, carrying 283 passengers and 15 crew members. The plane was shot down by a Russian BUK missile as it flew over eastern Ukraine, where war broke out in 2014. 

This documentary reflects on the tragedy of MH17. The film consists of archive material, intercepted telephone conversations, open-source material, excerpts from television broadcasts, and staged fictional episodes. By combining different materials into a comprehensive collage, the film sheds light on the crash and examines the connections between propaganda, justice, punishment, and the far-reaching consequences of actions. 

While the film revolves around the story of MH17, it also approaches the subject on a very personal level — including a meeting with a Dutch relative of one of the victims on the plane. By making connections to what is happening in Ukraine today, the film sheds light on the global repercussions of this crime. 

The film views the tragic events of July 17, 2014 from different perspectives and at different points in time, linking the crimes of the past with the present.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #flight #boeing777 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>AI&apos;s Energy Problem, Explained</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/7L_61B7ue9M</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7L_61B7ue9M?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 16:00:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">The Wall Street Journal</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[AI is pushing America’s power grid to its limits, and countries like China are racing ahead.⁠

#AI #Energy #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What Secrets Could Outer Space Be Hiding? | Solar System | BBC Earth Science</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1wYgHzB19K0</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/1wYgHzB19K0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 15:00:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">BBC Earth Science</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[With fresh perspectives on the Moon, Jupiter and alien life, this hour -long deep dive takes us further into understanding the marvel of what lays beyond the Earth's atmosphere.

Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

Taken from: Solar System (2024)

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Insane Submarine that Outran Torpedoes</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j6ttTK8x8ZA</link><author>Mustard</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/j6ttTK8x8ZA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:35:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC1ZBQ-F-yktYD4m5AzM6pww">Mustard</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get Nebula for 50% off using my link: https://go.nebula.tv/mustard

Watch Unsealed Episode 1 here: https://nebula.tv/videos/mustard-unsealed-episode-1-underwater-fighter-jet

Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/MustardChannel
Mustard Store: https://mustardchannel.com/
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/mustard_channel
Twitter:  https://twitter.com/MustardVideos
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/Mustard-109952378202335

By the late 1950s, it was becoming clear to Soviet naval planners that the United States was winning the battle beneath the world’s oceans.

Over the previous decade, American engineers had developed sophisticated silencing technologies that made the latest generation of submarines so stealthy, they could track Soviet subs for hours, and sometimes days, without being detected. For Soviet naval planners, a nightmare scenario was unfolding. If war broke out, American submarines could find and destroy Soviet submarines before they had a chance to strike back.

Simply catching up to American stealth wasn't an option. It wasn't a technology that could easily be copied, it was the result of decades of precision manufacturing, relentless quality control, advances in materials science, and industrial discipline that the Soviet system couldn't support at the time. It would take decades to catch up.

Faced with a widening stealth technology gap, Soviet planners stopped trying to play hide and seek under the oceans, and instead chose raw power. They would bet everything on speed, depth, maneuverability and brute force.

In 1960, the Soviet Union launched their most ambitious submarine programs in history. Project 705 ‘Lira’, later designated as the ‘Alfa Class’ submarine by NATO, was a nuclear-powered attack submarine capable of outrunning torpedoes, executing extreme maneuvers, and diving deeper than anything the world had ever seen. Built with a revolutionary liquid-metal nuclear reactor, advanced automation, and a titanium hull, this machine represented a generational leap in engineering.
It wasn’t just a faster submarine, it was a radical attempt to rewrite the rules of underwater warfare.

When Western intelligence realized what the Soviets were building, it caused immediate panic. A submarine that could outrun torpedoes and dive beyond existing weapons threatened to upend NATO’s entire anti-submarine strategy, forcing the West into a sudden scramble to catch up.

But Project 705, a super submarine meant to restore balance beneath the seas, would prove to be far more than the Soviets ever bargained for.

Thanks for watching!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Forgot To Loot Clean Pants #arcraiders</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/V7Wpr0hY3Hg</link><author>IcarusLIVES</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/V7Wpr0hY3Hg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:45:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgp_adxCQiesfxKYIqIE9yQ">IcarusLIVES</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Hey RaiDOHMYGOD 

Official ProtonVPN Partner - https://go.getproton.me/SH1mq

▬ Socials  ▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬
Twitch        ► www.twitch.tv/mr_icarus/
Bluesky        ► mistericarus.bsky.social
Patreon      ► www.patreon.com/MrIcarus
Bandcamp ► icarusliv3s.bandcamp.com/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Minneapolis Residents Are Organizing to Monitor ICE Activity</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/xZV318UwtZg</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/xZV318UwtZg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 22:03:43 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">The Wall Street Journal</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The surge of federal agents conducting immigration enforcement operations has sparked widespread resistance from local law enforcement and community groups. 

#Minneapolis #ICE #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Nintendo&apos;s First Console #nintendo #videogames #70s #history</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/45q9FQPSg7k</link><author>NesHacker</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/45q9FQPSg7k?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 22:00:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCXR5PCyUI2pG_a3ydnCIS-g">NesHacker</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Support the channel: https://patreon.com/NesHacker]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>This TECH Knife is Insane!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/PTd98UnJnnU</link><author>Marques Brownlee</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/PTd98UnJnnU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:56:34 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBJycsmduvYEL83R_U4JriQ">Marques Brownlee</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Sorry dinner is late, I had to charge my knife]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Investors Should Hold Onto Megabank Stocks–For Now</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/RNcarVhVsUI</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/RNcarVhVsUI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:29:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">The Wall Street Journal</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[WSJ’s Telis Demos explains why he thinks 2026 could be another busy deal-making year for Wall Street’s biggest banks.

#Markets #Banking #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>.NET in 100 Seconds</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MFsYaRnrcPQ</link><author>Fireship</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/MFsYaRnrcPQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:03:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsBjURrPoezykLs9EqgamOA">Fireship</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[.NET is a free and open-source platform for creating high-performance software in virtually every domain, powered primarily by the C# programming language.

#coding #programming #softwaredevelopment 

🔗 Resources
- https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/

🔥 Brain food for developers
- https://fireship.dev

🎨 My Editor Settings

- Atom One Dark 
- vscode-icons
- Fira Code Font

🔖 Topics Covered

- The history of .NET
- .NET explained
- The .Net ecosystem
- What can you build in .NET?
- .NET demo]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>My son was killed - A mother&apos;s journey through grief | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=36WcDbvRKtE</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/36WcDbvRKtE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:00:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In June 2024, Joanna lost her 20-year-old son Philippos. He was beaten up by another young man, following his sister's high school graduation party. Two days later, he died. The alleged perpetrator, a 19-year-old Syrian, was arrested.

A summer evening that ended in disaster. After his sister's high school graduation party, 20-year-old Philippos was brutally attacked in the German town of Bad Oeynhausen.

As his mother Joanna was mourning her son, Philippos became headline news. Before long, his death was used to reignite the debate on Germany’s asylum policy. Both in the German parliament, and in the media. 

Philippos' mother did not participate in this discussion. For her, the nationality of the perpetrator was irrelevant. "The doctor who fought for my child's life is Syrian," she said. "So is my hairdresser. And me? I'm Polish.”

Instead, Joanna, who is deeply religious, tried to find a way to deal with her anger, rage, despair, and grief. She sought advice from a prison psychologist and a priest: Why did Philippos have to die? Am I allowed to be angry with the perpetrator? Do I have to forgive him?

She sat opposite the defendant at the Bielefeld Regional Court, endured the police reports and witness statements, listened to the autopsy results from the forensic pathologists, and witnessed the images of her dead child on the dissection table.

"Even hearing the incomprehensible, the painful, knowing how Philippos died... I owe that to my child," she said. 

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>A First World War Luger and the Personal Items of a Major with Firearms Curator Lisa Traynor</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0Fvwk6DQ4fw</link><author>Royal Armouries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0Fvwk6DQ4fw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsMX-XuiEkBi4-GDrYuniWg">Royal Armouries</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A Luger with a story: Firearms Curator, Lisa Traynor, tells the story of this WWI Luger and the associated items of Major Charles Frederick Ashdown.
 
Find out more about the Luger via our collection online:
https://royalarmouries.org/collection/object/object-113919

Subscribe to our channel for more videos about arms and armour  

Help us bring history to life by supporting us here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/donations/

Sign up to our museum membership scheme here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/membership/ 

⚔Website: https://royalarmouries.org/home
⚔Blog: https://royalarmouries.org/stories/
⚔Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/RoyalArmouriesMuseum/
⚔Twitter: https://twitter.com/Royal_Armouries
⚔ Instagram: http://instagram.com/royalarmouriesmuseum

We are the Royal Armouries, the United Kingdom's national collection of arms and armour. Discover what goes on behind the scenes and watch our collection come to life. See combat demonstrations, experience jousting and meet our experts. 

Have a question about arms and armour? Feel free to leave us a comment and we'll do our best to answer it.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Watch Live: Anthropic CEO Dario Amodei From World Economic Forum | WSJ</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K7F6ohcBJus</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/K7F6ohcBJus?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:58:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">The Wall Street Journal</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Anthropic CEO Dario Amodei speaks live with WSJ Editor-in-Chief Emma Tucker from WSJ’s 2026 World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland. 

#Anthropic #AI #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Watch Live: Goldman Sachs CEO David Solomon From World Economic Forum | WSJ</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oDC0GzF-mao</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/oDC0GzF-mao?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:56:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">The Wall Street Journal</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs CEO David Solomon speaks live with WSJ Editor-in-Chief Emma Tucker from WSJ’s 2026 World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland. 

#GoldmanSachs #Banking #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We Made A New Channel!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D0WQK7cMJn8</link><author>Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/D0WQK7cMJn8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:30:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsXVk37bltHxD1rDPwtNM8Q">Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[For years, we’ve been dreaming of a second channel. A channel where we could tell different kinds of stories and dive into something else we deeply care about: history. Because the story of the past is also the story of us, of humanity. Welcome to the nightshift. 🌚

Our first video dives into the extraordinary story of Zheng Yi Sao, a young woman who built the largest pirate confederation the world has ever seen. Her floating shadow state of 1,800 ships and 70,000 pirates pushed the Chinese Empire to its limits and reshaped trade in the South China Sea. 

Continue watching on nightshift: https://kgs.link/NGT_PP

We’d love to hear what you think. 🖤


OUR CHANNELS
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
German:        https://kgs.link/youtubeDE
Spanish:        https://kgs.link/youtubeES
French:          https://kgs.link/youtubeFR
Portuguese:  https://kgs.link/youtubePT
Arabic:           https://kgs.link/youtubeAR
Hindi:             https://kgs.link/youtubeHI
Japanese:     https://kgs.link/youtubeJA
Korean:          https://kgs.link/youtubeKO


HOW CAN YOU SUPPORT US?
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
This is how we make our living and it would be a pleasure if you support us!

Get Products designed with ❤️ https://shop.kgs.link
Join the Patreon Bird Army 🐧  https://kgs.link/patreon  


DISCUSSIONS & SOCIAL MEDIA
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
TikTok:           https://kgs.link/tiktok
Reddit:            https://kgs.link/reddit
Instagram:     https://kgs.link/instagram
Twitter:           https://kgs.link/twitter
Facebook:      https://kgs.link/facebook
Discord:          https://kgs.link/discord
Newsletter:    https://kgs.link/newsletter


OUR VOICE
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
The kurzgesagt voice is from 
Steve Taylor:  https://kgs.link/youtube-voice


OUR MUSIC ♬♪
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
700+ minutes of kurzgesagt Soundtracks by Epic Mountain:

Spotify:            https://kgs.link/music-spotify
Soundcloud:   https://kgs.link/music-soundcloud
Bandcamp:     https://kgs.link/music-bandcamp
Youtube:          https://kgs.link/music-youtube
Facebook:       https://kgs.link/music-facebook


If you want to help us caption this video, please send subtitles to subtitle@kurzgesagt.org
You can find info on what subtitle files work on YouTube here:
https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2734698?hl=en-GB&ref_topic=7296214
Thank you!


🐦🐧🐤 PATREON BIRD ARMY 🐤🐧🐦
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Many Thanks to our wonderful Patreons (from http://kgs.link/patreon) who support us every month and made this video possible.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Most Brutal Stories From World War II | Compilation</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UQM2K2ZaNZ0</link><author>Weird History</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/UQM2K2ZaNZ0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:00:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCc-N24Y5OA0gqbjBwe1ttfA">Weird History</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This past century was a wild one. Especially concerning Wars... Today We delve into many different aspects of World War II - Life of a World War II G.I., what civilians ate during World War II to get by, how exactly the attack on Peal Harbor went down, and many many other aspects! What do you think was most interesting about World War II? Let us know in the comments!

Chapters:
00:00:00 - A Beat By Beat Breakdown of Pearl Harbor
00:12:19 - Little-Known Facts About The Finnish Soldiers of World War II
00:23:24 - What It Was Like to Be an American G.I. in WWII
00:34:24 - How World War II Is Taught Around The World
00:43:13 - How A Baseball Player Became a World War II Assassin
00:54:53 - What Happened Immediately After Hitler's Death
01:07:21 - What Happened After the Attack on Pearl Harbor
01:17:52 - Here's What People Ate To Survive During WWII
01:29:07 - Hiroo Onoda Fought WWII For 30 Additional Years
01:37:07 - What Was Hygiene Like For US Soldiers In WWII?


Be sure to subscribe to the Weird History Newsletter: https://bit.ly/WeirdHistoryNews

#ww2 #compilation #weirdhistory]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Ukraine’s Deadly Drone Operation Runs Like a ‘McDonald’s’ | WSJ</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9hzIMI2DLys</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9hzIMI2DLys?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:00:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">The Wall Street Journal</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Nearly four years into the Russia-Ukraine War, drones have gone from battlefield experiments to indispensable, scalable machines of destruction. Ukrainian forces have adapted drone tech and combat tactics to counter evolving Russian threats; and now they’re warning that Europe is unprepared for the kind of high-tech war they are fighting.

WSJ was given exclusive access inside Lasar’s Group, one of the largest and deadliest drone units in the world. We went inside their secret bunker, where dozens of drone pilots are attacking Russian targets 24 hours a day. 

Chapters:
0:00 Inside Ukraine’s secret bunker
1:39 The new drone warfare
2:56 Ukraine’s drone unit history
5:51 Lasar’s accomplishments and helping NATO
7:22 What’s next?

Russia-Ukraine War
WSJ’s latest news coverage around the 2022-2026 Russia-Ukraine War.

#Ukraine #Russia #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Modern X86 Assembly Language Programming • Daniel Kusswurm &amp; Matt Godbolt</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1GfPBqyGWmw</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/1GfPBqyGWmw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:24:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">GOTO Conferences</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for the GOTO Book Club.
http://gotopia.tech/bookclub

Check out more here:
https://gotopia.tech/episodes/411

Daniel Kusswurm - SW Developer, Computer Scientist & Author of "Modern X86 Assembly Language Programming" & many more books
Matt Godbolt - Low-level Latency Geek & Creator of Compiler Explorer

RESOURCES
Matt
https://bsky.app/profile/matt.godbolt.org
https://xania.org
https://github.com/mattgodbolt
https://www.linkedin.com/in/godbolt
https://twitter.com/mattgodbolt
https://godbolt.org

Links
https://link.springer.com
https://youtu.be/L2Qu9rk05rE
https://youtu.be/-HNpim5x-IE
https://youtu.be/hgcNM-6wr34

DESCRIPTION
Matt Godbolt, creator of Compiler Explorer, interviews Daniel Kusswurm, author of "Modern X86 Assembly Language Programming", about the enduring relevance of assembly language in modern software development. They explore what SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) is and why it enables dramatic performance improvements for specific computational tasks, discuss when assembly language programming is justified versus using compiler intrinsics, and examine the challenges of writing vectorized algorithms. Dan shares insights from his career optimizing image analysis software and explains how understanding low-level architecture can improve code quality even when writing in higher-level languages.

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Daniel Kusswurm • Modern X86 Assembly Language Programming v3 • https://amzn.to/44hIVZf
Daniel Kusswurm • Modern X86 Assembly Language Programming v2 • https://amzn.to/3LJlMIZ
Daniel Kusswurm • Modern X86 Assembly Language Programming v1 • https://amzn.to/43DPANj
Daniel Kusswurm • Modern Arm Assembly Language Programming • https://amzn.to/4rbyH6M
Daniel Kusswurm • Practical C++ STL Programming • https://amzn.to/4ickAdq
Daniel Kusswurm • Modern Parallel Programming with C++ and Assembly Language • https://amzn.to/4o5J3SF


Bluesky (https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com) 
Twitter (https://twitter.com/GOTOcon) 
Instagram (https://www.instagram.com/goto_con) 
LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-) 
Facebook (https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences) 

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket: gotopia.tech (https://gotopia.tech) 

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR YOUTUBE CHANNEL (https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1)  - new videos posted daily!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Japan’s Economy Is at a Tipping Point</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R_LlRX299fQ</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/R_LlRX299fQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:00:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Bloomberg Originals</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[For 30 years, Japan’s prices were largely at a standstill. Now, a weak yen is changing everything. Here’s how consumers and businesses are coping with rising costs, and what it means for the nation’s economic future.   

Get the Economics Daily newsletter https://www.bloomberg.com/account/newsletters/new-economy-daily?utm_medium=social&utm_source=youtube&utm_campaign=originals&utm_content=article

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Private Jet Billionaire Breaks Down Every Step in His Wealth Journey | The WSJ Money Interview</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MbsT2RC1wQo</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/MbsT2RC1wQo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 20:00:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">The Wall Street Journal</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Kenn Ricci is a pilot whose obsession over four decades with aviation and luxe travel made him a billionaire. He has started businesses tied to almost every aspect of flying—his private-jet company Flexjet was recently valued at $4 billion after an investment by a private-equity firm backed by LVMH. So how does he think about money and wealth? 

WSJ sat down with Kenn Ricci to learn how he made his first million, what spending in his tax bracket looks like and more. 

Chapters:
0:00 Introducing Kenn Ricci
0:48 How Ken made his first millions
3:34 Merging with Raytheon 
4:31 Ken’s next venture: Directional Aviation Capital 
5:42 Buying Raytheon out and turning it around
6:27 Hitting a billion dollar net worth 
7:39 How money changes things and passing on wealth
8:40 Family meeting agendas
10:17 How much money you donated last year
10:46 Vacation spending and tipping
12:03 Watch collection and spending on clothes 

Subscribers get access to full-length episodes of WSJ’s The Money Interview, plus the chance to have their questions answered by our millionaire guest. Watch the full series here: https://on.wsj.com/3ZauOly 

Follow our host Gunjan Banerji on Instagram at @gunjansb.

WSJ The Money Interview
What can some of the world’s most interesting tycoons teach us about ambition and wealth? WSJ’s Gunjan Banerji sits down with highfliers for a candid conversation about how they made it.

#Business #Wealth #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Flying Boats: The Boeing 314 Clipper</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wm-OKMqLHYY</link><author>Megaprojects</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wm-OKMqLHYY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:50:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0woBco6Dgcxt0h8SwyyOmw">Megaprojects</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Click here to check out Huel: https://huel.com/mega20 and use code mega20 for 20% off your order ($75+). New customers only. #ad

Got a beard? Good. I've got something for you: http://beardblaze.com

Simon's Social Media:
Twitter: https://twitter.com/SimonWhistler
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/simonwhistler/

This video is #sponsored by Huel. 

Love content? Check out Simon's other YouTube Channels:


Warfronts: https://www.youtube.com/@warographics643
SideProjects: https://www.youtube.com/@Sideprojects
Into The Shadows: https://www.youtube.com/@IntotheShadows
Today I Found Out: https://www.youtube.com/@TodayIFoundOut
Highlight History: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnb-VTwBHEV3gtiB9di9DZQ
Brain Blaze: https://www.youtube.com/@brainblaze6526
Casual Criminalist: https://www.youtube.com/@TheCasualCriminalist
Decoding the Unknown: https://www.youtube.com/@decodingtheunknown2373
Places: https://www.youtube.com/@Places302
Celestium: https://www.youtube.com/@astrographics-ve4yq
PoliticalFronts: http://www.youtube.com/@politicalfronts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Trump Paused Iran Threats: Will the Crackdown End?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/X5uncEv-fAw</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/X5uncEv-fAw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:45:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">The Wall Street Journal</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[President Trump appears to have cooled on the idea of a military strike against Iran, but as WSJ’s Sune Engel Rasmussen explains, ongoing volatility motivating his warnings still remains.  

#Trump #Iran #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The 10 Greatest Directors</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bZsn4zXJTzk</link><author>The House of Tabula</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bZsn4zXJTzk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:20:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCL5kBJmBUVFLYBDiSiK1VDw">The House of Tabula</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This is a personal list of my favourite filmmakers of all time.
This is not a ranking of technical achievement or historical importance, but a personal canon. The filmmakers I will always return to.

Support The House of Tabula (and join our Discord Film Club):
https://www.patreon.com/c/thehouseoftabula

Join this channel to get access to perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCL5kBJmBUVFLYBDiSiK1VDw/join
———————————
🎬 Deep Dive Film Club 
———————————
🎞️ All 30+ episodes: https://tinyurl.com/4kf9kjjd
🎥 The Film Club series: https://tinyurl.com/4hu3p89d
There Will Be Blood: https://tinyurl.com/2uwxewfy
Tetsuo: The Iron Man: https://tinyurl.com/336x9rec
—————————————————
💊 Acid is Bad for Business Podcast
—————————————————
All 70+ episodes: https://tinyurl.com/3r3kjw3w
Socialmediaocracy: https://tinyurl.com/mjdx75wu
Keep Robert De Niro Close, But Viola Davis Closer: https://tinyurl.com/9fmtb98y
The Artwork of the 21st Century: https://tinyurl.com/459c4vzu
————————————————————
⚔️ Exclusive Uncensored Essays & Workshops
—————————————————————
Join our Composition for Cinema & Visual Arts Workshop: https://tinyurl.com/2s4evptm
Over 20+ Uncensored Essays: https://tinyurl.com/3esebpew
💀 The Allure of the New Profane: https://tinyurl.com/2w6dsxzv
☕ Content with the Veneer of Depth: https://tinyurl.com/4fy83wyj
———————————————————————
For business inquiries: contact@thehouseoftabula.com
———————————————————————
TIMESTAMPS:
0:00 Number 10
4:37 Number 9
8:04 Number 8
12:52 Number 7
16:13 Number 6
19:05 Number 5
22:30 Number 4
27:22 Number 3
31:10 Number 2
35:13 Number 1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>A Brief History Of Greenland (And Why Trump Wants To Control It)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=db1oi_fMF7A</link><author>History Hit</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/db1oi_fMF7A?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ">History Hit</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greenland, the world's largest island, is at the centre of a rapidly heating geopolitical struggle.

In this video, historian Matt Lewis breaks down the brief history of Greenland, from its Indigenous Inuit origins and Norse settlements to Danish rule and modern self-governance. But history is only half the story. The real question is why the United States cares so much about Greenland right now.

As climate change melts Arctic ice, Greenland is no longer just the world’s largest island—it’s a strategic goldmine. New shipping routes, untapped rare earth minerals, and massive energy potential are turning the Arctic into the next great power competition zone. The U.S., China, and Russia are all watching closely, but America’s interest in Greenland goes back decades, from Cold War military bases to recent, very public attempts to increase influence.

0:00 Introduction 
1:23 Prehistory 
2:50 Viking Age
7:50 Rediscovery
9:21 Polar Exploration
11:30 World War Two
13:35 The Cold War
19:14 Modern Era

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world-renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.

Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ/join

#greenland #history #donaldtrump]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>America&apos;s First Emperor | Weird Dudes in History</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/fZERro4ic7k</link><author>Extra History</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/fZERro4ic7k?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:29:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCCODtTcd5M1JavPCOr_Uydg">Extra History</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[📚 For more Historical Tales, why not check out our series on the World's Tyrants here: https://youtu.be/99dygZ98Krg

* Watch us ad-free & get 1-week early access on NEBULA https://go.nebula.tv/extrahistory * 
* Suggest & Vote on our next episodes, get exclusive content & 24-hour early access on PATREON https://bit.ly/EHPatreon * 
* Show off your fandom with MERCH from our store! http://extracredits.store/ *

https://twitter.com/extracreditz | https://www.facebook.com/ExtraCredits/ | http://instagram.com/extracredits | https://www.tiktok.com/@extracreditz
GAMING: https://www.youtube.com/@extracredits | http://www.twitch.tv/extracredits/
https://bsky.app/profile/extracredits.bsky.social 

*Thanks for the high-quality conversations & for following our community guidelines: https://bit.ly/ECFansRNice

*Interested in sponsoring an episode? Email us: extracredits@standard.tv *
Artist: Scott DeWitt I Writer: Robert Rath I Showrunner & Narrator: Matthew Krol I Video Editor: Devon House Creative I Audio Editor: Clean Waves I Studio Director: Geoffrey Zatkin I Social Media: Kat Rider

#ExtraHistory  #Shorts  #History]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Inside the &apos;Woman, Life, Freedom&apos; protest movement in Iran | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=us8B_KdcB3c</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/us8B_KdcB3c?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:01:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">DW Documentary</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Filmed in secret, this documentary is a behind-the-scenes look at the "Woman, Life, Freedom” uprising in Iran. The story begins a few weeks after the death of Jina Mahsa Amini, a young Kurdish student who died on 16 September 2022.

She had allowed a few strands of hair to escape from her veil. Members of the Iranian morality police beat her so severely that she died of her injuries. The regime in Tehran has denied all responsibility for her death, which triggered nationwide mass protests under a slogan that echoed all around the world: "Woman, Life, Freedom”.

Iranian filmmaker Shorresh Afkari filmed in secret, smuggling the footage out of the country to a colleague in France. His documentary gives a voice to people who, like large sections of the Iranian population, have run out of strength and patience.

For example, the film observes a young couple who dream of being able to express their love openly and in complete freedom. We also meet a taxi driver, who ends up in prison as a bitter opponent of the regime. His mother tries to protect him at all costs. A painter continues to practise her art despite censorship; a doctor secretly treats demonstrators. A young man is prepared to do anything for cash, even sell one of his kidneys. Just like men who dare to protest, women who show their hair in public and publicly oppose the regime still face harsh punishment, including the death penalty. For this reason, many interviewees speak off-camera to protect their anonymity.

The widespread protests and mass demonstrations that began shortly before the end of 2025 and continue to this day show that large parts of the population no longer support the regime in Tehran — a regime that continues to respond with brutality against the people of Iran.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #iran #protest #womanlifefreedom 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Kiranmala: The tale of the princess who conquered Magic Mountain - Malay Bera</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-bFgGvl4pBQ</link><author>TED-Ed</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-bFgGvl4pBQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:00:50 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsooa4yRKGN_zEE8iknghZA">TED-Ed</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dig into the Bengali tale of a trio of siblings who attempt to scale the fearsome Magic Mountain to gain treasures for their home.

--

Inspired by a king’s visit, a trio of siblings began building a palace, traveling far and wide to collect rare jewels, seeds, and marble. A holy man stopped by and told them of a Magic Mountain, east of north and north of east, where they’d find their most meaningful treasures. But, he said, only a true hero could complete the journey. Malay Bera shares the Bengali tale of Kiranmala's quest.

Lesson by Malay Bera, directed by Héloïse Dorsan-Rachet.

Although this folktale exists in multiple oral variants across the Bengali-speaking world, this video is based on a variant akin to the better-known literary version, “Kironmala", from Thakurmar Jhuli (1907), an anthology of Bengali folktales collected by Dakshinaranjan Mitra Majumdar in the early 20th century.

Support Our Non-Profit Mission
----------------------------------------------
Support us on Patreon: http://bit.ly/TEDEdPatreon
Check out our merch: http://bit.ly/TEDEDShop
----------------------------------------------

Connect With Us
----------------------------------------------
Sign up for our newsletter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdNewsletter
Follow us on Facebook: http://bit.ly/TEDEdFacebook
Find us on Twitter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdTwitter
Peep us on Instagram: http://bit.ly/TEDEdInstagram
----------------------------------------------

Keep Learning
----------------------------------------------
View full lesson: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/the-princess-who-conquered-magic-mountain-malay-bera
Dig deeper with additional resources: 

Animator's website: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/the-princess-who-conquered-magic-mountain-malay-bera/digdeeper
----------------------------------------------

Thank you so much to our patrons for your support! Without you this video would not be possible! Ophelia Gibson Best, Paul Schneider, Joichiro Yamada, Henrique Cassús, Karthik Cherala, Clarence E. Harper Jr., Vignan Velivela, Ana Maria, Exal Enrique Cisneros Tuch, Tejas Dc, Khalifa Alhulail, Martin Stephen, Jose Henrique Leopoldo e Silva, Mandeep Singh, Abhijit Kiran Valluri, Morgan Williams, Devin Harris, Pavel Zalevskiy, Karen Goepen-Wee, Filip Dabrowski, Barbara Smalley, Megan Douglas, Tim Leistikow, Ka-Hei Law, Hiroshi Uchiyama, Mark Morris, Misaki Sato, EdoKun, SookKwan Loong, Bev Millar, Lex Azevedo, Michael Aquilina, Jason A Saslow, Yansong Li, Cristóbal Moenne, Dawn Jordan, Prasanth Mathialagan, Samuel Doerle, David Rosario, Dominik Kugelmann - they-them, Siamak Hajizadeh, Ryohky Araya, Mayank Kaul, Christophe Dessalles, Heather Slater, Sandra Tersluisen, Zhexi Shan, Bárbara Nazaré, Andrea Feliz, and Victor E Karhel.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Minneapolis Is Fighting ICE’s Enforcement Surge | WSJ</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4oGgFZ1BwpY</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/4oGgFZ1BwpY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:11:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">The Wall Street Journal</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The surge of federal agents conducting immigration enforcement operations has sparked widespread resistance from local law enforcement and community groups. 

Chapters:
0:00 The situation in Minneapolis
0:43 Ride along with the Minneapolis Police Chief
3:07 ICE shootings since July 
3:40 ICE protests and an ICE-watching patrol 

Trump threatens to invoke Insurrection Act in response to Minnesota protests: https://on.wsj.com/4jRI6wX

#Minneapolis #ICE #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Planets Around Black Holes</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/OU36JDGzXb0</link><author>Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/OU36JDGzXb0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:00:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsXVk37bltHxD1rDPwtNM8Q">Kurzgesagt – In a Nutshell</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Could planets form around black holes? Maybe! These “blanets” wouldn’t orbit stars but black holes. 

#kurzgesagt
#inanutshell #kurzgesagt_inanutshell #learnwithshorts #science #blackholes #blanets #astrophysics 

Sources & further reading: 
https://sites.google.com/view/kgs-tiktok-sources

Follow us for more sciencey content! 🦆

OUR CHANNELS
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
German:        https://kgs.link/youtubeDE
Spanish:        https://kgs.link/youtubeES
French:          https://kgs.link/youtubeFR
Portuguese:  https://kgs.link/youtubePT
Arabic:           https://kgs.link/youtubeAR
Hindi:             https://kgs.link/youtubeHI
Japanese:     https://kgs.link/youtubeJA
Korean:          https://kgs.link/youtubeKO


HOW CAN YOU SUPPORT US?
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
This is how we make our living and it would be a pleasure if you support us!

Get Products designed with ❤ https://shop.kgs.link/shorts
Become a Part of kurzgesagt by joining the Patreon Bird Army 🐧  https://kgs.link/patreon  


DISCUSSIONS & SOCIAL MEDIA
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Instagram:     https://kgs.link/instagram
TikTok:           https://kgs.link/tiktok
Reddit:            https://kgs.link/reddit
Discord:          https://kgs.link/discord
Twitter:           https://kgs.link/twitter
Bluesky:          https://kgs.link/bluesky
Facebook:      https://kgs.link/facebook
Newsletter:    https://kgs.link/newsletter


OUR VOICE
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
The Kurzgesagt voice is from 
Steve Taylor:  https://kgs.link/youtube-voice


OUR MUSIC ♬♪
▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
700+ minutes of Kurzgesagt Soundtracks by Epic Mountain:

Spotify:            https://kgs.link/music-spotify
Soundcloud:   https://kgs.link/music-soundcloud
Bandcamp:     https://kgs.link/music-bandcamp
Youtube:          https://kgs.link/music-youtube
Facebook:       https://kgs.link/music-facebook]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>