<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Youtube</title><link>https://konrad.website/feeds/</link><description></description><item><title>The RAM Apocalypse</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-YNk9_e4pg4</link><author>ColdFusion</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-YNk9_e4pg4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 01:58:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULF4QZ_LsYcvcq7qOsOhpAX4A">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Visit https://brilliant.org/coldfusion for 20% off a premium subscription.
In this episode we cover the insane supply shortage of RAM due to the AI buildout. It'll be the price and availability of a lot of consumer electronics over the next year.

Watch or listen to ColdFusion on Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/1YEwCKoRz8fEDqheXB6UJ1


ColdFusion Music: 

https://www.youtube.com/@ColdFusionmusic
http://burnwater.bandcamp.com   

ColdFusion Socials: 

https://discord.gg/coldfusion
https://facebook.com/ColdFusionTV 
https://twitter.com/ColdFusion_TV 
https://instagram.com/coldfusiontv

Created by: Dagogo Altraide
Producers: Tawsif Akkas, Dagogo Altraide]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ali Khamenei - The Full Biography of Iran’s Supreme Leader Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Iz7wrLw6IAk</link><author>The People Profiles</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Iz7wrLw6IAk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 1 Mar 2026 01:47:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFD6TPU-PvTMvqgzC_AM7_uA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This comprehensive biography of Ali Khamenei explores the life, power, and controversial legacy of the Islamic Republic of Iran’s Supreme Leader. From his humble beginnings in Mashhad and his early years as a revolutionary cleric to his pivotal role in the 1979 Islamic Revolution alongside Ayatollah Khomeini, we trace the definitive history of the man who has shaped the modern Middle East.

Discover the untold story of his rise to the Supreme Leadership in 1989, surviving the 1981 assassination attempt, and outlasting eight U.S. Presidents. We analyse his strategic control over the IRGC (Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps), his influence on the Axis of Resistance, and the internal struggles of the Iranian regime.

As geopolitical tensions peak in 2026, understanding Khamenei’s ideology from the nuclear program to his stance on Israel and the West is more critical than ever. Whether you are looking for a deep dive into Iranian history, the mechanics of the theocratic government, or the future of Tehran’s leadership, this documentary provides the ultimate breakdown.

Please subscribe here. https://www.youtube.com/@PeopleProfiles?sub_confirmation=1
Our second channel. https://www.youtube.com/@PeopleProfilesExtra
Follow us on Spotify. https://open.spotify.com/show/7fKALbrzEO9Q4VVvAwWHqL
Support us on Patreon https://patreon.com/thepeopleprofiles
Follow us on Twitter. https://twitter.com/tpprofiles

Thanks for watching! If you liked this video, check out our related videos below:
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLNwBhP0rWSz1EQOUiCo2hOzXogNU5psT8
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLNwBhP0rWSz0vPvWecG4EPQIWEIh34K-X
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLNwBhP0rWSz3l1yKTFKS6b3GPniSWVpmX

All footage, images and music used in People Profiles videos are sourced from free media websites or are purchased with commercial rights from online media archives.

All People Profiles scripts are researched and written by qualified Historians. The script for this video has been checked with Plagiarism and AI Detector software and scored 0% on Grammarly. In academia, a score of below 15% is considered good or acceptable. 

No AI is used during the writing process of People Profiles videos, which are narrated by human voice over artists. Please see the end credits of our videos for details and contact us for script references.

#peopleprofiles  #history  #biography]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Abraham Lincoln - The Extraordinary Life of America&apos;s 16th President Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qf_tt4Z4ls0</link><author>The People Profiles</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Qf_tt4Z4ls0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 23:00:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFD6TPU-PvTMvqgzC_AM7_uA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[If you’d like to start learning Spanish — or explore one of the other languages available — just click this link https://try.lingopie.com/creators/cr?utm_source=youtube&utm_medium=influencer&utm_campaign=people_profiles&utm_term=mar_2026&utm_creative=people_profiles&lmid=8008756&coupon= for a free 7-day trial and exclusive discount.

Explore the incredible journey of Abraham Lincoln in this definitive full documentary. From his humble beginnings in a Kentucky log cabin to his rise as a prairie lawyer and eventually the 16th President of the United States, this film examines the man known as "Honest Abe".

We dive deep into the American Civil War, analysing Lincoln's military strategy, his search for a winning general, and his leadership through the nation's greatest crisis. Discover the true story behind the Emancipation Proclamation, the 13th Amendment, and the powerful words of the Gettysburg Address that redefined American liberty.

This biography also uncovers lesser-known personal struggles, including his family history, his marriage to Mary Todd Lincoln, and the tragic events leading to his assassination at Ford’s Theatre by John Wilkes Booth.

Please subscribe here. https://www.youtube.com/@PeopleProfiles?sub_confirmation=1
Our second channel. https://www.youtube.com/@PeopleProfilesExtra
Follow us on Spotify. https://open.spotify.com/show/7fKALbrzEO9Q4VVvAwWHqL
Support us on Patreon https://patreon.com/thepeopleprofiles
Follow us on Twitter. https://twitter.com/tpprofiles

Thanks for watching! If you liked this video, check out our related videos below:
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLNwBhP0rWSz1EQOUiCo2hOzXogNU5psT8
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLNwBhP0rWSz0vPvWecG4EPQIWEIh34K-X
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLNwBhP0rWSz3l1yKTFKS6b3GPniSWVpmX

All footage, images and music used in People Profiles videos are sourced from free media websites or are purchased with commercial rights from online media archives.

All People Profiles scripts are researched and written by qualified Historians. The script for this video has been checked with Plagiarism and AI Detector software and scored 2% on Grammarly. In academia, a score of below 15% is considered good or acceptable. 

No AI is used during the writing process of People Profiles videos, which are narrated by human voice over artists. Please see the end credits of our videos for details and contact us for script references.

#peopleprofiles  #history  #biography]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Samsung Galaxy Buds 4 Pro Review: Better than AirPods!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wRaDbRjVrc4</link><author>Marques Brownlee</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wRaDbRjVrc4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 22:55:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFBJycsmduvYEL83R_U4JriQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Galaxy Buds 4 Pro are sneaky winners!

MKBHD Merch: [http://shop.MKBHD.com](http://shop.mkbhd.com/)

Playlist of MKBHD Intro music: https://goo.gl/B3AWV5

Earbuds provided by Samsung for review.

~
http://twitter.com/MKBHD
http://instagram.com/MKBHD
http://facebook.com/MKBHD]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Historical Tyrants: Richard III | European History</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p2-miHSltwM</link><author>Extra History</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/p2-miHSltwM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 18:29:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFCODtTcd5M1JavPCOr_Uydg">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[📚  When you're done learning about the Historical Tyrant Richard III, then check out our 2026 History Happens Everyday Calendar here: http://extracredits.store/  📆

This week, we crack open the case of Richard III, the last Plantagenet king of England. From the blood-soaked chaos of the Wars of the Roses to the mystery of the Princes in the Tower, we will follow Richard’s rise from loyal brother to crowned king and examine his role in the downfall of Edward V, the disappearance of the young princes, and the rebellion that ended at the Battle of Bosworth in 1485.

* Watch Extra History ad-free & get 1-week early access on *NEBULA* https://go.nebula.tv/extrahistory 
* Suggest & Vote on our next episodes, get exclusive content & 24-hour early access on *PATREON* https://bit.ly/EHPatreon   
* Show off your fandom with *MERCH* from our store! http://extracredits.store/  
* Interested in sponsoring an episode?* Email us: extracredits@standard.tv 

https://twitter.com/extracreditz | https://www.facebook.com/ExtraCredits/ | http://instagram.com/extracredits | https://www.tiktok.com/@extracreditz
GAMING: https://www.youtube.com/@extracredits | http://www.twitch.tv/extracredits/
https://bsky.app/profile/extracredits.bsky.social 

*Miss an episode in our Series?*
Part 1 - https://youtu.be/99dygZ98Krg
Part 2 - https://youtu.be/FaHQNoC5NZU
Part 3 - https://youtu.be/XtzQ2J8m3hs 
Part 4 - https://youtu.be/p2-miHSltwM
Recommended Reading / Lies Episode - Release Date: February 26th

Thanks for the high-quality conversations & for following our community guidelines here: https://bit.ly/ECFansRNice

Artist: David Hueso | Writer: Robert Rath | Researcher: A. Siso | Showrunner & Narrator: Matthew Krol | Video Editor: Devon House Creative | Audio Editor: Clean Waves | Studio Director: Geoffry Zatkin | Social Media: Kat Rider | ♪ Music by Demetori: http://bit.ly/1EQA5N7 |

#ExtraHistory #European #History]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Africa - Hotspot of the Cold War | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OoGhXmDVv0Y</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/OoGhXmDVv0Y?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:00:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In the collective memory, the Cold War is the conflict between the United States and the Soviet Union. However, one thing is often forgotten: the two superpowers also set their sights on the African continent.

To this day, the Cold War is remembered as an East-West conflict that was fought in the form of proxy and guerrilla wars in Asia and Latin America. However, one aspect of this confrontation is often forgotten: the United States and the Soviet Union also set their sights on Africa, which became a new arena for their power struggle, against the backdrop of decolonization. 
Left-wing political forces gained strength in African countries in the 1960s. Moscow seized the opportunity and invested heavily in East African Somalia, for example. The situation was similar in Angola. And Moscow triumphed.
With Ronald Reagan as the new president, the United States began preparing its return to the African continent in 1981. The timing was favorable, as communism had been devastating in Africa: the collectivization of agriculture in Ethiopia, for example, led to a famine that cost 500,000 people their lives. 
As more and more African countries turned away from the Soviet model, Moscow could only stand by and watch. Ultimately, Mikhail Gorbachev's reforms could not prevent the collapse of the USSR in 1991.
The end of the East-West conflict offered many countries in Africa the opportunity to take control of their own destiny once again. However, to avoid being exploited and manipulated by world powers once more, the continent had to learn the lessons of the Cold War era.


#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How a Small Wine Importer Smashed Trump’s Tariffs</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ChdQciz1gns</link><author>Patrick Boyle</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ChdQciz1gns?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:30:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFASM0cgfkJxQ1ICmRilfHLw">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Check out Even Realities ➡️ https://evenrealities.bio/1998a1

#EvenRealities#EvenG2#EvenR1#MyEvenG2#everydaydisplay#smartglasses#aiglasses#displaysmartglasses

In this episode, we explore the legal and economic fallout of the Supreme Court's landmark decision to strike down the "Liberation Day" tariffs, a move that has left the administration scrambling for a "Plan B". We dive into the "David vs. Goliath" story of VOS Selections, the tiny wine importer that successfully challenged the President's use of emergency powers, and examine why the new 10% flat-rate replacement may actually provide a competitive boost to China and Brazil while penalizing America's closest allies. From the bizarre world of "National Security Cabinets" to the $175 billion refund headache currently being exploited by "vulture" investors, we break down how tweeting out tariffs met its match in the U.S. Constitution.

Patrick's Books:
Statistics For The Trading Floor:  https://amzn.to/3eerLA0
Derivatives For The Trading Floor:  https://amzn.to/3cjsyPF
Corporate Finance:  https://amzn.to/3fn3rvC 

Ways To Support The Channel
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/PatrickBoyleOnFinance
Buy Me a Coffee: https://www.buymeacoffee.com/patrickboyle

Visit our website: https://www.onfinance.org
Follow Patrick on Twitter Here: https://bsky.app/profile/pboyle.bsky.social

Business Inquiries ➡️ sponsors@onfinance.org

Patrick Boyle On Finance Podcast:
Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/7uhrWlDvxzy9hLoW0EYf0b
Apple: https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/patrick-boyle-on-finance/id1547740313
Google Podcasts: https://tinyurl.com/62862nve

Join this channel to support making this content:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCASM0cgfkJxQ1ICmRilfHLw/join]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What&apos;s Jazz Doing In A Knight Of The Seven Kingdoms?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fqVm6mr5b-w</link><author>Nerdwriter1</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/fqVm6mr5b-w?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 15:30:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFJkMlOu7faDgqh4PfzbpLdg">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://www.squarespace.com/nerdwriter for 10% off your first purchase.
MY BOOK: https://amzn.to/3ymfQPV

SOURCES

Genette, Gérard. Narrative Discourse: An Essay in Method. Translated by Jane E. Lewin, Foreword by Jonathan Culler, Cornell University Press, 1980.

Genette, Gérard. Paratexts: Thresholds of Interpretation. Translated by Jane E. Lewin, Cambridge University Press, 1997.

Cook, James, Alexander Kolassa, and Adam Whittaker. “Music in Fantasy Pasts: Neomedievalism and Game of Thrones.” Representations of Early Music on Stage and Screen: Recomposing the Past, edited by James Cook, Alexander Kolassa, and Adam Whittaker, Routledge, 2018, pp. 13–42.

Re, Valentina. “The Monster at the End of This Book: Metalepsis, Fandom, and World Making in Contemporary TV Series.” World Building, edited by Marta Boni, Amsterdam University Press, 2017, pp. 321–42. JSTOR, https://doi.org/10.2307/j.ctt1zkjz0m.21

Hahn, James. “Game of Thrones: George R. R. Martin Isn’t Finished — Author Talks Thrones, Winds, Dragon and Knight.” The Hollywood Reporter, 15 Jan. 2026,
https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-features/george-rr-martin-interview-thrones-winds-dragon-knight-1236473519/

Hein, Daniel. “George R.R. Martin Confronted About The Winds of Winter at Worldcon 2025.” ScreenRant, 17 Aug. 2025, https://screenrant.com/george-rr-martin-confronted-winds-winter-worldcon-2025/

Landais, Clotilde. “The Narrative Metalepsis as an Instrument of the Uncanny in Contemporary Fantastic Fiction.” Journal of the Fantastic in the Arts, vol. 28, no. 2 (99), 2017, pp. 236–52. JSTOR, https://www.jstor.org/stable/26499449

MUSIC (via Epidemic Sound)

Nagisa - Hara Noda
The Fairy Dance - Bonnie Grace
Final Clarity - Stefan Ekstrom
To the End of the Line STEMS MELODY - Rachel Sandy]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rep. Ro Khanna takes on the “Epstein class” | Today, Explained</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7ciJkd3R-yo</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7ciJkd3R-yo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 13:00:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Our politics are deeply divided — there’s Democrat vs. Republican, there’s left vs. right. But maybe the biggest divide in our politics is the insider vs. outsider divide.

That’s only gotten more noticeable in recent months, as issues like the Epstein files and artificial intelligence have pitted the elites against everyone else. Rep. Ro Khanna (D-CA) is at the center of both of those issues. He wrote the Epstein Files Transparency Act. He brought one of Jeffrey Epstein’s abuse survivors to this week's State of the Union address. And he’s coined the term “the Epstein class” — the group of wealthy and connected individuals that he wants to bring to accountability. Even if they’re fellow Democrats.

Khanna represents Silicon Valley in his district, so he has worked with companies like Google and Meta for years. That puts him at the forefront of one of the important political and economic questions of the coming year: Is AI about to put us all out of work? And is the government prepared to do anything about it?

00:00 Intro
1:52 Advocating for Epstein survivors
4:31 Forcing the release of the Epstein Files
5:23 Pushing for a vote on Iran strikes
6:32 Should Dems work with Trump?
9:41 Holding the “Epstein class” accountable
15:03 Should Dems have done more to stop Epstein?
18:10 Tech leaders and income inequality
19:03 Is there an AI tsunami?
19:42 Are Dems anti-AI?
22:00 CA tax on billionaires
23:56 Is Khanna making a presidential bid?

Today, Explained publishes video episodes every Saturday tackling key issues in politics and culture. Subscribe to Vox’s YouTube channel to get them. New episodes of Today, Explained drop every day of the week on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, or your favorite listening app.

If you enjoy our reporting and want to hear more from Vox journalists, sign up for our Patreon at patreon.com/vox. Each month, our members get access to exclusive videos, livestreams, and chats with our newsroom.

Subscribe to our channel! http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on Facebook: http://goo.gl/U2g06o
Or Twitter: http://goo.gl/XFrZ5H]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ATK Hex80 review (Owlab Ti Magnetic)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=czI7ZKpDtFk</link><author>Chyrosran22</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/czI7ZKpDtFk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 06:00:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFD0y51PJfvkZNe3y3FR5riw">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Skip to 8:01 for a typing demonstration. 
Today we look the ATK Hex80, an interesting combination of a rather conservatively styled case with very showy keycaps and RGB. Hope you enjoy the video! :)

Intro by Kyle Carter
Outro by Facundo Cabanne

My keyboard reviews: http://bit.ly/1TbOtft
My switch teardowns: http://bit.ly/2C1QGHz
My TOP X videos: http://bit.ly/2FmpZfd
My XL typing demos: https://bit.ly/2OoAW3w
My tutorials and featurettes: https://bit.ly/2OrkLUh
My unboxing videos: https://bit.ly/2TSrr0m

I'm Thomas and I do videos and reviews on mechanical keyboards ranging from the most sickening modern RGB gaming keyboards to vintage hardware relics, or sometimes keycaps or keyswitches ranging from Cherry MX to Alps SKCM to IBM buckling springs and anything in between.

Follow me on Twitter for updates on my keyboard videos! https://twitter.com/chyrosran22

The practice sentence was: "Hello my name is Thomas and I'm typing on an ATK Gear Hex80 keyboard right now. This thing lights up like a Christmas tree even though the chassis looks so clean - an interesting idea!"]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Cop Reaches Into Box, Loses It When He Realizes What&apos;s Inside</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Ghe55PHc58</link><author>EXPLORE WITH US</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6Ghe55PHc58?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 02:31:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFJWKjrrUh2KL1d3zXQW79cQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In today's true crime documentary, we're covering the case of Devin O'Brien.

We are a news agency dedicated to delivering factual reporting on criminal investigations, public safety, and law enforcement procedures.

This video is a documentary intended to inform and educate viewers about real events of public concern.

It was produced for journalistic and educational purposes, and is presented in the public interest.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Rev. Jesse Jackson on Barack Obama as a presidential candidate</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EqRZmzBheg4</link><author>FRONTLINE PBS | Official</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EqRZmzBheg4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:00:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULF3ScyryU9Oy9Wse3a8OAmYQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Rev. Jesse Jackson (1941-2026) was a civil rights icon who launched two U.S. presidential campaigns, in 1984 and 1988, ending the second run as the runner-up for the Democratic nomination — two decades before Barack Obama became the first Black major party presidential nominee, and subsequently, the first Black U.S. president.

Jackson spoke to FRONTLINE’s Jim Gilmore on Aug. 13, 2008, for our documentary, "The Choice 2008," which you can watch here: https://www.pbs.org/wgbh/frontline/documentary/choice2008/

This journalism is made possible by viewers like you. Donate to FRONTLINE now: https://bit.ly/47DFzCb

And support your local PBS station here: https://www.pbs.org/donate

Jackson had worked alongside the Rev. Martin Luther King, Jr. in the Southern Christian Leadership Conference, and was appointed to lead Operation Breadbasket, a program aimed at addressing economic concerns of Black Americans. In the years after King’s assassination, Jackson formed the Rainbow PUSH Coalition, a civil rights organization pushing for equity in the economic and political spheres for Black Americans. He died in February 2026 at the age of 84.

The interview has been edited for length and clarity. See a more complete description of our process here: https://to.pbs.org/4lVZKzA

This interview is being published as part of FRONTLINE’s Transparency Project, an effort to open up the source material behind our documentaries. Read more about this project here: https://www.pbs.org/wgbh/frontline/about-frontlines-transparency-project/

Explore more of our extended interviews in this playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL_pPc6-qR9ZzEepVsKZsT58XiLb38Tttr

#JesseJackson #BarackObama #USPolitics

Subscribe on YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/user/PBSfrontline
Sign up for our newsletter: https://frontline.org/newsletter
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/frontlinepbs
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/frontline
Bluesky: https://bsky.app/profile/frontlinepbs.bsky.social

FRONTLINE is produced at GBH in Boston and airs nationwide on PBS.

The editor-in-chief and executive producer of FRONTLINE is Raney Aronson-Rath.

Funding for FRONTLINE is provided through the support of PBS viewers and by the Corporation for Public Broadcasting, with major support from Ford Foundation. Additional support for FRONTLINE is provided by the Abrams Foundation, Park Foundation, John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, Heising-Simons Foundation, and the FRONTLINE Trust, with major support from Jon and Jo Ann Hagler on behalf of the Jon L. Hagler Foundation, and additional support from Koo and Patricia Yuen.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Prison for Profit: 400 Years a Slave</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GgGGkqjWkj4</link><author>Georg Rockall-Schmidt</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/GgGGkqjWkj4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 20:55:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFG5h8yHSUS4n7zPnh0dG0SA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[For-profit prisons have been marketed as a cheap solution to prison overcrowding, but they wouldn't exist without the foundations of slavery, convict leasing, prison plantations, the war on drugs, the war on terror, and now, immigration detention. This is the story of private, for-profit prisons in America.

Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/GeorgRockallSchmidt 
Leave a tip: paypal.me/GeorgRockallSchmidt 
Twitter: https://twitter.com/grockallschmidt 
Bluesky: https://bsky.app/profile/grockallschmidt.bsky.social

Sources

Bauer, S. (2019). American prison: A reporter's undercover journey into the business of punishment. New York: Penguin Books.

Blackmon, D. A. (2013). Slavery by another name: The re-enslavement of Black Americans from the Civil War to World War II. Anchor Books. 

https://www.pbs.org/show/slavery-another-name/ 

https://blogs.loc.gov/inside_adams/2021/06/convict-leasing-system/ 

https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2016/06/history-of-americas-private-prison-industry-timeline/ 

https://www.austinchronicle.com/news/plantations-to-prison-farms-how-far-have-we-come-12946341/ 

https://time.com/5405158/the-true-history-of-americas-private-prison-industry/ 

https://lithub.com/the-straight-line-from-slavery-to-private-prisons/ 

https://www.themarshallproject.org/2015/05/01/prison-plantations 

https://www.texasstandard.org/stories/texas-plantation-prisons-history-forced-labor-tdcj-farms-convict-leasing/ 

https://www.searchablemuseum.com/black-codes/#black-codes-after-the-civil-war 

https://jimcrowmuseum.ferris.edu/timeline/slavery.htm#:~:text=Civil%20War%20began.-,The%201860%20census%20showed%20the%20black%20population%20of%20the%20United,were%20enslaved%20and%20488%2C070%20free.&text=1863%20January%201-,President%20Abraham%20Lincoln%20issued%20the%20Emancipation%20Proclamation%2C%20which%20made%20it,slavery%20in%20the%20United%20States 

https://www.aaihs.org/convict-leasing-in-the-fami-ly/#:~:text=This%20system%20of%20racial%20capitalism%20was%20akin,and%20discipline%20convicts%20on%20their%20own%20terms 

https://www.georgiaencyclopedia.org/articles/government-politics/bourbon-triumvirate/ 

https://www.columbusstate.edu/archives/_docs/gah/1990/117-125.pdf 

https://www.columbusstate.edu/archives/_docs/gah/1990/117-125.pdf 
Convict Leasing After Slavery
https://picturingblackhistory.org/convict-leas-ing/#:~:text=Ultimately%2C%20through%20the%20work%20of%20Black%20activists,did%20not%20end%20the%20practice%20until%201928 

https://canyonvista.com/blog/is-there-link-joblessness-addiction/ 

https://spia.princeton.edu/news/princeton-policy-advocacy-clinic-students-release-analysis-federal-crack-powder-cocaine 

https://civilrights.org/blog/americas-war-on-drugs-50-years-later/# 

https://drugabusestatistics.org/drug-related-crime-statistics/ 

https://www.washingtonpost.com/posteverything/wp/2015/04/28/how-for-profit-prisons-have-become-the-biggest-lobby-no-one-is-talking-about/ 

https://www.opensecrets.org/industries/lobbying?cycle=2024&ind=G7000 

https://www.migrationpolicy.org/article/profiting-enforcement-role-private-prisons-us-immigration-detention 

https://www.nilc.org/articles/the-2025-reconciliation-bill-allows-private-prison-execs-to-cash-in-on-cruelty/ 

https://stateline.org/2025/04/11/for-profit-immigration-detention-expands-as-trump-accelerates-his-deportation-plans/ 

https://www.nytimes.com/2016/08/19/us/us-to-phase-out-use-of-private-prisons-for-federal-inmates.html 

https://abcnews.go.com/US/private-prison-firms-contributed-1m-trumps-reelection-now/story?id=116046776 

https://www.prisonlegalnews.org/in-the-news/2017/pln-quoted-re-private-prison-industry/ 

https://www.brennancenter.org/our-work/analysis-opinion/private-prison-companies-enormous-windfall-who-stands-gain-ice-expands 

https://www.opensecrets.org/news/2025/04/private-prison-companies-positioned-to-benefit-from-increased-deportations/ 

https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/01/us/prisons-immigration-detention.html 

https://prismreports.org/2025/10/23/private-prison-executives-revel-in-ice-arrests/ 

https://theappeal.org/geo-group-earnings-mass-deportations/ 

https://www.brennancenter.org/our-work/analysis-opinion/what-trumps-victory-means-private-prison-industry 

https://www.wusf.org/politics-issues/2026-02-09/migrants-languish-in-us-detention-centers-facing-dire-conditions-and-prolonged-waits 

https://ccrjustice.org/sites/default/files/attach/2019/05/2015_Banking_on_Detention_DWN_CCR.pdf 

https://azmirror.com/2025/04/08/ice-director-envisions-amazon-like-mass-deportation-system-prime-but-with-human-beings/ 

https://www.mlive.com/news/2026/02/owner-of-michigan-ice-detention-center-reported-254m-profit-last-year.html 

https://theappeal.org/ice-geo-group-corecivic-profits/ 

https://investors.geogroup.com/news-releases/news-release-details/geo-group-reports-fourth-quarter-and-full-year-2025-results]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Surprising Way Leopard Geckos Mate | Life in Cold Blood | BBC Earth Science</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O82SyuHI1zQ</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/O82SyuHI1zQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 19:00:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Sir David Attenborough gives us unique insight into the leopard gecko's elaborate courtship routine and temperature-based sex determination of their eggs. 

Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

Taken from: Life in Cold Blood (2008)

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ingmar Bergman - The Master of Cinematic Emotion</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T1kGIcPvPbg</link><author>The House of Tabula</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/T1kGIcPvPbg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 18:24:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFL5kBJmBUVFLYBDiSiK1VDw">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This is an analysis of the career and techniques of master filmmaker Ingmar Bergman. How his unique lens turned inward toward the human condition in a way that no filmmaker had achieved or has achieved since. 

Support The House of Tabula (and join our Discord Film Club):
https://www.patreon.com/c/thehouseoftabula

Join this channel to get access to perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCL5kBJmBUVFLYBDiSiK1VDw/join
———————————
🎬 Deep Dive Film Club 
———————————
🎞️ All 30+ episodes: https://tinyurl.com/4kf9kjjd
🎥 The Film Club series: https://tinyurl.com/4hu3p89d
There Will Be Blood: https://tinyurl.com/2uwxewfy
Tetsuo: The Iron Man: https://tinyurl.com/336x9rec
—————————————————
💊 Acid is Bad for Business Podcast
—————————————————
All 70+ episodes: https://tinyurl.com/3r3kjw3w
Socialmediaocracy: https://tinyurl.com/mjdx75wu
Keep Robert De Niro Close, But Viola Davis Closer: https://tinyurl.com/9fmtb98y
The Artwork of the 21st Century: https://tinyurl.com/459c4vzu
————————————————————
⚔️ Exclusive Uncensored Essays & Workshops
—————————————————————
Join our Composition for Cinema & Visual Arts Workshop: https://tinyurl.com/2s4evptm
Over 20+ Uncensored Essays: https://tinyurl.com/3esebpew
💀 The Allure of the New Profane: https://tinyurl.com/2w6dsxzv
☕ Content with the Veneer of Depth: https://tinyurl.com/4fy83wyj
———————————————————————
For business inquiries: contact@thehouseoftabula.com
———————————————————————
TIMESTAMPS:
0:00 - Why Bergman Matters
4:23 - Bergman's Phases - From Exterior to Interior
15:37 - Techniques to Construct The Inner World
30:01 - Bergman's Cinema as Existential Enquiry]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Violence against women in India - A system of inequality | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sbWCiX_ys3s</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/sbWCiX_ys3s?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:01:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In India, more than 80 women are raped every day. This number is probably just the tip of the iceberg. In most cases, the crimes are not reported - whether out of shame, fear of the perpetrator, or mistrust of the police and the justice system.

In the west of the country, in the wealthy and conservative state of Gujarat, the story of 17-year-old Kinjal portrays an India in which rape is apparently considered a "trivial offense.” 
Three years ago, the young girl, who belongs to the Dalit community - a group considered "untouchables,” who occupy the lowest social status, at the bottom of the caste system -- was raped by the son of a landowner from a higher caste. 
To cover up the incident, the rapist's family offered Kinjal's parents land and 100,000 euros - a fortune. But Kinjal's father rejected the compromise, preferring to take the case to court. 
This rare act of courage was considered an affront by the higher castes. As a sign of his struggle, he decided not to cut his hair again until the perpetrator was convicted. 
Kinjal and her family were supported by Manjula Pradeep. The activist, who is also a Dalit, has dedicated her life to defending women who have been raped. Her goal, as yet unattained, is that each victim she helps will be the last. 
For six months, a camera crew accompanied Kinjal and her family in their search for justice. A glimpse behind the scenes in India, where the violence of the caste system and the weight of tradition determine the lives of hundreds of millions of women.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #india 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What It Actually Takes to Run a Broadway Show Every Night | WSJ</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NPQO353bUaQ</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NPQO353bUaQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:00:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Broadway has long been a place where audiences come to put their fears aside and sit together to be entertained, even in times of war, recession and uncertainty. Today, it’s also a billion-dollar industry powered by thousands of workers across 41 theaters in New York’s Times Square theater district. 

WSJ spent a day in the life of a Broadway electrician in the lead up to a “Chicago” show to reveal the machine behind this American art form—from the factory floor to a nearly sold-out curtain call. 

Chapters: 
0:00 – Broadway's influence 
1:00 – 8:00am: Morning routine
3:23 – 11:00am: Scenic shop
4:30 – 1:00pm: Lighting tests
5:32 – 2:00pm: Visit the loading bays
6:33 – 5:00pm: Ambassador Theatre and “Chicago” pre-show checks
9:14 – 6:15pm: Doors open and show starts
9:53 – 9:15pm: “Chicago” ends

#Broadway #Theatre #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Most Shocking Moments In History | Compilation</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GSkKbe_Y96Y</link><author>Weird History</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/GSkKbe_Y96Y?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFc-N24Y5OA0gqbjBwe1ttfA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[History is FULL of shocking moments. In the past, they were written about, then came video. Today we are offering a compilation of some of the more shocking moments in hour history - Wild events caught on Live TV, Shocking Facts about the Death of John Lennon, crazy deathbed confessions, and even getting into the history of Cannibalism! What do you find crazy in this world of ours? Let us know in the comments! 



Chapters: 
00:00:00 - 10 Most Shocking Events That Happened On Live TV 
00:10:11 - Shocking Facts About John Lennon's Death 
00:21:00 - The Original Wizard of Oz Books Are Shockingly Violent 
00:26:05 - The Shockingly Dark History of Chippendales 
00:37:31 - The Most Shocking Deathbed Confessions In History 
00:48:21 - Shocking Facts About the Space Shuttle Challenger Disaster 
00:59:07 - The Shocking History of Lipstick, The Outlawed Royal Cosmetic 
01:09:52 - The Shocking History of Cannibalism 

Be sure to subscribe to the Weird History Newsletter: https://bit.ly/WeirdHistoryNews

#shockingmoments #compilation #weirdhistory]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Pretty Fly for a Spy Pi</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2LayXUxMjPU</link><author>Jeff Geerling</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2LayXUxMjPU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 15:00:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFR-DXc1voovS8nhAvccRZhg">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[I more than doubled the performance of my NVR with a new CM5 board. And it has PoE+ built in!

Some of the resources I referenced in this video (some links are affiliate links):

  - Exaviz Cruiser: https://exa-pedia.com/docs/cruiser/
  - Frigate: https://frigate.video
  - Seagate IronWolf NAS 4TB HDD: https://amzn.to/46vIPyx
  - Hard Drive sleds (Dell R720-compatible): https://www.ebay.com/itm/404293056771
  - DeskPi 2U mini rack mount: https://deskpi.com/products/deskpi-2u-mini-rack-mount-case-pre-order-for-the-exaviz-cruiser-carrier-board
  - My 1U Interceptor NVR build from 2024: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7wkVGcdI2vk
  - Blog post configuring Hailo and Frigate on Pi CM5: https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2026/frigate-with-hailo-for-object-detection-on-a-raspberry-pi/

Exaviz sent me a prototype version of the Cruiser for testing, and DeskPi sent an early prototype of their mini rack case for the Cruiser. Neither company paid for this video or had any input in its production, but I still mark my videos as 'sponsored' if any equipment was provided by vendors in the making of the video. See my sponsorship policies here: https://github.com/geerlingguy/youtube#sponsorships

Support me on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/geerlingguy
Sponsor me on GitHub: https://github.com/sponsors/geerlingguy
Merch: https://www.redshirtjeff.com
2nd Channel: https://www.youtube.com/@GeerlingEngineering
3rd Channel: https://www.youtube.com/@Level2Jeff

Contents:

00:00 - Upgrading from the Interceptor
00:38 - Exaviz Cruiser CM5 board
01:57 - Adding another camera
02:46 - Google abandoned the Coral TPU
04:27 - Cruiser's USB-heavy architecture
06:08 - Building the mini-rack server
07:43 - Tada! And some hot-swap drive sleds
09:02 - Setting up RAID, Hailo, and Frigate
10:53 - Power consumption, PoE, and a 4K camera
12:17 - Future Home Assistant plans]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Gen Z men want babies. Gen Z women don’t. | The Gray Area</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k_tSL4L01i4</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/k_tSL4L01i4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:01:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A lot of Gen Z men sound surprisingly excited about fatherhood. A lot of Gen Z women…do not. 

And that divide — and the national handwringing about it — says a lot about the changing status of men and women in this country, and the uncomfortable realization that for American policymakers, not all children are created equal. 

Today’s guest on The Gray Area is Vox reporter and bestselling novelist Anna North, who covers kids, parenting, and American family life. She writes the Vox newsletter Kids Today, and her latest chart-topping novel is Bog Queen. She recently reported on the gap between young men and young women on parenthood and what that might tell us about gender roles, relationships, and the future of family formation in a politically polarized country.

Host: Sean Illing (@SeanIlling)
Guest: Anna North, Staff Writer, Vox

3:30 The poll that revealed a massive parenting gender gap in Gen Z.
11:20 Why "Tradwife" content and traditional values are finding a new audience.
15:43 The Gen Z family split
23:11 The "Care Crisis" and the trauma of modern immigration enforcement on children.
26:15 The future of the American family in 2026 and beyond.

We would love to hear from you. To tell us what you thought of this episode, email us at thegrayarea@vox.com or leave us a voicemail at 1-800-214-5749. Your comments and questions help us make a better show. 

And you can watch new episodes of The Gray Area on YouTube. New episodes drop every Monday and Friday.

Listen to The Gray Area ad-free by becoming a Vox Member: vox.com/members. 

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Subscribe to our channel! http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on Facebook: http://goo.gl/U2g06o
Or Twitter: http://goo.gl/XFrZ5H]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>SW Design, Architecture &amp; Clarity at Scale • Sam Newman, Jacqui Read &amp; Simon Rohrer</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vUL7iijIqes</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vUL7iijIqes?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:27:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This conversation was recorded at GOTO Copenhagen 2025.
https://gotocph.com

Sam Newman - Author of Building Microservices & Monolith to Microservices
Jacqui Read - Author of Communication Patterns: A Guide for Developers and Architects
Simon Rohrer - Global Head of Enterprise Tech Architecture and Ways of Thinking

ORIGINAL TALK TITLE
Software Design, Architecture & Giving Clarity at Scale

RESOURCES
Sam
https://twitter.com/samnewman
https://www.linkedin.com/in/samnewman
http://samnewman.io
http://samnewman.io/blog
https://github.com/snewman

Jacqui
https://bsky.app/profile/tekiegirl.bsky.social
https://jacquiread.com
https://fosstodon.org/@tekiegirl
https://www.linkedin.com/in/jacquelineread
https://github.com/tekiegirl

Simon
https://bsky.app/profile/simon.bvssh.com
https://mastodon.social/@simonr
https://x.com/sirohrer
https://www.linkedin.com/in/simonrohrer
https://github.com/sirohrer
https://www.soonersaferhappier.com

Links
https://acedmodel.com

ABSTRACT
In this session, we will explore the nature of software design - what is it, and where is the intersection with architecture? We’ll also look at the importance of communicating context, design, and architecture across an organization.

If you’d like to do some advanced reading, head over to acedmodel.com for more.

Both Jacqui and Simon will be sharing their expertise and experiences, but this session is also all about your questions. Come along, and get involved! [...]

Read the full abstract here:
https://gotocph.com/2025/sessions/3932

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Jacqui Read • Communication Patterns • https://amzn.to/3E37lvv
Sam Newman • Building Resilient Distributed Systems • https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/building-resilient-distributed/9781098163532
Sam Newman • Monolith to Microservices • https://amzn.to/2Nml96E
Sam Newman • Building Microservices • https://amzn.to/3dMPbOs
Jonathan Smart, Zsolt Berend, Myles Ogilvie & Simon Rohrer • Sooner Safer Happier • https://amzn.to/3Emm9p2


Bluesky (https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com) 
Twitter (https://twitter.com/GOTOcon) 
Instagram (https://www.instagram.com/goto_con) 
LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-) 
Facebook (https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences) 

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket: gotopia.tech (https://gotopia.tech) 

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR YOUTUBE CHANNEL (https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1)  - new videos posted daily!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The 3-Ingredient Sauce That Elevates ANY Chicken (Watercress Butter)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DFEdc8RQgDw</link><author>French Cooking Academy</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/DFEdc8RQgDw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:00:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULF0lG3Ihe4LGV851lODRIS5g">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get our free eBook: ►https://french-cooking-academy.myflodesk.com/hb6z0zrnq5
Want to join my cooking community  ➡️ https://www.thefrenchcookingacademy.com/fcaclub

Want restaurant-quality chicken at home? Today we are making a brilliant recipe from legendary Swiss Chef Frédy Girardet. We are using the French "concentration" poaching technique to lock in the juices, served with a vibrant, creamy Watercress Compound Butter sauce. This technique will change the way you cook chicken forever!

⏱️ CHAPTERS (Skip to the recipe!):
0:00 The Secret to French Poached Chicken
1:00 How to Make Watercress Compound Butter
4:20 The French "Concentration" Poaching Method
6:41 Prepping the Aromatic Vegetables
8:50 Making the Creamy Pan Sauce
11:53 Plating & Taste Test

GET THE RECIPE  ➡️ https://www.thefrenchcookingacademy.com/recipes/chicken-with-creamy-watercress-sauce

🔔 Don't forget to SUBSCRIBE and hit the bell so you don't miss our midweek video where we turn today's leftover bouillon into an amazing zero-waste chicken sauce!

📌 In this video, you will learn:
• How to prep and process raw watercress for maximum flavor.
• How to make and roll a compound butter log.
• The "Concentration Method" for poaching meats in a hot stock.
• How to build a rich, glossy sauce using stock reduction, cream, and compound butter.
• Plating and pairing with boiled winter vegetables.


📺 Watch Next:
Missed Episode 1? Learn how to make a sauté chicken with prawn butter: https://youtu.be/49WsCIJakUg?si=69ug-YgsrrGpD0iS


SUPPORT US ON PATREON ❤️
Your support helps us keep creating these free video lessons for everyone to enjoy. 
► https://www.patreon.com/frenchcookingacademy

STAY IN TOUCH ✉️
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/french_cooking_academy
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/FrenchCookingAcademy
We love hearing from you! If you have any questions about this recipe, please leave them in the comments below.

ABOUT THE FRENCH COOKING ACADEMY 👨‍🍳
We believe that the joys of French cuisine should be accessible to everyone. Our channel is dedicated to teaching classic recipes and foundational techniques in a clear and approachable way, so you can create restaurant-quality meals for your friends and family. Subscribe and join us on this delicious journey!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How Trump&apos;s Tariffs Got a Reality Check</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0S35WwkQ6gQ</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0S35WwkQ6gQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 09:00:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Supreme Court’s ruling that Donald Trump illegally used an emergency law to launch his global trade war last April has thrown US trade policy into further turmoil. As the president scrambles to chart a new path, we look at what a year of threats, tariffs, retreats and deals both concrete and nebulous have accomplished. 

0:00 Introduction 
2:06 Supreme Court’s ruling
2:58 Refunds & prices
4:03 Trump’s economic goals
6:02 Foreign policy 
7:43 Midterms & what next

#trump #economy #supremecourt 
--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Mystery of the World&apos;s Strongest Drug</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hhjhU5MXZOo</link><author>fern</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hhjhU5MXZOo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 21:33:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFODHrzPMGbNv67e84WDZhQQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Head to https://betterhelp.com/fern for 10% off your first month of therapy with our paid partner, BetterHelp. Make your mental health and growth a positive focus this year. (ad)

This is dimethyltryptamine, known as DMT – arguably the world's strongest psychedelic drug.

Sources: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1rOMVSXqQWNBSiqnde7xnTKPv3F1wUcV0bP9ZnOYDZt8/edit?usp=sharing

0:00 - Intro
1:46 - Chapter 1: Deep in the Jungle
9:16 - Chapter 2: High in Switzerland
16:04 - Chapter 3: Subject 34 Ready for Takeoff
25:47 - Chapter 4: The Brain on DMT

Corrections:
09:43 Hofmann did not ingest "250 grams" of LSD. This should of course be "250 micrograms".

Music list:

Artlist:
Kyle Preston - Duality
Matooma - Get out Now
Onyx Music - Blue Dream
Alon Peretz - Pleasure and Pain; Is There Somebody Here; All Hope Abandon; Spiral
Theatre of Delays - Obsessions
Jimmy Svensson - No More Light
Itai Argaman - Longitude Travel; Heavens
Max H - War
Fabien Fustinoni - Between Light and Shadow
Master Minded - Feel
Michael Vignola - 3 Hours; Calling for You; Through the Past
KeMi - The Unknown - Creative Cut - Minimal
Yotam Agam - Aura 174 Hz; Qing Long
Jordan Hatfield - Light Shines
Quinten Coblentz - Babylon
Victor Spiegel - Ground Beneath
megks - Sundrops
Gruber - The Uprising
Out of Flux - darklouds
Jakub Pietras - Jungle Temple

Epidemic Sound:
Squiid - Dance of the Spirits
Johnny Berglund - Cellar Stellar
Christian Andersen - A Special Rite of Passage
Edward Karl Hanson - Manic and Me
Amber Glow - Waves of Time
Flouw - By Heart and Spirit
Out To The World - Luxx; Bulletin World; Adaption
Sarah, the Illstrumentalist - Drop Top Down
Niklas Gabrielsson with Martin Landstrom & His Orchestra - Myself and I
(Instrumental Version)
The Best Ofs - Cadillac Quiff Boys
Parallax Deep - Northern Lights
Johan Glossner - Wap Away
Luella Gren - The Murdered Dancer
Lennon Hutton - Who's at the Window; Signs; Echo 
Ruiqi Zhao - Strings Attached
Max Anson - Where Does It End
Experia - Underlying Cause; Deception Uncovered
Ritchie Everett - Where to Next
Stationary Sign - Manhattan Mystery
Pulsed - Emoticon
Helmut Schenker - Dragonflies
Dream Cave - Into the Maze
baegel - My Ringtone Is a Voice Memo of You Last Summer
John B. Lund - Shadowed
Broad Sky - Tree of Life
David Celeste - Kokoku
Craft Case - Mind Your Step
Brotin - Transparent Bathtub

Other:
The Beatles - Revolution


_____
Armchair documentaries, almost weekly]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>New Scan of Titanic Wreck Reveals Secrets Hidden for a Century</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qW1R1_VpeoE</link><author>History Hit</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/qW1R1_VpeoE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Titanic scan reveals ground-breaking details of ship's final hours with @Magellan-gg 

Join historians Dan Snow and Tim Maltin as they delve into the Titanic’s wreck site, guided by Magellan’s cutting-edge 2022 scan.

Built from over 700,000 individual photographs, this extraordinary “point cloud” is the most detailed scan of the Titanic ever captured, offering everyone the opportunity to explore the wreck from the safety of their own homes.

Want to find out more about Magellan, the team behind these remarkable scans? You can find out more on the below links:

Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/MagellanLtd 

Magellan Youtube: https://www.youtube.com/@Magellan-gg/featured

And for those interested, you can dive in for yourself via the Titanic ROV Pilot on steam:

https://store.steampowered.com/app/3397800/vROVpilot_TITANIC/

00:01:24 The Stern
00:02:35 The Ship Splitting 
00:04:03 The Debris Field
00:04:52 The Handrail 
00:05:48 Port Holes
00:07:00 The Boilers
00:12:55 Lifeboat Davits
00:16:38 Cargo Cranes
00:19:32 Engine Cylinder 
00:22:52 Water Tank
00:24:15 Engine Room Hatch 
00:28:32 Steam Whistle
00:32:32 Recovery Basket 

You can now become a History Hit member right here on YouTube! Join for access to a new exclusive documentary every week, and access to over 160+ of our documentaries presented by world-renowned historians like Dan Snow, Eleanor Janega, Tristan Hughes, Mary Beard, Matt Lewis and more.

Get an exclusive release every week by signing up here: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZwU2G-KVl-P-O-B35chZOQ/join

#titanic #titanichistory #titanicdisaster]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>China’s “Luanniao” Space Warship Concept</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Go8jCDGkE-g</link><author>Megaprojects</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Go8jCDGkE-g?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 18:50:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULF0woBco6Dgcxt0h8SwyyOmw">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Head to https://squarespace.com/megaprojects for a free trial, and when you’re ready to launch, use OFFER CODE MEGAPROJECTS to save 10% off your first purchase of a website or domain.

Got a beard? Good. I've got something for you: http://beardblaze.com

Simon's Social Media:
Twitter: https://twitter.com/SimonWhistler
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/simonwhistler/

This video is #sponsored by Squarespace.

Love content? Check out Simon's other YouTube Channels:


Warfronts: https://www.youtube.com/@warographics643
SideProjects: https://www.youtube.com/@Sideprojects
Into The Shadows: https://www.youtube.com/@IntotheShadows
Today I Found Out: https://www.youtube.com/@TodayIFoundOut
Highlight History: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnb-VTwBHEV3gtiB9di9DZQ
Brain Blaze: https://www.youtube.com/@brainblaze6526
Casual Criminalist: https://www.youtube.com/@TheCasualCriminalist
Decoding the Unknown: https://www.youtube.com/@decodingtheunknown2373
Places: https://www.youtube.com/@Places302
Celestium: https://www.youtube.com/@astrographics-ve4yq
PoliticalFronts: http://www.youtube.com/@politicalfronts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>When open-sourcing your code goes wrong...</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wzzh7Not8XE</link><author>Fireship</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wzzh7Not8XE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 18:26:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFsBjURrPoezykLs9EqgamOA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Try out CodeRabbit’s AI code reviewer with custom PR summaries - https://coderabbit.link/fireship. It’s free forever for any open source project.

Everything you use on the internet today is built on the shoulders of OSS - but not every open-source project makes it. Let's take a look at 5 open-source projects that achieved a meteoric rise and then crashed out under the weight of their own success.

#coding #programming #oss  

🔖 Topics Covered
- Mutable Instruments
- Faker.js
- Meteor
- OpenSolaris
- Netscape

Want more Fireship?

🗞️ Newsletter: https://bytes.dev
🧠 Courses: https://fireship.dev]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Is Uranus Actually a Rock Giant?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wKcMvR2C0oA</link><author>Astrum</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wKcMvR2C0oA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 17:08:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULF-9b7aDP6ZN0coj9-xFnrtw">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[New discoveries about Uranus reveal something surprising hidden inside its core.
Join the adventure with Alex and discover more from DwarfLab at: https://bit.ly/3ObkGXK. And don't forget to use the code ASTRUM5 for 5% off!

▀▀▀▀▀▀

A rare alignment is approaching, offering a fresh opportunity to study Uranus. Although only visited once by Voyager 2, cutting-edge telescopes and modern data methods mean new discoveries are still pouring in. So what is really hiding beneath the clouds of this mysterious pale blue giant?

▀▀▀▀▀▀

0:00 Uranus Update
4:10 Ice Giant or Rock Giant?
6:44 Uranus’s Bizarre Storms
11:05 Coldest Planet?
13:03 Protoplanet Collision
14:39 Corkscrew Magneto-tail 
17:24 New Moons
19:19 Bullseye Rings
20:57 2025 Occultation

▀▀▀▀▀▀

To stay on top of space news, sign up to the Astrum newsletter: https://astrumspace.kit.com 
 
Astrum Displate Posters: https://displate.com/astrumspace?art=5f04759ac338b  
Astrum Merch: https://astrum-shop.fourthwall.com/ 

Join us on the Astrum discord: https://discord.gg/TKw8Hpvtv8 

A huge thanks to our Patreons who help make these videos possible. Sign-up here to support the channel: https://bit.ly/4aiJZNF 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Astrum Podcast on Spotify: https://open.spotify.com/show/6jPRrbq3o3dpvBb173ZTKi?si=a90d3efe3b704c83 

Astrum Earth: https://youtube.com/@AstrumEarth 
Astrum Extra: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumextra 

Astrum Spanish: https://www.youtube.com/@astrumespanol 
Astrum Portuguese: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChn_-OwvV63mr1yeUGvH-BQ 

▀▀▀▀▀▀

References:
Uranus Facts”, via science.nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/uranusfacts 
“Icy or Rocky? Convective or Stable?”, via arxiv.org https://astrumspace.info/uranusinterior 
“Record-Breaking Storm Activity on Uranus in 2014”, via adsabs.harvard.edu https://astrumspace.info/uranusstorms 
“20-Year Hubble Study of Uranus Yields New Atmospheric Insights”, via science.nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/hubbleuranus 
“Solar Wind Heating for Uranus: Decades-Long Mystery Solved”, via imperial.ac.uk https://astrumspace.info/uranussolarwind 
“The Energy Balance of Uranus”, via academic.oup.com https://astrumspace.info/uranusenergy 
“Giant Impact on Early Uranus”, via iopscience.iop.org https://astrumspace.info/uranusimpact 
“New Moon Discovered Orbiting Uranus Using NASA’s Webb Telescope”, via science.nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/webburanus 
“Uranus: Rings of Dark Particles”, via jpl.nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/uranusrings 
“Planetary Alignment Provides NASA Rare Opportunity to Study Uranus”, via nasa.gov https://astrumspace.info/uranusoccultation

▀▀▀▀▀▀

Credits:
Writer: Patricia Ward
Video Editor: Barnaby Egan
Researcher: Shourya Shrivastava
Script Editor: Damaris McColgan
Thumbnail Designer: Peter Sheppard
Publishing Lead: Georgina Brenner
Production Manager: Raquel Taylor
Edit Producer: Poppy Pinnock
Head of Astrum: Jess Jordan
Creator of Astrum: Alex McColgan

With special thanks to:
NASA/ESO/ESA

#Astrum #Space #Uranus]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Economic powerhouse China - How dependent is Europe? | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jzu3uVPIRiE</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Jzu3uVPIRiE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 17:00:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[China is pushing into European markets - and striving for ever greater military power. This has already had an impact on the internal and external security of Western countries. How dependent is Germany on China?

Fancy some iced tea? It'll be delivered by drone. A tree falls onto the road? The driverless taxi swerves out of the way. The rapid development of artificial intelligence and automation in the megacity of Shenzhen shows how high-tech China is integrating innovation into everyday life. Digitalization is everywhere, in a country where administrative procedures are carried out via mobile phone. 
But the example of Shenzhen also shows that western countries are in danger of being left behind by China in key technologies such as AI, robotics and electric cars. 
Behind all this advancement lies a great deal of state planning - as well as possible attempts to exert influence. 
This film shows how China is creating economic and technological dependencies, for example when it comes to so-called "rare earths" and "technology metals.” These are not only indispensable for photovoltaics, wind power and robotics: Many armaments also depend on these raw materials, which are supplied almost exclusively by China.
Chinese manufacturers of batteries and electric cars are also focusing on Hungary as a location to conquer the European market. Factories are being built there, partly to circumvent EU customs duties. The country is actively courting Chinese investment. Within the EU, Hungary repeatedly blocks tougher measures against China. This is putting pressure on Germany's automotive industry.
The film explores the question of how dependent Germany is on China and what risks this poses for security and cyber security. What are the strengths and weaknesses of this global power? China competes with the US for leadership in the world, and has long been a security policy challenge for the West. The documentary looks at the two countries’ economic ties, political goals and interrelations -- down to the hyper-local level. Experts from Europe, the US and China provide insights and answers.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #china #europe 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Vail Resorts Is Losing Skiers in a Growing Industry | WSJ</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GlcWwAcrsfI</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/GlcWwAcrsfI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 17:00:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Vail Resorts built the Epic Pass into a ski subscription model that drives nearly $1 billion in revenue before the ski season even starts each year. But today Vail’s resorts are facing growing competition from other passes and independent mountains, along with criticism over lift ticket prices and crowded slopes.

WSJ visited Vail Resorts to learn more about how they changed the economics of the entire ski industry and whether the mega pass model can keep growing.

Chapters:
0:00 The Epic pass
0:52 The ski industry and the intro of the ski pass
3:05 The early success of the ski pass
4:57 The criticism of the ski pass
6:39 The Indy pass and skiing at Whitefish Mountain 
9:08 Why Epic pass sales are plateauing 

#Vail #Skiing #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The biggest mistake lottery winners make</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wxf_pKCOCBo</link><author>TED-Ed</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wxf_pKCOCBo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 16:00:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFsooa4yRKGN_zEE8iknghZA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Dig into the pros and cons of annuity and lump sum lottery payouts, and find out the most common mistakes lottery winners make.

--

After winning the lottery, one of the first decisions you’d have to make is how you want your winnings to be paid out. You can choose the full jackpot amount, paid out in annual installments over 30 years. Or you can take a much smaller lump sum paid out immediately. So, which is the better option? Explore the financial implications of annuity and lump sum payments.

Directed by Anton Bogaty.

This video made possible in collaboration with Gifted Savings
Learn more about how TED-Ed partnerships work: https://bit.ly/TEDEdPartner

Support Our Non-Profit Mission
----------------------------------------------
Support us on Patreon: http://bit.ly/TEDEdPatreon
Check out our merch: http://bit.ly/TEDEDShop
----------------------------------------------

Connect With Us
----------------------------------------------
Sign up for our newsletter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdNewsletter
Follow us on Facebook: http://bit.ly/TEDEdFacebook
Find us on Twitter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdTwitter
Peep us on Instagram: http://bit.ly/TEDEdInstagram
----------------------------------------------

Keep Learning
----------------------------------------------
View full lesson: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/the-biggest-mistake-lottery-winners-make
Dig deeper with additional resources: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/the-biggest-mistake-lottery-winners-make/digdeeper

Animator's website: https://antonbogaty.com
Music: https://www.workplaywork.com
----------------------------------------------

Thank you so much to our patrons for your support! Without you this video would not be possible! Thomas Mungavan, Jaron Blackburn, Venkat Venkatakrishnan, ReuniteKorea, Aaron Henson, Rohan Gupta, Begum Tutuncu, Brian Richards, Jørgen Østerpart, Tyron Jung, Carsten Tobehn, Katie Dean, Ezgi Yersu, Gerald Onyango, alessandra tasso, Doreen Reynolds-Consolati, Manognya Chakrapani, Ayala Ron, Eunsun Kim, Phyllis Dubrow, Ophelia Gibson Best, Paul Schneider, Joichiro Yamada, Henrique Cassús, Karthik Cherala, Clarence E. Harper Jr., Vignan Velivela, Ana Maria, Exal Enrique Cisneros Tuch, Tejas Dc, Khalifa Alhulail, Martin Stephen, Jose Henrique Leopoldo e Silva, Mandeep Singh, Abhijit Kiran Valluri, Morgan Williams, Devin Harris, Pavel Zalevskiy, Karen Goepen-Wee, Filip Dabrowski, Barbara Smalley, Megan Douglas, Tim Leistikow, Ka-Hei Law, Hiroshi Uchiyama, Mark Morris, Misaki Sato, EdoKun, SookKwan Loong, and Bev Millar.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Nightmare Geography Glitch Hiding in New Hampshire</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TBHryws39sc</link><author>RealLifeLore</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/TBHryws39sc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 15:56:14 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFP5tjEmvPItGyLhmjdwP7Ww">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[🌏 Get Exclusive NordVPN deal + 4 months extra 
here → https://nordvpn.com/reallifelore It’s risk-free
with Nord’s 30-day money-back guarantee! 

Please subscribe: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP5tjEmvPItGyLhmjdwP7Ww

RealLifeLore on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/RealLifeLore/

Select video clips courtesy of Getty Images

Select video clips courtesy of the AP Archive

Special thanks to MapTiler / OpenStreetMap Contributors and GEOlayers 3

https://www.maptiler.com/copyright/
https://www.openstreetmap.org/copyright
https://aescripts.com/geolayers/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Learn Docker in a Month of Lunches • Elton Stoneman &amp; Bret Fisher • GOTO 2026</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7G7eEk7AZxw</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7G7eEk7AZxw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 13:00:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for the GOTO Book Club. #GOTOcon #GOTObookclub
http://gotopia.tech/bookclub

Check out more here:
https://gotopia.tech/episodes/428

Elton Stoneman - Freelance Consultant, Trainer & Author of "Learn Docker in a Month of Lunches" @EltonStoneman 
Bret Fisher - Docker Captain, Cloud Native Ambassador, Course Creator, YouTuber & Podcaster @BretFisher 

RESOURCES
Elton
https://bsky.app/profile/eltonstoneman.bsky.social
https://x.com/EltonStoneman
https://github.com/sixeyed
https://www.linkedin.com/in/eltonstoneman
https://blog.sixeyed.com

Bret
https://bsky.app/profile/bretfisher.com
https://x.com/BretFisher
https://github.com/BretFisher
https://www.linkedin.com/in/bretefisher
https://www.bretfisher.com/start
https://www.bretfisher.com

Links
Get 45% discount on Manning products with code: GOTOstoneman3
https://www.manning.com
https://blog.sixeyed.com/why-would-you-write-a-book-about-docker-in-2025
https://12factor.net
https://youtu.be/5zY5_iTGIsU
https://youtu.be/xRj9rYKV48k
https://youtu.be/SY9qrTMhZkg
https://youtu.be/Qj_CwFtid00
https://youtu.be/MkbgZMCTUyU
https://youtu.be/ZnIiFWD7yUw
https://youtu.be/ePyFJ7Hd57Q
https://youtu.be/8fi7uSYlOdc
https://youtu.be/iXz4i2EbB4M
https://youtu.be/9NUOiL48hbo
https://youtu.be/E0GBU8Q-VFY
https://youtu.be/LvhIMkr0rXg
https://youtu.be/eQ-XMDzuvxY
https://youtu.be/v50oJao8W1Y

DESCRIPTION
In this conversation, Docker educator Brett Fisher sits down with Elton Stoneman - freelance consultant, former Docker employee, and author of "Learn Docker in a Month of Lunches" — to discuss the newly released second edition of his book. They cover what has changed in the container ecosystem over the last five years, why Docker fundamentals still matter even as Kubernetes dominates production environments, and what separates a Docker beginner from a true expert.

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
02:05 Why Docker fundamentals still matter
06:56 Docker Compose, Multi-Platform images & what's new in the 2nd edition
12:52 The gap between Docker beginners & experts
21:44 The structure of the book
24:08 The road ahead for containers
26:06 Outro

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Elton Stoneman • Learn Docker in a Month of Lunches • https://amzn.to/4kJVSSD
Elton Stoneman • Learn Kubernetes in a Month of Lunches • https://amzn.to/4qKjate
Elton Stoneman • Docker on Windows • https://amzn.to/4cD6kJD
Burns, Beda & Hightower • Kubernetes: Up & Running • https://amzn.to/3sueuuI
Liz Rice • Container Security • https://amzn.to/3oU4iJe
Liz Rice • Kubernetes Security • https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/kubernetes-security/9781492039075

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#Docker #DockerSwarm #Kubernetes #k8s #Containers #CloudNative #TodayInTech #SoftwareEngineering #Programming #EltonStoneman #BretFisher #BookClub

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>I just watched the longest state of the union speech ever | About That</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hUmp3nmRK_E</link><author>CBC News</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hUmp3nmRK_E?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 00:56:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLeyJPHbRnGaZeajS8uAtr8cyc19TYBZZ9">About That</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In Donald Trump's 2026 state of the union address — which broke the record for the longest such speech — he spoke about everything from lauding the men's Olympic hockey team to repeatedly chastizing Democrats for not standing up to applaud his comments. Andrew Chang breaks down the choreography of the address to explain the strategy behind the words.

Intro - 00:00
Reading the room- 01:20
‘Borrowed prestige’ - 06:07
Substance and signaling - 10:48

Images provided by The Canadian Press, Reuters and Getty Images


»»» Subscribe to CBC News to watch more videos: http://bit.ly/1RreYWS

For breaking news, video, audio and in-depth coverage: https://www.cbc.ca/news
Follow CBC News on TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@cbcnews
Subscribe to CBC News on Snapchat: https://bit.ly/3leaWsr
Subscribe to CBC News on WhatsApp: https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Vb6MSjH9Bb63S9tbQa1Y

Download the CBC News app for iOS: http://apple.co/25mpsUz
Download the CBC News app for Android: http://bit.ly/1XxuozZ

»»»»»»»»»»»»»»»»»»
For more than 80 years, CBC News has been the source Canadians turn to, to keep them informed about their communities, their country and their world. Through regional and national programming on multiple platforms, including CBC Television, CBC News Network, CBC Radio, CBCNews.ca, mobile and on-demand, CBC News and its internationally recognized team of award-winning journalists deliver the breaking stories, the issues, the analyses and the personalities that matter to Canadians.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Internet Was Weeks Away From Disaster and No One Knew</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aoag03mSuXQ</link><author>Veritasium</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/aoag03mSuXQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 20:28:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[How a single hack infected the world’s most important operating system. Sponsored by NordVPN - Get exclusive NordVPN deal here: https://NordVPN.com/veritasium It’s risk free with Nord’s 30 day money-back guarantee!

If you’re looking for a molecular modelling kit, try Snatoms, a kit I invented where the atoms snap together magnetically - https://ve42.co/SnatomsV 

Sign up for the Veritasium newsletter for weekly science updates - https://ve42.co/Newsletter 

▀▀▀
0:00 The Free Software Foundation
5:03 Why is Linux so popular?
9:57 The XZ Weakness
12:07 End To End Encryption - SSH
18:40 How To Compress Data
23:47 How The .XZ Hack Worked
34:24 A Bug In Jia’s Code
38:27 Henry Hacks Derek
43:16 The Back Door Is Exposed
47:16 Who is Jia Tan?
50:33 Open Vs Closed Source

▀▀▀
A huge thank you to everyone who made this possible:

Rich Jones for his openness throughout this project.

Denzel Farmer for his incredible breakdown - https://youtu.be/Q6ovtLdSbEA?si=qlbcg6skR-BoS5z1 

Karsten Nohl @hackingmatters, Yannis Hofmann, and Matthias Marx at SRLabs for their help throughout this project.

Fabian Fäßler @LiveOverflow  Alex Schlögl and the rest of the Cure53 team for their technical insights on the project.

Tom Scott, and Computerphile for their excellent videos on compression.

Josh at @breakfastserial  for the filming inspiration.

Planet Money for a podcast that helped inform our research and @fern-tv  for inspiration.

Thomas Roccia for his technical feedback on the video. And Ed at @LowLevelTV for helping out early on!

▀▀▀
References: https://ve42.co/XZHackRefs

▀▀▀
Special thanks to our Patreon supporters: Adam Foreman, Albert Wenger, Alex Porter, Alexander Tamas, Anton Ragin, armedtoe, Balkrishna Heroor, Bertrand Serlet, Blake Byers, Bruce, Charles Ian Norman Venn, Daniel Martins, Data Don, Dave Kircher, David Johnston, David Tseng, EJ Alexandra, Evgeny Skvortsov, Garrett Mueller, Gnare, gpoly, Hayden Christensen, Hong Thai Le, Ibby Hadeed, Jeromy Johnson, Jesse Brandsoy, Jon Jamison, Juan Benet, Kelcey Steele, KeyWestr, Kyi, Lee Redden, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Mark Heising, Martin Paull, Meekay, meg noah, Michael Krugman, Moebiusol - Cristian, Orlando Bassotto, Parsee Health, Paul Peijzel, Richard Sundvall, Robson, Sam Lutfi, Shalva Bukia, Sinan Taifour, Tj Steyn, Ubiquity Ventures, Vahe Andonians, wolfee

▀▀▀
Writer, Director & Producer: Henry van Dyck
Presenters: Derek Muller & Henry van Dyck
Editor: Trenton Oliver
Animators: Fabio Albertelli, Domonkos Józsa, Andrew Neet, Alex Drakoulis & Emma Wright
Illustrators: Jakub Misiek & Nataly Zhuk
Researchers: Aakash Singh Bagga & Sophia Rose
Additional Editing: James Stuart & Peter Nelson
Thumbnail Designers: Abdallah Rabah, Ren Hurley, Ben Powell & Henry van Dyck
Production Team: Josh Pitt, Matthew Cavanagh, Anna Milkovic, Katy Southwood & Jess Bishop-Laggett
Executive Producers: Derek Muller & Casper Mebius

Additional video/photos supplied by Getty Images & Storyblocks
Music from Epidemic Sound]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Prince Albert Victor - The Heir Who Died and Changed Royal History Forever Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aGe3QTgYkbY</link><author>The People Profiles</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/aGe3QTgYkbY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 19:59:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFD6TPU-PvTMvqgzC_AM7_uA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Go to https://piavpn.com/thepeopleprofiles to get 83% off from our sponsor Private Internet Access with 4 months free!

Uncover the dramatic true story of Prince Albert Victor, the man who was destined to be King but instead became one of the Victorian era's most controversial figures. Known as "Eddy" to his family, Queen Victoria's grandson and the eldest son of King Edward VII lived a life defined by privilege, mystery, and explosive royal scandals.

In this full documentary, we investigate the events that shadowed his legacy—from the notorious Cleveland Street Scandal and rumours of a secret life in London’s underworld to the sensational (though debunked) theories linking him to the Jack the Ripper murders. Was there a royal cover-up to protect the heir apparent, or was he a "black sheep" prince unfairly targeted by the press?

We also explore his tragic death at just 28 during the 1892 influenza pandemic, an event that changed British royal history forever by paving the way for his brother, King George V. Featuring insights into his education at Trinity College, his military service, and his failed romances, this biography reveals the human story behind the "Lost King."

Please subscribe here. https://www.youtube.com/@PeopleProfiles?sub_confirmation=1
Our second channel. https://www.youtube.com/@PeopleProfilesExtra
Follow us on Spotify. https://open.spotify.com/show/7fKALbrzEO9Q4VVvAwWHqL
Support us on Patreon https://patreon.com/thepeopleprofiles
Follow us on Twitter. https://twitter.com/tpprofiles

Thanks for watching! If you liked this video, check out our related videos below:
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLNwBhP0rWSz1EQOUiCo2hOzXogNU5psT8
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLNwBhP0rWSz0vPvWecG4EPQIWEIh34K-X
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLNwBhP0rWSz3l1yKTFKS6b3GPniSWVpmX

All footage, images and music used in People Profiles videos are sourced from free media websites or are purchased with commercial rights from online media archives.

All People Profiles scripts are researched and written by qualified Historians. The script for this video has been checked with Plagiarism and AI Detector software and scored 0% on Grammarly. In academia, a score of below 15% is considered good or acceptable. 

No AI is used during the writing process of People Profiles videos, which are narrated by human voice over artists. Please see the end credits of our videos for details and contact us for script references.

#peopleprofiles  #history  #biography]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Science Behind Dessert Lizards | Life in Cold Blood | BBC Earth Science</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=havwC6Qk1qY</link><author>BBC Earth Science</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/havwC6Qk1qY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 19:00:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFdsOTr6SmDrxuWE7sJFrkhQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[From the Arizona desert, Sir David Attenborough takes us through the unique way a few desert lizards sunbathe and defend themselves against predators with the regal horned lizard and the armadillo lizard as live examples.

Best of Earth Science: http://bit.ly/EarthLabOriginals 
Best of BBC Earth: http://bit.ly/TheBestOfBBCEarthVideos 

Taken from: Life in Cold Blood (2008)

This is a channel from BBC Studios who help fund new BBC programmes. Service information and feedback: http://bbcworldwide.com/vod-feedback--contact-details.aspx]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Samsung Galaxy S26/Ultra Impressions: 1 Crazy Display Feature!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FRI78tq9Eik</link><author>Marques Brownlee</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FRI78tq9Eik?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 18:00:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFBJycsmduvYEL83R_U4JriQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Galaxy S26 Ultra has one pretty sick privacy display feature

Protect your Samsung S26 with dbrand at http://dbrand.com/shop/s26-ultra

That shirt: http://MKBHD.com

Affiliate Links:
Samsung Galaxy S26 Ultra: https://geni.us/6Bh61
Samsung Galaxy S26: https://geni.us/TZA66

Playlist of MKBHD Intro music: https://goo.gl/B3AWV5

~
http://twitter.com/MKBHD
http://instagram.com/MKBHD
http://facebook.com/MKBHD]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The British AR-15 Story: From Borneo to the Falklands with firearms expert Jonathan Ferguson</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f24_ZefxVlQ</link><author>Royal Armouries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/f24_ZefxVlQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:54:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFsMX-XuiEkBi4-GDrYuniWg">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[When did Britain first adopt the AR-15 and was it really before the Americans?

In this episode of What Is This Weapon?, Jonathan Ferguson explores the little-known story of early British procurement of the AR-15 beginning in 1964.

Read the full research in ARMAX: Journal of Contemporary Arms, Volume 11, Issue 1 (Spring/Summer 2025). '“A Delightful Weapon”: British Adoption of the AR-15 Rifle. Jonathan S. Ferguson':
https://www.armaxjournal.org/doi/armax35519

Subscribe to our channel for more videos about arms and armour  

Help us bring history to life by supporting us here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/donations/

Sign up to our museum membership scheme here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/membership/ 

⚔Website: https://royalarmouries.org/home
⚔Blog: https://royalarmouries.org/stories/
⚔Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/RoyalArmouriesMuseum/
⚔Twitter: https://twitter.com/Royal_Armouries
⚔ Instagram: http://instagram.com/royalarmouriesmuseum

We are the Royal Armouries, the United Kingdom's national collection of arms and armour. Discover what goes on behind the scenes and watch our collection come to life. See combat demonstrations, experience jousting and meet our experts. 

Have a question about arms and armour? Feel free to leave us a comment and we'll do our best to answer it.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Canary Islands paradox - Desalination plants: Curse or blessing? | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5WTkvkQSOn4</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5WTkvkQSOn4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:00:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Sixty years ago, Europe's first seawater desalination plant was built in the Canary Islands. This technology for producing fresh water was a blessing for the islands. Now, it could prove to be a curse for the ecosystem.

This water treatment system is essential for life in the area - but is it compatible with the principles of sustainable development?

Due to limited freshwater resources and rising demand, the first seawater desalination plant in Europe was built in the Canary Islands. It is often touted as a perfect solution. Today, the Canary Islands have the highest number of desalinations plants in the world, relative to the islands’ size and population. 

The fresh water obtained in this way is indispensable for human life on the volcanic islands, but - since it appears to be available in abundance - it also encourages unbridled economic development, such as mass tourism and the intensive monoculture of bananas for export. 

Moreover, seawater desalination is anything but climate-neutral. The plants consume vast amounts of electricity from fossil fuels. The brine returned to the sea destroys marine life and contributes to ocean acidification. 

The film sheds light for the first time on this region's dependence on desalinated seawater. The documentary also explains how water desalination works, and the various impacts that need to be considered.
 
Aware of the urgent need to protect nature, their own health and the future of their children, the Canarian people are working together with scientists to find alternative solutions for sustainable water management. 

Thanks to decades of experience, the Canary Islands are now leaders in the field of seawater desalination, and their technical expertise is in demand worldwide. In view of increasingly frequent droughts due to climate change, the extraction of drinking water using this technology is becoming a matter of survival for an increasing number of people.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #canaryislands #water 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How To Build a GenAI-Augmented Software Organization • Marko Klemetti &amp; Kris Jenkins • GOTO 2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u1nuS5MUFfc</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/u1nuS5MUFfc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 13:01:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This conversation was recorded at GOTO Copenhagen 2025. #GOTOcon #GOTOcph
https://gotocph.com

Marko Klemetti - CTO of Eficode @mr-ako 
Kris Jenkins - Lifelong Computer Geek and Podcast Host @krisajenkins 

ORIGINAL TALK TITLE
Rewriting the SDLC Playbook with GenAI: How To Build a GenAI-Augmented Software Organization?

RESOURCES
Marko
https://bsky.app/profile/mrako.com
https://twitter.com/mrako
https://github.com/mrako
https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrako
https://mrako.com

Kris
https://bsky.app/profile/krisajenkins.bsky.social
https://twitter.com/krisajenkins
https://www.linkedin.com/in/krisjenkins
https://github.com/krisajenkins
http://blog.jenkster.com

ABSTRACT
Speakers interview each other on topics that matter to them.

The Program Committee brings special guests in front of the camera — with you as the audience. Some interviews will be planned, others completely spontaneous. All of them will be magnificent, no doubt about it.

Expect the unexpected. [...]

TIMECODES
00:00 Intro
00:41 AI as the next paradigm shift
05:04 Team topologies & platform engineering
12:48 Case study: Volkswagen spin-off
17:55 Gen AI reaches doctorate‑level performance
20:04 Flattened organizations & “pizza‑sized” teams
29:50 Why some succeed & others fail
41:35 Audience Q&A
46:45 Outro

Read the full abstract here:
https://gotocph.com/2025/sessions/3931

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Matthew Skelton & Manuel Pais • Team Topologies • http://amzn.to/3sVLyLQ
Forsgren, Humble & Kim • Accelerate: The Science of Lean Software and DevOps • https://amzn.to/3tCz1xO
John Arundel & Justin Domingus • Cloud Native DevOps with Kubernetes • https://amzn.to/3hKZvI5
Wynne, Hellesoy & Tooke • The Cucumber Book • https://amzn.to/3tEUINJ
Sol Rashidi • Your AI Survival Guide • https://amzn.to/3UFYnKC
David Foster • Generative Deep Learning • https://amzn.to/48ZgP4x
Phil Winder • Reinforcement Learning • https://amzn.to/3t1S1VZ

https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com
https://twitter.com/GOTOcon
https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-
https://www.instagram.com/goto_con
https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences
#SDLC #GenAI #Augmented #GenAIAugmented #AI #ArtificialIntelligence #CoPilot #GitHubCoPilot #OpenAI #AIDrivenDevelopment #TeamTopologies #PlatformEngineering #TodayInTech #Programming #SoftwareEngineering #MarkoKlemetti #KrisJenkins

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket at https://gotopia.tech
Sign up for updates and specials at https://gotopia.tech/newsletter

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR CHANNEL - new videos posted almost daily.
https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Are Prescription Drugs So Costly in the US? | The Other Drug War (full documentary) | FRONTLINE</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XkIbIGeeWR0</link><author>FRONTLINE PBS | Official</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XkIbIGeeWR0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 22:44:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULF3ScyryU9Oy9Wse3a8OAmYQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Why are prescription drugs so expensive in the U.S.? In this 2003 documentary that still resonates, FRONTLINE investigated the battle between U.S. consumers and pharmaceutical companies, and the debate over the role the government should play in drug pricing. Read updates on our website about what’s happened since “The Other Drug War” aired, including recalls of two of the prescription drugs mentioned in the film: https://www.pbs.org/wgbh/frontline/article/prescription-drug-costs-pharmaceutical-companies-documentary/

This journalism is made possible by viewers like you. Donate to FRONTLINE now: https://bit.ly/47DFzCb

And support your local PBS station here: https://www.pbs.org/donate

“The Other Drug War” went inside America’s decades-long fight over prescription drug costs. Through interviews with consumers, legislators, scientists, industry leaders and analysts, the documentary probed the tension between the high cost of scientific innovation and consumers’ need for affordable medications. It also examined the debate over whether federal and state governments should be involved in drug pricing, and the legislative landscape at the time. 

"The Other Drug War" is a FRONTLINE co-production with Palfreman Film Group, Inc. The producer, director and writer is Jon Palfreman. The producer and director is Barbara Moran. 

Explore additional reporting on "The Other Drug War" on our website:
https://www.pbs.org/wgbh/pages/frontline/shows/other/

#Documentary #DrugPrices #Pharma #PrescriptionDrugs #Medicare #DrugCosts

Subscribe on YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/user/PBSfrontline
Sign up for our newsletter: https://frontline.org/newsletter
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/frontlinepbs
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/frontline
Bluesky: https://bsky.app/profile/frontlinepbs.bsky.social

FRONTLINE is produced at GBH in Boston and airs nationwide on PBS. The editor-in-chief and executive producer of FRONTLINE is Raney Aronson-Rath. Funding for FRONTLINE is provided through the support of PBS viewers and by the Corporation for Public Broadcasting, with major support from Ford Foundation. Additional support for FRONTLINE is provided by the Abrams Foundation, Park Foundation, John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, Heising-Simons Foundation, and the FRONTLINE Trust, with major support from Jon and Jo Ann Hagler on behalf of the Jon L. Hagler Foundation, and additional support from Koo and Patricia Yuen.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Impossible Landing</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Nkad_6aigM</link><author>neo</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5Nkad_6aigM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFtYKe7-XbaDjpUwcU5x0bLg">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get Nebula for 40% off an annual subscription using my link: https://go.nebula.tv/neo

Watch my exclusive Nebula video about the Tenerife Disaster:
https://nebula.tv/videos/neo-the-tenerife-disaster

United Airlines Flight 232 lost all hydraulics mid-air. This is the story of the “impossible landing".

Images via Getty
Map source by MapTiler / OpenStreetMap Contributors via Geolayers 3

Animations and Narration: Leon Herres
Research and Writing: Erin Ganley
Illustrations: Burak Ata]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Swiss bar fire disaster - Life after the nightmare | DW Documentary</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_sG2rBRHGYg</link><author>DW Documentary</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_sG2rBRHGYg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:01:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFW39zufHfsuGgpLviKh297Q">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The survivors of the bar fire in the Swiss mountain resort and their families are desperately trying to come to terms with the tragedy. Could the New Year's blaze in Crans-Montana that claimed 41 lives and left 116 people injured have been prevented?

New Year's celebrations ended in tragedy at the Le Constellation bar in the upscale ski resort of Crans-Montana. Swiss investigators believe that sparklers attached to champagne bottles set light to sound insulation foam on the basement ceiling. The flames spread within seconds, turning the basement of the bar - a popular party location - into a death trap. 
41 people died as a result of the blaze and 116 people were left injured. Many of the mostly teenaged victims sustained severe burns. That night was the start of a living nightmare for the families affected. 
This documentary accompanies some of the parents whose children were left critically injured and now face long hospital stays far from home, uncertain outcomes and the daily struggle to keep hope alive. 
One young survivor also describes what she went through that night and how it has affected her. The psychological wounds run deep: anxiety, trauma and feelings of guilt. She is plagued by the question of why she survived when others died. 
The film shows how initial reactions of shock and dismay quickly turned to outrage after revelations that human blunders and safety shortcomings may have led to the blaze. The investigation and legal proceedings are only just getting underway, but the mental and emotional impact is already overwhelming.

#documentary #dwdocumentary #dwdocs #swiss #switzerland 
______

DW Documentary gives you knowledge beyond the headlines. Watch top documentaries from German broadcasters and international production companies. Meet intriguing people, travel to distant lands, get a look behind the complexities of daily life and build a deeper understanding of current affairs and global events. Subscribe and explore the world around you with DW Documentary.

Subscribe to: ‬
⮞ DW Documentary (English): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumentary 
⮞ DW Documental (Spanish): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDocumental 
⮞ DW Documentary وثائقية دي دبليو (Arabic): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdocarabia
⮞ DW Documentary हिन्दी (Hindi): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdochindi
⮞ DW Dokumenter (Indonesian): https://www.youtube.com/@DWDokumenter
⮞ DW Doku (German): https://www.youtube.com/@dwdoku

For more visit: http://www.dw.com/en/tv/docfilm/s-3610
Follow DW Documentary on Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/dwdocumentary/
Follow DW Documental on Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/dwdocumental

We kindly ask viewers to read and stick to the DW netiquette policy on our channel: https://p.dw.com/p/MF1G]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Does hypnosis ever actually work? - Devin Terhune</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JJdoAMiaLZo</link><author>TED-Ed</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/JJdoAMiaLZo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFsooa4yRKGN_zEE8iknghZA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Explore the science of hypnosis, and dig into how the practice can affect your body and brain when hypnotic suggestions work.

--

In the 19th century, Scottish surgeon James Braid revolutionized the field of hypnotism, transitioning the practice towards inducing a sleep-like state. Today, hypnosis is used in psychiatry as a helpful medical tool, yet it still holds an entrancing place in popular fantasy. So, is there any truth to what it can accomplish? Or is it just illusion? Devin Terhune explores the power of suggestion.

Lesson by Devin Terhune, directed by Leah Putnam.

Support Our Non-Profit Mission
----------------------------------------------
Support us on Patreon: http://bit.ly/TEDEdPatreon
Check out our merch: http://bit.ly/TEDEDShop
----------------------------------------------

Connect With Us
----------------------------------------------
Sign up for our newsletter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdNewsletter
Follow us on Facebook: http://bit.ly/TEDEdFacebook
Find us on Twitter: http://bit.ly/TEDEdTwitter
Peep us on Instagram: http://bit.ly/TEDEdInstagram
----------------------------------------------

Keep Learning
----------------------------------------------
View full lesson: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/does-hypnosis-ever-actually-work-devin-terhune
Dig deeper with additional resources: https://ed.ted.com/lessons/does-hypnosis-ever-actually-work-devin-terhune/digdeeper

Animator's website: https://www.leahputnamillustration.com
----------------------------------------------

Thank you so much to our patrons for your support! Without you this video would not be possible! Lex Azevedo, Michael Aquilina, Jason A Saslow, Yansong Li, Cristóbal Moenne, Dawn Jordan, Prasanth Mathialagan, Samuel Doerle, David Rosario, Dominik Kugelmann - they-them, Siamak Hajizadeh, Ryohky Araya, Mayank Kaul, Christophe Dessalles, Heather Slater, Sandra Tersluisen, Zhexi Shan, Bárbara Nazaré, Andrea Feliz, Victor E Karhel, Sydney Evans, Latora, Noel Situ, emily lam, Sid, Niccolò Frassetto, Mana, I'm here because of Knowledge Fight Facebook group., Linda Freedman, Edgardo Cuellar, Jaspar Carmichael-Jack, Michael Burton, VIVIANA A GARCIA BESNE, The Vernon's, Olha Bahatiuk, Jesús Bíquez Talayero, Chels Raknrl, Sai Pranavi Jonnalagadda, Stuart Rice, Jing Chen, Vector-Dopamine math, Jasper Song, Giorgio Bugnatelli, Chardon, Eddy Trochez, OnlineBookClub.org, Eric Shear, Leith Salem, Omar Hicham, and Adrian Rotaru.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Effect Oriented Programming • Bill Frasure, Bruce Eckel, James Ward &amp; Andrew Harmel-Law</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UOiVp1ZjUs4</link><author>GOTO Conferences</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/UOiVp1ZjUs4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:35:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This interview was recorded for the GOTO Book Club.
http://gotopia.tech/bookclub

Check out more here:
https://gotopia.tech/episodes/420

Bill Frasure - Co-Author of  "Effect Oriented Programming"
Bruce Eckel - Author of many books such as "Thinking in Java", "Thinking in C++" & Atomic Kotlin & Co-Author of  "Effect Oriented Programming"
James Ward - Principal Developer Advocate at AWS & Co-Author of  "Effect Oriented Programming"
Andrew Harmel-Law - Technical Principal at Thoughtworks & Author of "Facilitating Software Architecture"

RESOURCES
Bill
https://github.com/swoogles
https://x.com/bill_frasure

Bruce
https://bsky.app/profile/bruceeckel.bsky.social
https://x.com/BruceEckel
https://github.com/BruceEckel
https://www.linkedin.com/in/bruceeckel

James
https://bsky.app/profile/jamesward.com
https://twitter.com/_JamesWard
https://github.com/jamesward
https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamesward

Andrew
https://bsky.app/profile/andrewhl.bsky.social
https://twit.social/@ahl
https://x.com/al94781
https://github.com/andrewharmellaw
https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewharmellaw
https://andrewharmellaw.github.io

Links
https://effectorientedprogramming.com
https://happypathprogramming.com
https://zio.dev
https://www.unison-lang.org
https://www.roc-lang.org

DESCRIPTION
Andrew Harmel-Law explores the core concepts of effect oriented programming with authors Bill Frasure, Bruce Eckel, and James Ward. The discussion reveals that effects are composable operations that encapsulate side effects and defer execution, giving developers the right handles to manage unpredictability through compiler-checked types.
The authors explain how ZIO tracks three critical types: outputs, failures, and environmental requirements, enabling better testing with mock clocks and random number generators.

They share their intentional avoidance of intimidating functional programming terminology like "monads" proving you don't need mathematical foundations to understand effects. The conversation covers effect systems' expansion beyond Scala into TypeScript, Kotlin, and new languages like Unison and Roc, and how their collaborative writing process with strict constraints like 47-character line limits - created a coherent 100-page book readable in portrait mode on your phone.

RECOMMENDED BOOKS
Bill Frasure, Bruce Eckel, James Ward • Effect Oriented Programming • https://amzn.to/4sO6wLV
Bruce Eckel & Svetlana Isakova • Atomic Kotlin • https://amzn.to/4qT1gEQ
Bruce Eckel • Thinking in C++ • https://amzn.to/4qnrIGW
Andrew Harmel-Law • Facilitating Software Architecture • https://amzn.eu/d/5kZKVfU
Sam Keen • Clean Architecture with Python • https://amzn.to/4pBT5g0
Eric Evans • Domain-Driven Design • https://amzn.to/3tnGhwm


Bluesky (https://bsky.app/profile/gotocon.com) 
Twitter (https://twitter.com/GOTOcon) 
Instagram (https://www.instagram.com/goto_con) 
LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/company/goto-) 
Facebook (https://www.facebook.com/GOTOConferences) 

CHANNEL MEMBERSHIP BONUS
Join this channel to get early access to videos & other perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCs_tLP3AiwYKwdUHpltJPuA/join

Looking for a unique learning experience?
Attend the next GOTO conference near you! Get your ticket: gotopia.tech (https://gotopia.tech) 

SUBSCRIBE TO OUR YOUTUBE CHANNEL (https://www.youtube.com/user/GotoConferences/?sub_confirmation=1)  - new videos posted daily!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>&apos;Those Who Hold The Reins&apos; - Short Documentary Trailer of the Legacy of Modern Jousting</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EvgsReWzVXA</link><author>Royal Armouries</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EvgsReWzVXA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:28:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFsMX-XuiEkBi4-GDrYuniWg">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Those Who Hold the Reins is a short profile documentary by the director and editor of What is this Weapon, showcasing that competitive medieval jousting isn’t just history, it’s still alive.

Following the Royal Armouries team to a small community in Opalenie, Poland you'll be able to get a small glimpse of the people that continue the teachable legacy of historic re-enactment, from horse archery to modern competitive full tilt jousting.

Subscribe to our channel for more videos about arms and armour  

Help us bring history to life by supporting us here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/donations/

Sign up to our museum membership scheme here: https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/membership/ 

⚔Website: https://royalarmouries.org/home
⚔Blog: https://royalarmouries.org/stories/
⚔Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/RoyalArmouriesMuseum/
⚔Twitter: https://twitter.com/Royal_Armouries
⚔ Instagram: http://instagram.com/royalarmouriesmuseum

We are the Royal Armouries, the United Kingdom's national collection of arms and armour. Discover what goes on behind the scenes and watch our collection come to life. See combat demonstrations, experience jousting and meet our experts. 

Have a question about arms and armour? Feel free to leave us a comment and we'll do our best to answer it.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>To fight authoritarianism, America should look to Brazil</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mhPHV7aoFHg</link><author>Vox</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/mhPHV7aoFHg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:45:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFLXo7UDZvByw2ixzpQCufnA">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[On January 8, 2023, thousands of supporters of Brazil’s right-wing former President Jair Bolsonaro stormed federal buildings in the country’s capital. Their goal? Overthrow the results of an election they claimed was rigged, despite no credible evidence of fraud. 

If that sounds familiar, that’s because it is. Brazil’s January 8 looked a lot like the January 6 attack on the US capital, just two years earlier: mob violence, an insurrection, and a defeated leader who refused to concede.

But the aftermath could not be more different. Jair Bolsonaro is now serving a 27-year prison sentence, while Donald Trump is president, again. 

So how did two democracies, facing similar threats, end up with such different outcomes? This video explains how Brazil’s democratic system worked to hold “the Trump of the Tropics” accountable and what the US could learn from the aftermath.

Read more about Brazil’s response:

Vox correspondent Zack Beauchamp’s deep dive into what Brazil got right: How one country stopped a Trump-style authoritarian in his tracks | https://www.vox.com/politics/479290/brazil-democracy-trump-bolsonaro-multiparty

The Brazilian Report breaks down the details of Bolsonaro’s coup plans: Anatomy of a coup attempt | https://newsletters.brazilian.report/p/bolsonaro-coup-right-pistachio

Carnegie Endowment’s podcast, The World Unpacked, breaks down the trial and conviction of former Bolsonaro | Did the Bolsonaro Trial Really Save Brazil's Democracy? | https://carnegieendowment.org/podcasts/the-world-unpacked/did-the-bolsonaro-trial-really-save-brazils-democracy

The New Yorker’s excellent profile of Alexandre de Moraes includes a lot more detail on how the judge became an enemy of Trump and Elon Musk, in his mission to crack down on election misinformation: The Brazilian Judge Taking On the Digital Far Right | https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2025/04/14/the-brazilian-judge-taking-on-the-digital-far-right

The New York Times Op Ed, co-written by Filipe Campante, who is featured in the video: Brazil Just Succeeded Where America Failed | https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/12/opinion/trump-bolsonaro-conviction-democracy.html

The Economist’s take on how countries recover from populism: Brazil offers America a lesson in democratic maturity | https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/08/28/brazil-offers-america-a-lesson-in-democratic-maturity

If you enjoy our reporting and want to hear more from Vox journalists, sign up for our Patreon at patreon.com/vox. Each month, our members get access to exclusive videos, livestreams, and chats with our newsroom.

This story was supported by a grant from Protect Democracy. Vox had full discretion over the content of this reporting.

Subscribe to our channel! http://goo.gl/0bsAjO

Vox.com is a news website that helps you cut through the noise and understand what's really driving the events in the headlines. Check out http://www.vox.com.

Watch our full video catalog: http://goo.gl/IZONyE
Follow Vox on Facebook: http://goo.gl/U2g06o
Or Twitter: http://goo.gl/XFrZ5H]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How China&apos;s &apos;Perfect&apos; Spy Got Caught | Bloomberg Investigates</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ox8HVWjboww</link><author>Bloomberg Originals</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Ox8HVWjboww?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 09:00:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFUMZ7gohGI9HcU9VNsr2FJQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Ji Chaoqun was a promising young engineer from Beijing heading to the US to study. Then China’s Ministry of State Security came calling with bags of cash, the promise of glory and an offer that would change his life forever. Student, Mormon, gamer, spy – who was Ji Chaoqun, and how did he come to be at the center of a corporate espionage showdown?

The Sixth Bureau podcast from Bloomberg News follows a Chinese intelligence officer whose mission was to steal the trade secrets of American aerospace companies: http://www.bloomberg.com/thesixthbureau

Listen to The Sixth Bureau on the iHeartRadio App, Apple Podcasts, or wherever you get your podcasts.

--------
Like this video? Subscribe: http://www.youtube.com/Bloomberg?sub_confirmation=1

Get unlimited access to Bloomberg.com for just $1.99 your first month: https://www.bloomberg.com/subscriptions?in_source=YoutubeOriginals
Bloomberg Originals offers bold takes for curious minds on today’s biggest topics. Hosted by experts covering stories you haven’t seen and viewpoints you haven’t heard, you’ll discover cinematic, data-led shows that investigate the intersection of business and culture. Exploring every angle of climate change, technology, finance, sports and beyond, Bloomberg Originals is business as you’ve never seen it. 

Subscribe for business news, but not as you've known it: exclusive interviews, fascinating profiles, data-driven analysis, and the latest in tech innovation from around the world.

Visit our partner channel Bloomberg News for global news and insight in an instant.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Inside Apple’s Multibillion-Dollar Push to Make Chips in the U.S. | WSJ</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ktFlaBhpMu8</link><author>The Wall Street Journal</author><category>yt</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ktFlaBhpMu8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 02:00:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFK7tptUDHh-RYDsdxO1-5QQ">Videos</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Apple is beginning to bring its semiconductor manufacturing supply chain back to the United States. Nearly all of the most advanced chips are made in Taiwan, which China has threatened to annex. Concentrating chip supplies on an island that could be invaded, or face steep U.S. tariffs from Trump, is a big risk to Apple’s business.

To find out how far the company still has to go, WSJ reporter Rolfe Winkler visited several of the company’s suppliers including TSMC, ASML and Foxconn in the Southwest.

Chapters:
0:00 Apple’s supply chain shift
1:02 The start of the supply chain: silicon wafer facility
3:59 The next stop: TSMC
6:05 The third stop: ASML
7:13 The final stop: Foxconn

Read more about Apple’s push to build an all-American chip here: https://on.wsj.com/4tPgi0M

News Explainers
Some days the high-speed news cycle can bring more questions than answers. WSJ’s news explainers break down the day's biggest stories into bite-size pieces to help you make sense of the news.

#Apple #Chips #WSJ]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>