<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Movies</title><link>https://konrad.website/feeds/</link><description></description><item><title>The A24 Podcast | Center Stage with John Early &amp; Da&apos;Vine Joy Randolph</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u6LCH9E_f4g</link><author>A24</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/u6LCH9E_f4g?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLpd1itfTDtaVLCrM6OgjyE7TY_CwUnnGE">Movies - A24 Podcast</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[SUBSCRIBE: http://bit.ly/A24subscribe
Today on The A24 Podcast, Eternity co-stars John Early and Da’Vine Joy Randolph reunite for a rollicking conversation on opera singing, choosing to be the clown, and the realization that they went to the same performing arts summer camp at the Exact. Same. Time.

Getting comfortable in the chaos, moments of brevity, John writing his directorial debut on set of Eternity, the loud sound that is silence, double-fisting at TIFF, attending Interlochen at the exact same time, training in opera, Da’Vine’s stint as a camp counselor for child prodigies,ill-informed southern accents for The Laramie Project, witnessing the greatness of Audra McDonald in Gypsy, a shared love of Company, John’s huge plans for Da’Vine’s career, vocal tics, Da’Vine losing her voice on Broadway after she got nominated for a Tony, choosing to be the clown,and the great problem with contemporary musicals.

------

ABOUT A24:
The studio behind EVERYTHING EVERYWHERE ALL AT ONCE, UNCUT GEMS, MIDSOMMAR, MOONLIGHT, BEEF on Netflix, EUPHORIA on Max & more.

Coming Soon: EDDINGTON, THE SMASHING MACHINE, MARTY SUPREME & more

Subscribe to A24's NEWSLETTER:  http://bit.ly/A24signup
Sign up for A24 MEMBERSHIP: aaa24.com
Visit A24 WEBSITE: http://bit.ly/A24filmsdotcom
Like A24 on FACEBOOK: http://bit.ly/FBA24
Follow A24 on TWITTER: http://bit.ly/TweetA24
Follow A24 on INSTAGRAM: http://bit.ly/InstaA24]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Wagner Moura’s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hvOnBK-L-zg</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hvOnBK-L-zg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 19:04:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The actor and director praises BLACK GOD, WHITE DEVIL as one of the most important Brazilian films ever made, talks about the complex humanity of IL POSTO, and reflects on why Jean-Pierre and Luc Dardenne are his favorite filmmakers.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Best of the Worst Spotlight: Axe &apos;Em!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uhdraU2wf_Y</link><author>RedLetterMedia</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/uhdraU2wf_Y?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 16:21:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrTNhL_yO3tPTdQ5XgmmWjA">Movies - RedLetterMedia</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[It's time for Axe 'Em!!! This is a "movie" that's been looming over us for years. Often considered one of the worst movies ever made, if not THE worst movie ever made, Jay and Josh saw Axe 'Em a long time ago and have always dreaded revisiting it. But today is that day! Who is Axe 'Em? Why is Axe 'Em? Will the movie answer these questions? If it does, will we be able to hear and understand the answers?]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Kahlil Joseph’s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PPw7sJJkQFY</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/PPw7sJJkQFY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:05:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The filmmaker and artist shares his intimate connection to THE COLOR OF POMEGRANATES, talks about the “invisible magic” of Edward Yang’s cinema, and praises the innovative cinematography in TOKYO OLYMPIAD.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>21/11/2025 Box Office Top Ten</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ckOogyOSmzY</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ckOogyOSmzY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:01:14 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark and Simon Mayo run through this week's box office top 10…

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The best/worst dad jokes from the Laughter Lift 21/11/2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q8sBo3PuUqo</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Q8sBo3PuUqo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:01:14 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark Kermode and Simon Mayo

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Simon Mayo Interviews Alexander Skarsgård</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vOZcQqfrgBU</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vOZcQqfrgBU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:01:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews The Carpenter’s Son</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IZ9j0rP4bPc</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/IZ9j0rP4bPc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:01:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Family hiding in Roman Egypt. Son known as 'the Boy' doubts guardian 'the Carpenter', rebelling with mysterious powers. As he uses abilities, they face natural and divine horrors.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Sisu: Road to Revenge</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FoXe--Fw-yY</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FoXe--Fw-yY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:01:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

A man returns to dismantle his family's house, where they were murdered in war, to rebuild it elsewhere. When the killer, a Red Army commander, tracks him down, a brutal cross-country pursuit begins.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Wicked: For Good</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aC50p33WIa8</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/aC50p33WIa8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:01:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Elphaba, the future Wicked Witch of the West and her relationship with Glinda, the Good Witch of the North. The second of a two-part feature film adaptation of the Broadway musical.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>FULL SHOW: WICKED: Which Witch Wins - Is the Sequel/Prequel Equal?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g1Wge4TMm68</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/g1Wge4TMm68?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:30:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Some exciting news—The Take is now on Patreon: www.patreon.com/kermodeandmayo.  Become a Vanguardista or an Ultra Vanguardista to get video episodes of Take Two every week, plus member‑only chat rooms, polls and submissions to influence the show, behind‑the‑scenes photos and videos, the monthly Redactor’s Roundup newsletter, and access to a new fortnightly LIVE show—a raucous, unfiltered lunchtime special with the Good Doctors, new features, and live chat so you can heckle, vote, and have your questions read out in real time. 

A leather-clad Alexander Skarsgård is riding into this week’s Take as our very special guest. That’s because he’s here to talk about ‘Pillion’, the one-of-a-kind comedy drama where he stars as mysterious BDSM biker Ray. The film follows his unfolding relationship with Colin, a shy small-town boy played by Harry Melling—who you might have heard on the show a few months back chatting to Simon about ‘Harvest’. Colin begins to discover his submissive streak under Ray’s dominant hand, as their complex relationship develops. Alexander sits down with Simon to unpack the film—a ‘Dom-Com’, as he calls it—and gives us the lowdown on what a Skarsgård Christmas looks like too.  

Don’s miss Mark’s review of ‘Pillion’ on next week’s show. This week we’ve got his verdicts on three more juicy new releases for you as usual. First up, ‘Sisu: Road to Revenge’--the Finnish action sequel to 2022’s ‘Sisu’, where seemingly unkillable action man Aatami Korpi goes on a revenge rampage against the Red Army. Plus, Bizarre biblical horror ‘The Carpenter’s Son’, starring Nicolas Cage going full Nicola Cage yet again—and ‘Wicked: For Good’ – the sequel to last year’s musical smash spectacle.  

The Good Doctors run down the box office top 10 too—and from the top of the charts to the bottom of the barrel, there’s the Laughter Lift. Plus your excellent and erudite correspondence answered.  

AND Don’t miss our upcoming LIVE Christmas Extravaganza at London’s Prince Edward Theatre on 7th December—with special guests Nia DaCosta, Gurinder Chadha, and more! Tickets here: fane.co.uk/kermode-mayo   

  

Timecodes (for Vanguardistas listening ad-free) 

 
Sisu: Road to Revenge Review; 13;44 

BO10; 22;21 

Alexander Skarsgard Interview; 37;37 

The Carpenter’s Son Review; 51;15 

Laughter Lift; 01;01;28 

Wicked: For Good Review; 01;05;51
 
 

You can contact the show by emailing correspondence@kermodeandmayo.com or you can find us on social media, @KermodeandMayo 

Please take our survey and help shape the future of our show: https://www.kermodeandmayo.com/survey  

EXCLUSIVE NordVPN Deal ➼ https://nordvpn.com/take Try it risk-free now with a 30-day money-back guarantee! 

A Sony Music Entertainment production.     

Find more great podcasts from Sony Music Entertainment at sonymusic.com/podcasts and follow us @sonypodcasts   

To advertise on this show contact: podcastadsales@sonymusic.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>TED SCHILOWITZ - Futurist</title><link>https://teamdeakins.libsyn.com/ted-schilowitz-futurist</link><author></author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/teamdeakins/S2-168_Ted_Schilowitz_Final_Sandstorm-Aputure-SPlea.mp3?dest-id=2018942" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.rogerdeakins.com/">Movies - Team Deakins</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[SEASON 2 - EPISODE 168 - Ted Schilowitz - FuturistIn this episode of the Team Deakins Podcast, we speak with futurist Ted Schilowitz. Ted has spent his life working in entertainment, from producing commercials in Florida to exploring virtual reality at Fox and Paramount, and we thought his perspective on the relationship between technology and entertainment could help us better understand where we might be headed. Over the course of our conversation, we discover that to think of the future, we need to remember the past, and Ted connects recent developments in technology to a number of breakthroughs he was witness to himself. We learn about Grass Valley—the video equivalent of Silicon Valley—and of the origins of the RED camera system, and Ted reveals Apple's early attempts to bring digital video to their computer systems. We also discuss modern consumer trends and our changing relationships with screens, and we learn about Kodak's missed opportunity in the prehistoric days of digital cameras. Ted later shares his observations on AI, and he makes a prediction of what we'll see over the next five years of cinema. This episode is sponsored by Sandstorm & Aputure]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Elle Fanning’s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4G7KuHCJMFg</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/4G7KuHCJMFg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 21:28:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The actor recalls a memorable viewing of THE RED SHOES, celebrates performances by Kirsten Dunst and Nicole Kidman, and shares why THE WORST PERSON IN THE WORLD made her want to work with Joachim Trier.

Shop Elle's Closet Picks for 50% OFF at Barnes & Noble in stores and online through December 7!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>When an Actor Had to Start Over – Andrew Garfield</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ShED9drljLI</link><author>FilmStack</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ShED9drljLI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 17:00:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCFOfgEQLHpPuVNP_m-XldTg">Movies - FilmStack</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[What happens when your dream role ends up breaking your heart? For Andrew Garfield, it only made him better.

After years of working his way through British films, Garfield broke out in Hollywood with The Social Network. He was charming, vulnerable, and instantly in demand. Then came Spider-Man, his dream role since childhood. He poured everything into it, but behind the scenes, the experience was far from heroic. Studio politics and the scrapping of his sequels left him feeling lost, both with the industry and himself.

But he didn’t give up. He chased riskier and more personal roles that challenged him as an actor, like a soldier who refused to use a weapon in Hacksaw Ridge, a priest questioning his faith in Silence, a composer racing against time in Tick, Tick… Boom!, and a performance so demanding it nearly broke him in Angels in America. Some of those roles took a year to prepare, but each one brought him closer to the kind of actor he wanted to be.

This is the story of an actor who refused to give up, both with his career and his commitment to every role. This is Andrew Garfield.

Chapters:
00:00 - The Intro
01:00 - The Rise
05:16 - The Human Spider
08:44 - Moving On
14:16 - Acceptance

Andrew Garfield. The Amazing Spider-Man. The Social Network. Boy A. Hacksaw Ridge. Silence. Martin Scorcese. The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus. Never Let Me Go. Eduardo Saverin. 99 Homes. Tick Tick Boom. Under the Silver Lake. Spider-Man No Way Home. Angels in America. The Eyes of Tammy Faye. Jonathan Larson. We Live in Time. After the Hunt. Under the Banner of Heaven. Emma Stone. Florence Pugh. 

If you like this video don't forget to leave a like, and if you're interested in videos about movies and the film industry in general, make sure to subscribe to FilmStack for more great content.

If you have any other ideas for videos, leave a comment and I might make a video with your idea.

Patreon: https://patreon.com/FilmStack
Twitter: https://twitter.com/realFilmStack
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/realfilmstack/

#andrewgarfield    #actor   #spiderman]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Claire Danes&apos;s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nudBFPgWGGA</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/nudBFPgWGGA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 19:05:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The actor talks about falling in love with SOME LIKE IT HOT at a young age, praises Lili Taylor’s and River Phoenix’s tender performances in DOGFIGHT, and shares the profound effect that STREETWISE has had on her.

Shop Claire's Picks for 50% OFF at Barnes & Noble! Shop online or in stores through December 7!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>14/11/2025 Box Office Top Ten</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mg5HdRRRmBY</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Mg5HdRRRmBY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:01:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark and Simon Mayo run through this week's box office top 10…

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Simon Mayo Interviews Edgar Wright</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ufdNIn3EiFg</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ufdNIn3EiFg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:01:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Now You See Me: Now You Don’t</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Uy4TW9c1XII</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Uy4TW9c1XII?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:01:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

A diamond heist reunites retired Horsemen illusionists with new performers Greenblatt, Smith and Sessa as they target dangerous criminals.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Alpha</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rV5jD2BtGfE</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/rV5jD2BtGfE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:01:14 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Alpha, 13, is a troubled teenager who lives alone with her mother. Their world comes crashing down the day she comes home from school with a tattoo on her arm.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The best/worst dad jokes from the Laughter Lift 14/11/2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jvw3yt-ivMc</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Jvw3yt-ivMc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:01:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark Kermode and Simon Mayo

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews The Running Man</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UOIy7cr9nCM</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/UOIy7cr9nCM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:01:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

A man joins a game show in which contestants, allowed to go anywhere in the world, are pursued by "hunters" hired to kill them.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Every Frame x Lackadaisy - Interview with Tracy J. Butler &amp; Fable Siegel</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZXUBoI9eHfQ</link><author>Every Frame a Painting</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZXUBoI9eHfQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:43 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCjFqcJQXGZ6T6sxyFB-5i6A">Movies - Every Frame a Painting</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A few weeks ago, we were invited onto a livestream to interview Tracy J. Butler & Fable Siegel of Lackadaisy. (https://www.youtube.com/@LackadaisyComic)

For those who don’t know, Lackadaisy is an indie comic that became an indie animated series. It’s about a group of cats who run a speakeasy in St. Louis during Prohibition.

We thoroughly enjoyed the experience and want to share the results.

This conversation was put together with the support of Eat Your Peas (https://www.youtube.com/@EatYourPeas_Acc) an animation coaching collective run by Lindsay Knowler.

Our conversation with the Lackadaisy team focused on three major topics.

The first - a guide through the opening sequence of the pilot, available here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vffu6FG4YP4

The second - what it was like for them to run an indie animation studio remotely.

And the third - the current state of the animation industry itself. 

So come join us by the fire and enjoy!

​​00:00 Intro
01:13 Part One, opening sequence of pilot
04:10 From comic to animation, working on your opening later
08:31 The sample platter vs. traditional pilot, additive nature of animation
12:46 Small details, the moon, screen direction, car driving by
16:19 80s & 90s influences, Great Mouse Detective, Secret of Nimh, The Rescuers
19:17 Part Two, The Average Day on an Indie Production
21:51 Value of a Production Manager
25:27 Overestimating abilities, being a leader, hustle culture
27:38 Downtime, needing to live, finding inspiration for art in life
32:32 A lot of animation production is cloistered off
34:39 Part Three, The Industry
36:53 Why is indie animation happening right now?
40:44 Art is communication, not worried about GenAI, perfection
46:09 Fable’s intentions
49:54 Tracy’s intentions
52:58 Last bit


Lackadaisy
Website: https://lackadaisy.com/
YT: https://www.youtube.com/@LackadaisyComic
Store: https://lackadaisy.store/
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/Lackadaisy

Eat Your Peas
Insta: https://www.instagram.com/eatyourpeas_acc/
YT: https://www.youtube.com/@EatYourPeas_Acc
Website: https://eatyourpeas.ca/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We ❤️ Akira Kurosawa | Closet Picks Edition</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/X2x1-t3GDZA</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/X2x1-t3GDZA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 22:36:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Shop all the Akira Kurosawa films in the Criterion Collection for 50% OFF at Barnes & Noble, both online and in stores through December 7!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>FULL SHOW: Edgar Wright on THE RUNNING MAN</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wtxRzwqbNH8</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wtxRzwqbNH8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 21:00:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Some exciting news—The Take is now on Patreon: www.patreon.com/kermodeandmayo.  Become a Vanguardista or an Ultra Vanguardista to get video episodes of Take Two every week, plus member‑only chat rooms, polls and submissions to influence the show, behind‑the‑scenes photos and videos, the monthly Redactor’s Roundup newsletter, and access to a new fortnightly LIVE show—a raucous, unfiltered lunchtime special with the Good Doctors, new features, and live chat so you can heckle, vote, and have your questions read out in real time. 

The fabulous Edgar Wright joins us on this week’s Take to talk ‘The Running Man’—his new adaptation of the Stephen King dystopia. You might remember the Arnie version from 1987, but Wright’s is a refreshed take starring very angry action man Glen Powell. He plays Ben Richards, an out-of-work dad living in the slums of a sci-fi totalitarian state, who enters a deathmatch gameshow in the hope of winning the cash he needs to save his sick child. Edgar and Simon talk action classics, staying on Arnie’s good side, and why Stephen King called the film ‘Die Hard for our time’.  

Mark reviews it too—plus two more big movies out this week: a blockbuster and an exciting indie. In the arthouse corner, the Palme d’Or-winning ‘Titane’ director Julia Ducournau’s latest, ‘Alpha’. In her usual out-there style, it follows a troubled teenage girl who returns home with a mysterious tattoo, amidst a terrifying bloodborne epidemic. And from Hollywood, ‘Now You See Me: Now You Don’t’, the latest entry in the slick magician‑heist franchise... which has left Mark wishing it would do a disappearing act. Ladies and gentlemen, be marveled as a Kermodean rant is conjured before your eyes!  

Plus more exquisite dad jokes and guaranteed groans in The Laughter Lift, and we’ll hear plenty from you lovely lot as always—including some prizewinning pedantry. Keep it coming!  

AND Don’t miss our upcoming LIVE Christmas Extravaganza at London’s Prince Edward Theatre on 7th December—with special guests Nia DaCosta, Gurinder Chadha, and more! Tickets here: fane.co.uk/kermode-mayo   

 

Timecodes (for Vanguardistas listening ad-free) 

 
Alpha Review; 13;11 

BO10; 21;42 

Edgar Wright Interview; 38;14 

The Running Man Review; 53;04 

Laughter Lift; 1;03;12 

Now You See Me; Now You Don’t Review; 1;04;40 

 
 

You can contact the show by emailing correspondence@kermodeandmayo.com or you can find us on social media, @KermodeandMayo 

Please take our survey and help shape the future of our show: https://www.kermodeandmayo.com/survey  

EXCLUSIVE NordVPN Deal ➼ https://nordvpn.com/take Try it risk-free now with a 30-day money-back guarantee! 

A Sony Music Entertainment production.     

Find more great podcasts from Sony Music Entertainment at sonymusic.com/podcasts and follow us @sonypodcasts   

To advertise on this show contact: podcastadsales@sonymusic.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>FULL SHOW: Edgar Wright on THE RUNNING MAN</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_qNDgeY9yp4</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_qNDgeY9yp4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 16:30:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Some exciting news—The Take is now on Patreon: www.patreon.com/kermodeandmayo.  Become a Vanguardista or an Ultra Vanguardista to get video episodes of Take Two every week, plus member‑only chat rooms, polls and submissions to influence the show, behind‑the‑scenes photos and videos, the monthly Redactor’s Roundup newsletter, and access to a new fortnightly LIVE show—a raucous, unfiltered lunchtime special with the Good Doctors, new features, and live chat so you can heckle, vote, and have your questions read out in real time. 

The fabulous Edgar Wright joins us on this week’s Take to talk ‘The Running Man’—his new adaptation of the Stephen King dystopia. You might remember the Arnie version from 1987, but Wright’s is a refreshed take starring very angry action man Glen Powell. He plays Ben Richards, an out-of-work dad living in the slums of a sci-fi totalitarian state, who enters a deathmatch gameshow in the hope of winning the cash he needs to save his sick child. Edgar and Simon talk action classics, staying on Arnie’s good side, and why Stephen King called the film ‘Die Hard for our time’.  

Mark reviews it too—plus two more big movies out this week: a blockbuster and an exciting indie. In the arthouse corner, the Palme d’Or-winning ‘Titane’ director Julia Ducournau’s latest, ‘Alpha’. In her usual out-there style, it follows a troubled teenage girl who returns home with a mysterious tattoo, amidst a terrifying bloodborne epidemic. And from Hollywood, ‘Now You See Me: Now You Don’t’, the latest entry in the slick magician‑heist franchise... which has left Mark wishing it would do a disappearing act. Ladies and gentlemen, be marveled as a Kermodean rant is conjured before your eyes!  

Plus more exquisite dad jokes and guaranteed groans in The Laughter Lift, and we’ll hear plenty from you lovely lot as always—including some prizewinning pedantry. Keep it coming!  

AND Don’t miss our upcoming LIVE Christmas Extravaganza at London’s Prince Edward Theatre on 7th December—with special guests Nia DaCosta, Gurinder Chadha, and more! Tickets here: fane.co.uk/kermode-mayo   

 

Timecodes (for Vanguardistas listening ad-free) 

 
Alpha Review; 13;11 

BO10; 21;42 

Edgar Wright Interview; 38;14 

The Running Man Review; 53;04 

Laughter Lift; 1;03;12 

Now You See Me; Now You Don’t Review; 1;04;40 

 
 

You can contact the show by emailing correspondence@kermodeandmayo.com or you can find us on social media, @KermodeandMayo 

Please take our survey and help shape the future of our show: https://www.kermodeandmayo.com/survey  

EXCLUSIVE NordVPN Deal ➼ https://nordvpn.com/take Try it risk-free now with a 30-day money-back guarantee! 

A Sony Music Entertainment production.     

Find more great podcasts from Sony Music Entertainment at sonymusic.com/podcasts and follow us @sonypodcasts   

To advertise on this show contact: podcastadsales@sonymusic.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Half in the Bag: Halloween Hangover (2025)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vmFFNbj3Siw</link><author>RedLetterMedia</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vmFFNbj3Siw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:00:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrTNhL_yO3tPTdQ5XgmmWjA">Movies - RedLetterMedia</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Tell me about it, Sailor!!! Hi it’s November and that's means the month of October is officially over. October is known for a holiday called Halloween. A spooky day where kids come to your home asking for candy and grownups watch horror movies, although apparently not in the theaters? Mike and Ray have seen some scary movies recently, but there was nothing scarier than the box office returns this year! Are movie theaters FINALLY dead? Ray seems to think so. Boy, does he like to complain! Talking about box office numbers being low all the time. Well... did he get out there and support horror movies and first-time directors in movie theaters? Or did he hide in his weird dungeon basement making his automated can openers and spend his time filling up thousands of "silosilianium hydroxyosuccinate" capsules all night? What he does with those I'll never know! Powders, scales, jars, capsules, duct tape, video cameras. I'll never understand it! LOL. He so craaaazy! Anyway, these two old as* clowns talk some big talk while sitting on their fat a*ses drinking coffee to sober up. So everyone get Atlanta drunk and listen to these guys talk movies!!!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>JAMES LAXTON - Cinematographer</title><link>https://teamdeakins.libsyn.com/james-laxton-cinematographer</link><author></author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/teamdeakins/S2-167_James_Laxton_Final_Aputure-Sandstorm-SPlea-2.mp3?dest-id=2018942" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.rogerdeakins.com/">Movies - Team Deakins</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[SEASON 2 - EPISODE 167 - James Laxton - CinematographerIn this episode of the Team Deakins Podcast, we speak with cinematographer James Laxton (THE UNDERGROUND RAILROAD, ANYTHING, MOONLIGHT). If you've seen a film directed by Barry Jenkins (Season 2, Episode 156), then you've seen James' work. Throughout much of the episode, we discuss his longstanding collaborative relationship with Barry, but we also learn how James tries to fit into the visions of the other directors he's worked with. The three of us share a love for preparation, and we learn how James' prep process has evolved and also stayed the same in both his work with Barry and with other filmmakers. James later reveals his perspective on executing the sweeping camera move in the diner in the final act of MOONLIGHT, and we discuss his work using colour in ANYTHING. We also compare our experiences working in animation, and James reflects on being a terrible assistant camera in his salad years.Recommended Viewing: ANYTHING, MOONLIGHT, MEDICINE FOR MELANCHOLYThis episode is sponsored by Aputure & Sandstorm]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Edgar Wright’s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f-bklvjQftk</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/f-bklvjQftk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:26:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The writer and director returns to the Criterion Closet, where he talks about a moment from BLACK NARCISSUS that is ingrained in his memory, shares what he loves about Max Ophuls and THE EARRINGS OF MADAME DE. . ., and reflects on how Richard Lester captured lightning in a bottle with A HARD DAY'S NIGHT.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ben Whishaw’s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8kKR9UakxQQ</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8kKR9UakxQQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Nov 2025 18:11:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The actor praises the melancholy tenderness of A CANTERBURY TALE, shares his admiration for Derek Jarman’s creative genius, and selects favorites like SWEETIE and L'HUMANITÉ.

You can see Ben in Ira Sachs's new film PETER HUJAR'S DAY — in theaters now from Janus Films! For showtimes and tickets: peterhujarsday.com

Shop Ben's Picks and all of your favorites from the Criterion Collection for 50% OFF at Barnes 
& Noble, both online and in stores, through December 7!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>FULL SHOW: Daniel Day-Lewis and Ronan Day-Lewis on ANEMONE</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HXWdAeoKJhA</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/HXWdAeoKJhA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Nov 2025 11:30:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Some exciting news — The Take is now on Patreon: www.patreon.com/kermodeandmayo.  Become a Vanguardista or an Ultra Vanguardista to get video episodes of Take Two every week, plus member‑only chat rooms, polls and submissions to influence the show, behind‑the‑scenes photos and videos, the monthly Redactor’s Roundup newsletter, and access to a new fortnightly LIVE show — a raucous, unfiltered lunchtime special with the Good Doctors, new features, and live chat so you can heckle, vote, and have your questions read out in real time. 

It’s a pretty special week for guests over here in Take town. We’re welcoming debut filmmaker Ronan Day-Lewis, and his dad who’s come with him and is apparently quite famous or something? Yes, that’s Sir Daniel Day-Lewis, star and co-writer of ‘Anemone’—the father-son co-created drama that has brought him out of retirement. Day-Lewis stars as reclusive and damaged former soldier Ray, who reconnects with his brother Jem (Sean Bean) after years in the wilderness. The pair unpack the film with Simon—including how a 16th Century manuscript partially inspired it, their family history in Ireland, and what it was like to write and shoot an intense father-son story as a real life father-son team. 

Mark reviews it too, along with three more big movies you can head down to the cinema to watch this weekend—code compliantly, obvs. First up, ‘Predator: Badlands’—the latest instalment in this very loooong running sci-fi action franchise which the classic villain turns hero and the hunter turns hunted. In calmer territory, we’ve got ‘The Choral’ too—a cosy drama about a Yorkshire village choir during WWI, led by controversial new conductor Dr. Henry Guthrie (Ralph Fiennes). And finally, the new and long-awaited Lynne Ramsay film ‘Die My Love’—a dark family drama starring Jennifer Lawrence and Robert Pattinson. Reckon Mark’s going to be excited about this one...  

All the usual email excellence, bantz, rantz, and everything you’ve come to expect from a top Take too. 

AND Don’t miss our upcoming LIVE Christmas Extravaganza at London’s Prince Edward Theatre on 7th December. Tickets here: fane.co.uk/kermode-mayo   



Timecodes (for Vanguardistas listening ad-free) 

 
Predator; Badlands Review; 11;33 
 
BO10; 19;21  
 
Daniel Day-Lewis & Ronan Day-Lewis Interview; 29;13  
 
Anemone Review;  30;30  
 
Laughter Lift; 57;21  
 
The Choral Review; 1;02;41 
 
Die My Love Review; 1;12;44 
 

 

You can contact the show by emailing correspondence@kermodeandmayo.com or you can find us on social media, @KermodeandMayo 

Please take our survey and help shape the future of our show: https://www.kermodeandmayo.com/survey  

EXCLUSIVE NordVPN Deal ➼ https://nordvpn.com/take Try it risk-free now with a 30-day money-back guarantee! 

A Sony Music Entertainment production.     

Find more great podcasts from Sony Music Entertainment at sonymusic.com/podcasts and follow us @sonypodcasts   

To advertise on this show contact: podcastadsales@sonymusic.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We&apos;re doing a live Christmas theatre show in London - come and join us!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=op1puD56-ZA</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/op1puD56-ZA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Nov 2025 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo 

On December 7th at 2.30pm, at the Prince Edward Theatre in London's West End, we'll be bringing you the 2025 edition of KERMODE AND MAYO'S CHRISTMAS SPECTACULAR, including special guests Jason Isaacs and Gurinder Chadha OBE. We'll be voting in the grand final of THE GREATEST CHRISTMAS MOVIE SCENE OF ALL TIME and playing KERMODE'S KRISTMAS KWIZ. 

Tickets here: https://www.fane.co.uk/kermode-mayo]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Anemone</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u-20Xydn9RY</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/u-20Xydn9RY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Nov 2025 00:01:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

In Northern England, a man heads out on a journey into the woods to reconnect with the estranged hermit brother with whom he shared a complicated past that was altered by life-changing events decades ago.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>07/11/2025 Box Office Top Ten</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tVQ6NJIVbSs</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/tVQ6NJIVbSs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Nov 2025 00:01:14 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark and Simon Mayo run through this week's box office top 10…

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Predator: Badlands</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wvauJ_lqPLA</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wvauJ_lqPLA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Nov 2025 00:01:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

A young Predator outcast from his clan finds an unlikely ally on his journey in search of the ultimate adversary.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Die, My Love</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kXCDv_EkEng</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/kXCDv_EkEng?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Nov 2025 00:01:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Grace, a writer and young mother, is slowly slipping into madness. Locked away in an old house in and around Montana, we see her acting increasingly agitated and erratic, leaving her companion, Jackson, increasingly worried and helpless.
  
To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The best/worst dad jokes from the Laughter Lift 07/11/2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oxHpjm6mvIE</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/oxHpjm6mvIE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Nov 2025 00:01:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark Kermode and Simon Mayo

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews The Choral</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZYJStu0_gjc</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZYJStu0_gjc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Nov 2025 00:01:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

A choral society's male members enlist in World War I, leaving the demanding Dr. Guthrie to recruit teenagers. Together, they experience the joy of singing while the young boys grapple with their impending conscription into the army.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Simon Mayo Interviews Daniel and Ronan Day-Lewis</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2ChsKbCrnh4</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2ChsKbCrnh4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 7 Nov 2025 00:01:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>