<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Movies</title><link>https://konrad.website/feeds/</link><description></description><item><title>We ❤️ John Cassavetes | Closet Picks Edition</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/COEHFCx2UWk</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/COEHFCx2UWk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 23:52:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The films of John Cassavetes, pioneer of American independent cinema, recommended by visitors to the Criterion Closet.

The FIVE FILMS box set is available–alongside individual Blu-ray editions of HUSBANDS (1970), A WOMAN UNDER THE INFLUENCE (1974), and LOVE STREAMS (1984)–from criterion.com: https://www.criterion.com/shop/collection/135-john-cassavetes]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>MARTIN CAMPBELL - Director</title><link>https://teamdeakins.libsyn.com/martin-campbell-director</link><author></author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/teamdeakins/S2-182_Martin_Campbell_Final_PictureShop-Aputure-SPlea.mp3?dest-id=2018942" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.rogerdeakins.com/">Movies - Team Deakins</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[SEASON 2 - EPISODE 182 - Martin Campbell - DirectorIn this episode of the Team Deakins Podcast, we speak with director Martin Campbell (CASINO ROYALE, GOLDENEYE, EDGE OF DARKNESS). Faced with limited options for a career as a cameraman in New Zealand, Martin sailed to England, and five years in TV and 51 Tom Jones shows later, Martin transitioned into directing full time. As big fans of Martin's EDGE OF DARKNESS (1985), we didn't miss the opportunity to ask him about the making of the six-part BBC limited series, and we extensively discuss his choices and the challenges he faced. Martin describes the relative freedom the BBC gave him to shoot it, and we learn why he cast Bob Peck and Joe Don Baker in the two lead roles. Martin also reveals how they filmed the show as the scripts came in, and we discuss the alternative ending originally written for the final episode. Plus, Martin reveals why he remade the show as a feature years later in the United States. With two Bond films under his belt, Martin later shares how he was approached to direct GOLDENEYE, and he reveals why CASINO ROYALE was chosen to be grounded in reality. Martin also shares his tips for dealing with studio notes, and he reflects on how, throughout his life, his previous experiences set him up for success for what came next.Recommended Viewing: EDGE OF DARKNESS (1985 UK TV Series)This episode is sponsored by Picture Shop & Aputure]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Why Some Movies Feel More Alive</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vwUrzKaXyT4</link><author>Thomas Flight</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vwUrzKaXyT4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:08:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFUyvQV2JsICeLZP4c_h40kA">Movies - Thomas Flight</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get $30 off your first order of Cometeer: https://cometeer.com/thomasflight

More than just a blur of faces in the background, extras play a crucial but often overlooked role in the art of filmmaking. This video examines some of the most unique, interesting, and artful uses of extras I've ever seen in film and TV. 

// FIND MY WORK // 
-Early Access (Ad Free) on Nebula: https://nebula.tv/thomasflight
-Read my Newsletter: https://www.seeingthroughfilm.com/
-Reviews on Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/thomasflight
-Watch My Experimental Documentary: https://labyrinthion.com
-Website: http://www.thomasflight.com

// FOLLOW ME //
- Letterboxd: https://letterboxd.com/thomasflight/
- Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/thomasflight
- Twitter: https://twitter.com/thomasflight
- Substack: https://thomasflight.substack.com/

// CONTACT //
-Sponsorship and Business inquiries: thomasflight@nebula.tv
-Questions, feedback, anything else: contact@thomasflight.com
-FAQ: https://www.thomasflight.com/faq

// GEAR I USE // 
https://thomasflight.com/gear

#ThomasFlight #VideoEssay]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Halle Berry’s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NxtUjQOrJZU</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NxtUjQOrJZU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 19:29:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The actor and director talks about what makes FANTASTIC MR. FOX a household favorite, shares how Gina Prince-Bythewood inspired her to step behind the camera, and praises Diahann Carroll and her performance in CLAUDINE.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ranking Every Sam Raimi Movie Part 2 - re:View</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mzFMJgWklz4</link><author>RedLetterMedia</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/mzFMJgWklz4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 15:50:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFrTNhL_yO3tPTdQ5XgmmWjA">Movies - RedLetterMedia</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Alex Winter’s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=284iOLWmQCw</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/284iOLWmQCw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 19:00:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The actor and director praises Iranian cinema legends Abbas Kiarostami and Jafar Panahi, shares why he considers Luis Buñuel to be “the grand master of cinema,” and reminisces about spending his childhood at the movie theater.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Untitled Movie Genre Themed Trivia Related Program (Alternate Edit)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K70Ol8au1uY</link><author>RedLetterMedia</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/K70Ol8au1uY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:49:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFrTNhL_yO3tPTdQ5XgmmWjA">Movies - RedLetterMedia</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Watch two adult persons whose gender assigned at birth is male answer safe and fun questions about movies in a certain genre that is acceptable for most folks. Jay and Josh answer questions from host Mike. In the end both contestants will be awarded a participation trophy and crowned "most knowledgeable peoples or persons" in this particular category of which is displayed.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The best/worst dad jokes from the Laughter Lift 20/02/2026</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r7EjAr4a94Q</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/r7EjAr4a94Q?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:01:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark Kermode and Simon Mayo

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Wasteman</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sj4T-e--PXw</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/sj4T-e--PXw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:01:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Follows parolee Taylor whose fresh start hopes are jeopardized by cellmate Dee's arrival. As Dee takes Taylor under his wing, a vicious attack tests their bond, forcing Taylor to choose between protecting Dee and his own parole chances.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>20/02/2026 Box Office Top Ten</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rE8sjA3irAc</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/rE8sjA3irAc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:01:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark and Simon Mayo run through this week's box office top 10…

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Simon Mayo Interviews Amanda Seyfried and Mona Fastvold</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oqBGHNfzDvs</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/oqBGHNfzDvs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:01:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews The Secret Agent</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LTyAAxxPcRM</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/LTyAAxxPcRM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:01:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

In 1977, a technology expert flees from a mysterious past and returns to his hometown of Recife in search of peace. He soon realizes that the city is far from being the refuge he seeks.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Good Luck, Have Fun, Don’t Die</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DWtOETn8BEQ</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/DWtOETn8BEQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:01:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

A "Man From the Future" arrives at a diner in Los Angeles where he must recruit the precise combination of disgruntled patrons to join him on a one-night quest to save the world from the terminal threat of a rogue artificial intelligence.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews If I Had Legs I’d Kick You</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3Kps_xRd2Do</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/3Kps_xRd2Do?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:01:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

While trying to manage her own life and career, a woman on the verge of a breakdown must cope with her daughter's illness, an absent husband, a missing person, and an unusual relationship with her therapist.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Lucy Liu on IN THE MOOD FOR LOVE (2000)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/kg6B7HL5jAI</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/kg6B7HL5jAI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 22:39:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[All Criterion 4K editions — including Wong Kar Wai's IN THE MOOD FOR LOVE — are now 30% OFF at criterion.com! Shop now through February 22!

Watch Lucy's full Closet Video here: criterion.com/shop/collection/910-lucy-liu-s-closet-picks]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Amanda Seyfried… as a Mancunian?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gndWetwT-3Y</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/gndWetwT-3Y?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:15:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Some exciting news—The Take is now on Patreon: www.patreon.com/kermodeandmayo.  Become a Vanguardista or an Ultra Vanguardista to get video episodes of Take Two every week, plus member‑only chat rooms, polls and submissions to influence the show, behind‑the‑scenes photos and videos, the monthly Redactor’s Roundup newsletter, and access to a new fortnightly LIVE show—a raucous, unfiltered lunchtime special with the Good Doctors, new features, and live chat so you can heckle, vote, and have your questions read out in real time.  
Amanda Seyfried is our special guest this week. She’s starred in Mean Girls, The Housemaid and Mamma Mia!, but she’s never been a Mancunian... until now. She joins Simon alongside writer-director Mona Fastvold to talk about The Testament of Ann Lee, in which Seyfried stars as the titular leader of the Shakers. You might not have heard of her and the 18th century radical religious sect she founded—and we promise you’ve definitely never seen a musical about her. Seyfried talks about her struggle to crack a Manchester accent for the role, never mind all that ecstatic song and dance—and we hear from Fastvold about he old-school filmmaking techniques that helped her and co-writer husband Brady Corbet bring this unique story to the screen on shoestring budget.  

Mark will review The Testament of Ann Lee next week, but we’ve got four more movie reviews for you in the meantime—it's a packed show! First, The Secret Agent, where paranoia and deception collide as an ex-academic gets caught up in South American political turmoil. Then there’s If I Had Legs I'd Kick You, a darkly comic tale of maternal burnout pushed to surreal extremes. We also have Wasteman—a gritty prison drama starring Rye Lane’s David Jonsson. And finally, Good Luck Have Fun Don't Die, a genre-bending evil-tech adventure starring Sam Rockwell.  

Plus all the usual delights: the box office top 10, the unpredictable joy of the Laughter Lift, and your tip-top correspondence. Don’t miss it. 


Timecodes 

00:00:00 Show starts  
00:10:09 The Secret Agent review  
00:22:02 Box Office Top 10  
00:39:24 Mona Fastvold and Amanda Seyfried interview  
01:01:24 If I Had Legs I’d Kick You review  
01:07:35 Laughter Lift  
01:12:09  Wasteman review  
01:19:13  Good Luck, Have Fun, Don’t Die review  


You can contact the show by emailing correspondence@kermodeandmayo.com or you can find us on social media, @KermodeandMayo 

Please take our survey and help shape the future of our show: https://www.kermodeandmayo.com/survey  

EXCLUSIVE NordVPN Deal ➼ https://nordvpn.com/take Try it risk-free now with a 30-day money-back guarantee! 

A Sony Music Entertainment production.     

Find more great podcasts from Sony Music Entertainment at sonymusic.com/podcasts and follow us @sonypodcasts   

To advertise on this show contact: podcastadsales@sonymusic.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Trivia of Terror</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vgZtjULJvkU</link><author>RedLetterMedia</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vgZtjULJvkU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 18:48:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFrTNhL_yO3tPTdQ5XgmmWjA">Movies - RedLetterMedia</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Tell us all about it, sailor! You asked for it! Here it is! MOAR TRIVIA! This time, the elderly clown-man, Mike curates a bunch of random questions about horror pictures for Jay and Josh to answer and be made fools of. Finding questions that didn’t seem too easy or too hard was actually kind of difficult. Mike knows some things about horror, but not too mech. He nows moar about Star Trek and eating ultra processed foods from the Dollar Store. Did you know he shops for groceries at the Dollar Store?!? I once caught that man eating a box of shortbread cookies and ramen noodles for “dinner” then for a dessert he had a generic brand frozen pizza with a bottle of that sugar juice. I looked at the “nutritional” facts on the pizza. Zeros in all categories except carbohydrates and sodium. 50,000mg of sodium - 100 million times your recommended daily amount. Same with the carbs. 250 million grams of carbohydrates. 55 billion times your daily limit. That’s like eating liquid concrete. No food value. Anyway, I digress. Jay and special guest Josh Roger Thompson join the gang for this embarrassing trivia show down. Josh knows horror though. Him and Jay chat it up constantly. Like the saying goes, Jay is Josh’s brother from another individual(s) that currently identifies as a woman or person or person(s) assigned that specific gender or non-gender at birth. Josh knows lots of things, but he’s no match for Jay’s recall. Jay can remember mostly any actor from any movie. His memory is a steel bear trap. But I guess the biggest takeaway from this whole video is that Josh thinks Shaun of the Dead is “Hipster horse sh*t” “A two star film at best”. Get ready for the battle of the century as these two titans of weird perv*rted horror movies duke it out in a filthy Wisconsin warehouse!!!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>JACK FISK - Production Designer</title><link>https://teamdeakins.libsyn.com/jack-fisk-production-designer</link><author></author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/teamdeakins/S2-181_Jack_Fisk_Final_Aputure-PictureShop-SPlea.mp3?dest-id=2018942" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.rogerdeakins.com/">Movies - Team Deakins</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[SEASON 2 - EPISODE 181 - Jack Fisk - Production DesignerIn this extended episode of the Team Deakins Podcast, we speak with production designer Jack Fisk (MARTY SUPREME, THERE WILL BE BLOOD, MULHOLLAND DRIVE). Spanning the worlds' jungles, mountains, and open plains, Jack's work as a designer brings the real world to the audience on the big screen. Throughout our conversation, Jack discusses his views on designing, and he recalls numerous stories detailing the exhaustive work behind his contributions to films such as DAYS OF HEAVEN, THE THIN RED LINE, and THE REVENANT. Later, Jack reveals how he resurrected post-war New York City in the Lower East Side in MARTY SUPREME, and we discuss how he collaborated with cinematographer Darius Khondji (Season 1, Episode 135) on the film and strove for originality in its design. Jack also reflects on the evolution of his lifelong friendship with David Lynch from high school up until his death in 2025, and he shares how he overcame a number of obstacles while designing MULHOLLAND DRIVE. Plus, Jack recalls how he survived the "highway of death" in Costa Rica.Listen to Ruth De Jong's episode (Season 2, Episode 49) to learn even more about Jack.Recommended Viewing: MULHOLLAND DRIVE, DAYS OF HEAVENThis episode is sponsored by Aputure & Picture Shop ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>From Criterion, With Love | Closet Picks Edition</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/2SS0RQzGvds</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2SS0RQzGvds?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 20:49:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Eight perfect Valentine’s Day films, recommended by visitors to the Criterion Closet:

LOVE & BASKETBALL (2000)
IN THE MOOD FOR LOVE (2000)
THE AGE OF INNOCENCE (1993)
Y TU MAMÁ TAMBIÉN (2001)
PUNCH-DRUNK LOVE (2002)
LOVE JONES (1997)
MOONSTRUCK (1987)
BRIEF ENCOUNTER (1945)

IN THE MOOD FOR LOVE, THE AGE OF INNOCENCE, and BRIEF ENCOUNTER are now playing on our streaming service, The Criterion Channel: https://www.criterionchannel.com/browse]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Diego Calva’s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZJF_asiGU3c</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZJF_asiGU3c?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:13:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The actor talks about studying Charlie Chaplin’s performance in CITY LIGHTS, shows off his tattoos dedicated to AFTER HOURS and SLACKER, and selects favorite coming-of-age movies by Harmony Korine and Andrea Arnold.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Crime 101</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hw1qbxAftU0</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hw1qbxAftU0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

An elusive thief, eyeing his final score, encounters a disillusioned insurance broker at her own crossroads. As their paths intertwine, a relentless detective trails them hoping to thwart the multi-million dollar heist they are planning.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://listen.sonymusic-podcasts.link/TFTF28194?sid=kermodeandmayo.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The best/worst dad jokes from the Laughter Lift 13/02/2026</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hQijOgeepRw</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hQijOgeepRw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark Kermode and Simon Mayo

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://listen.sonymusic-podcasts.link/TFTF28194?sid=kermodeandmayo.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Wuthering Heights</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hSkSk4cb54Q</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hSkSk4cb54Q?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

A passionate and tumultuous love story set against the backdrop of the Yorkshire moors, exploring the intense and destructive relationship between Heathcliff and Catherine Earnshaw.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://listen.sonymusic-podcasts.link/TFTF28194?sid=kermodeandmayo.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>13/02/2026 Box Office Top Ten</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iM35ZGfZPb0</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/iM35ZGfZPb0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark and Simon Mayo run through this week's box office top 10…

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://listen.sonymusic-podcasts.link/TFTF28194?sid=kermodeandmayo.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Little Amélie</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X1qRrUxVzzQ</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/X1qRrUxVzzQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Amélie, a Belgian child in Japan, explores life with her companion Nishio-san. Her third birthday becomes a turning point, marking the beginning of life-altering events that shape her understanding of the world.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://listen.sonymusic-podcasts.link/TFTF28194?sid=kermodeandmayo.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Simon Mayo interviews Emerald Fennell</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TK5i0gbeE4s</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/TK5i0gbeE4s?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://listen.sonymusic-podcasts.link/TFTF28194?sid=kermodeandmayo.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Whistle</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A7z90Ln-EK8</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/A7z90Ln-EK8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

A misfit group of unwitting high school students stumble upon a cursed object, an ancient Aztec Death Whistle. They discover that blowing the whistle and the terrifying sound it emits will summon their future deaths to hunt them down.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://listen.sonymusic-podcasts.link/TFTF28194?sid=kermodeandmayo.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Charli xcx &amp; Aidan Zamiri | The A24 Podcast</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F7cBEKMPRwE</link><author>A24</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/F7cBEKMPRwE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLpd1itfTDtaVLCrM6OgjyE7TY_CwUnnGE">Movies - A24 Podcast</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[SUBSCRIBE: http://bit.ly/A24subscribe

Girl, Whatever with Charli xcx & Aidan Zamiri

Topics covered include:
Aidan first becoming aware of Charli, early demos of “I Love It,” Scandi accents, the whelks at Caroline Polachek’s birthday, silliness as high art, imposing structure, growing up on Tumblr, voyeurism, Aidan’s work with Timothée on the Marty Supreme campaign, a general sense of FOMO, teapot necklaces, Aidan’s mom’s notes on the “Guess” music video, not wanting to present yourself as an entrepreneur, embracing embarrassment, Charli’s early tracks like “Dinosaur Sex” and “I Wanna Be Darth Vader,” being a tiny bit hungover, and a brief round of the Cauldron Game.

------

ABOUT A24:
The studio behind EVERYTHING EVERYWHERE ALL AT ONCE, UNCUT GEMS, MIDSOMMAR, MOONLIGHT, BEEF on Netflix, EUPHORIA on Max & more.

Coming Soon: HOW TO MAKE A KILLING, UNDERTONE, THE DRAMA

Subscribe to A24's NEWSLETTER:  http://bit.ly/A24signup
Sign up for A24 MEMBERSHIP: aaa24.com
Visit A24 WEBSITE: http://bit.ly/A24filmsdotcom
Like A24 on FACEBOOK: http://bit.ly/FBA24
Follow A24 on TWITTER: http://bit.ly/TweetA24
Follow A24 on INSTAGRAM: http://bit.ly/InstaA24]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>NICHOLAS BRITELL - Composer</title><link>https://teamdeakins.libsyn.com/nicholas-britell-composer</link><author></author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/teamdeakins/S2-180_Nicholas_Britell_Final_PictureShop-Aputure-SPlea.mp3?dest-id=2018942" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.rogerdeakins.com/">Movies - Team Deakins</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[SEASON 2 - EPISODE 180 - Nicholas Britell - ComposerIn this episode of the Team Deakins Podcast, we speak with composer Nicholas Britell (JAY KELLY, DON'T LOOK UP, MOONLIGHT). "How can a score function within a film?" is the question driving most of our conversation with Nicholas, and throughout the episode he generously provides insight into his process and recalls several examples from his own work to demonstrate how he and his directors arrived at specific pieces of music. We also reflect on the varying natures of scores across film history, and Nicholas shares the challenges of composing for television. He also shares the types of conversations he has with directors after he's brought onto a project, and we learn how he developed the themes for JAY KELLY, DON'T LOOK UP, and THE BIG SHORT. In addition to composing full scores, Nicholas has also contributed music heard within a film's world—during the development of 12 YEARS A SLAVE, he was brought on to compose the songs played in individual scenes, and he reflects on how he balanced the music as both a dramatic element and a piece of history. Recommended Viewing: DON'T LOOK UPThis episode is sponsored by Picture Shop & Aputure]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Wagner Moura on Mário Peixoto&apos;s LIMITE (1931)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/tiafmmKAUBE</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/tiafmmKAUBE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 9 Feb 2026 19:52:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Watch LIMITE on the Criterion Channel and as part of our Martin Scorsese's World Cinema Project No. 2 box set and check out Wagner's full Closet video here: criterion.com/shop/collection/892-wagner-moura-s-closet-picks

An astonishing creation, LIMITE is the only feature by the Brazilian director and author Mário Peixoto, made when he was just twenty-two years old. Inspired by a haunting André Kertész photograph on the cover of a French magazine, this avant-garde silent master­piece centers on a man and two women lost at sea, their pasts unfolding through flashbacks propelled by the music of Erik Satie, Claude Debussy, Igor Stravinsky, and others. An early work of independent Latin American filmmaking, LIMITE was famously difficult to see for most of the twentieth century. It is a pioneering achievement that continues to captivate with its timeless visual poetry.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Laura Dern’s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c2IZf_NRJKs</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/c2IZf_NRJKs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 9 Feb 2026 18:42:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The actor fondly recalls the gift of working with David Lynch on INLAND EMPIRE, praises the comedic brilliance of Albert Brooks, and  pairs Robert Altman and Spike Lee as directors whose films capture “the essence of culture, community, and truth.”

You can watch some of Laura's amazing Closet Picks on the Criterion Channel now!
TANNER '88
FANNY AND ALEXANDER
PERSONA
DIABOLIQUE
THE UMBRELLAS OF CHERBOURG
BELLE DE JOUR
DAVID LYNCH: THE ART LIFE
INLAND EMPIRE
SMOOTH TALK
ESSENTIAL FELLINI
SCORSESE SHORTS]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ranking Every Sam Raimi Movie Part 1 - re:View</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H4UxU0mu06M</link><author>RedLetterMedia</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/H4UxU0mu06M?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 8 Feb 2026 15:55:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=UULFrTNhL_yO3tPTdQ5XgmmWjA">Movies - RedLetterMedia</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[With the recent release of Sam Raimi's new movie Send Help, Jay and Rich decided to do another ranking video! Raimi's Spider-Man movies are beloved by an entire generation that grew up with them, so get ready to be angry at Rich!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mary Bronstein&apos;s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o4Zt1CAprPo</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/o4Zt1CAprPo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 6 Feb 2026 18:48:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The writer and director selects a pair of feminist films by Dorothy Arzner, shares why Chantal Akerman and David Lynch are her filmmaking idols, and praises how Eric Rohmer’s SIX MORAL TALES portray complex dynamics between women and men.]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>