<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Movies</title><link>https://konrad.website/feeds/</link><description></description><item><title>Jodie Foster’s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wO2fHMqAXO8</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wO2fHMqAXO8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:50:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The actor and director shares her love for the films of Céline Sciamma, talks about the Olympic documentary VISIONS OF EIGHT, and reminisces about watching BERLIN ALEXANDERPLATZ with her mom.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews H is for Hawk</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XbSdnF-kjPs</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XbSdnF-kjPs?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:01:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

After losing her beloved father, Helen finds herself saved by an unlikely friendship with a stubborn hawk named Mabel.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>23/01/2026 Box Office Top Ten</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=usD3fHTUIec</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/usD3fHTUIec?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:01:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark and Simon Mayo run through this week's box office top 10…

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews No Other Choice</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YgP5Wnahy3o</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/YgP5Wnahy3o?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:01:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

After being unemployed for several years, a man devises a unique plan to secure a new job: eliminate his competition.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Simon Mayo Interviews Claire Foy</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-a8vZp-vmI4</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-a8vZp-vmI4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:01:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Saipan</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5SOwhAK5YvQ</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5SOwhAK5YvQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:01:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

On the eve of the 2002 FIFA World Cup, the Irish captain Roy Keane forfeits his place in the squad at the team's preparation base in Saipan, following a heated disagreement with the Irish manager Mick McCarthy.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews The History of Sound</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0I-GpdqlFHU</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0I-GpdqlFHU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:01:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Two young men during World War I set out to record the lives, voices and music of their American countrymen.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The best/worst dad jokes from the Laughter Lift 23/01/2026</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JVTgUpmDcS4</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/JVTgUpmDcS4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:01:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark Kermode and Simon Mayo

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>FULL SHOW: Can Claire Foy handle a “perfectly evolved psychopath” in H IS FOR HAWK?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tdc95STthdM</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/tdc95STthdM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:01:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Some exciting news—The Take is now on Patreon: www.patreon.com/kermodeandmayo.  Become a Vanguardista or an Ultra Vanguardista to get video episodes of Take Two every week, plus member‑only chat rooms, polls and submissions to influence the show, behind‑the‑scenes photos and videos, the monthly Redactor’s Roundup newsletter, and access to a new fortnightly LIVE show—a raucous, unfiltered lunchtime special with the Good Doctors, new features, and live chat so you can heckle, vote, and have your questions read out in real time.  
Claire Foy is our special guest this week—and we promise that’s not just because her dad keeps writing in to the show... It’s also because she’s starring in H is For Hawk, out in cinemas this week. She plays Helen, who decides to keep and train a notoriously difficult goshawk as a means of coming to terms with the death of her father (played by Brendan Gleeson). Claire chats to Simon about bringing this bestselling memoir to the screen and learning to falcon with one of these ‘perfectly evolved psychopaths’ for real. 

Mark reviews H is for Hawk, plus three more fresh film releases—it's a packed show! First, Saipan—the football drama starring Éanna Hardwicke as Roy Keane and Steve Coogan as Ireland manager Mick McCarthy, which charts their legendary bust-up ahead of the 2002 world cup. From Korean cinema superstar Park Chan-wook we’ve got No Other Choice, a black comedy about a white-collar worker who turns lethal after being laid off. And last but certainly not least we’ve got even more Josh O’Connor and more Paul Mescal (surely those two lads deserve a holiday?) in The History of Sound—a gay romance between two student musicians in WW1 era America.   
Plus all the cinema action from the box office top 10, the endless hilarity of the laughter lift, and your tip top correspondence. Don’t miss it!  

Timings

00:00 Podcast begins
08: 36 Saipan review 
18:43 Box Office Top 10 
 42:09 Claire Foy Interview
58:08 Hi is for Hawk review
01:07:47 Laughter Lift
 01:16:01 The History of Sound
01:10:54 No Other Choice review

You can contact the show by emailing correspondence@kermodeandmayo.com or you can find us on social media, @KermodeandMayo 

Please take our survey and help shape the future of our show: https://www.kermodeandmayo.com/survey  

EXCLUSIVE NordVPN Deal ➼ https://nordvpn.com/take Try it risk-free now with a 30-day money-back guarantee! 

A Sony Music Entertainment production.     

Find more great podcasts from Sony Music Entertainment at sonymusic.com/podcasts and follow us @sonypodcasts   

To advertise on this show contact: podcastadsales@sonymusic.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Star Trek: Deep Space Nine - Season One (part 2) - re:View</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SXYFrc1-ES8</link><author>RedLetterMedia</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/SXYFrc1-ES8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:56:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrTNhL_yO3tPTdQ5XgmmWjA">Movies - RedLetterMedia</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Best friends Rick and Morn talk about the remaining episodes of season 1 of Star Trek: Deep Space Nine. As of this writing, the new show Star Trek: Starfleet Academy has come out and it's release is totally unrelated to this release. The timing is pure coincidence I assure you. Mark and Gork love Star Trek and probably will continue to talk about. However, after seeing Starfleet Academy (or SA as Kurtzman calls it) it is so bad and misguided it's almost a moot point. Star Trek as it once was... is lost. I think it's too far gone. It is possible to make a new series (with new producers) and set it in the 24th century in an isolated setting and have smaller, well written stories that don't involve revenge, a super-weapon, or people that sound like total idiots and are annoying, but knowing that the future of Starfleet will eventually look like it does is a specter that cannot be ignored. What has happened? HOW did this happen? Who has dirt on who? Is NuTrek a scam? A tax write-off? Is 80% of the budget going to the 24 credited producers? I mean, how does a show with so few viewers even become profitable for a streaming service. Or even an asset and not a liability? Morg smells something fishy going on... maybe? At least according to his opinion. Rork and Glorg in no way suggest any illegal activity, but just perhaps activity that might not be moral at the very least. I mean, seriously? It's become a joke at this point. Anyway, no one can ever take my DS9 DVDs away from me. You'll have to pry them from my cold, dead hand. Anyway, enjoy this deep dive into old Trek. Rich and Mike promise more. MUCH MORE!!! WE WILL NOT STOP. WE WILL CONTINUE!!!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>JAMES SLATTERY - Colourist</title><link>https://teamdeakins.libsyn.com/james-slattery-colourist</link><author></author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/teamdeakins/S2-177_James_Slattery_Final_Aputure-SPlea.mp3?dest-id=2018942" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.rogerdeakins.com/">Movies - Team Deakins</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[SEASON 2 - EPISODE 177 - James Slattery - ColouristIn this extended episode of the Team Deakins Podcast, we speak with colourist James Slattery (THE LOST BUS, EMPIRE OF LIGHT, 1917). How does someone become a colourist? What do they really do? What is a CDL? DI? QC? DIT? P3? HDR? James, with whom we've worked with several times, graciously explains what all these acronyms (and more) mean, how a colourist generally goes about their work nowadays on any given project, and what he's able to do to help filmmakers solve problems and help realize their visions in the final stages of post-production. James has experience timing dailies and also applying the finishing grade, and he helps us explain the different responsibilities and expectations of each process. James later helps us provide an overview of the different types of deliverables for a film, and he shares some common mistakes young colorists today should avoid. Though the role of a colourist is technically and creatively demanding, James, throughout our conversation, stresses the importance of being able to work with others as a member of the team.This episode is sponsored by Aputure]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We ❤️ David Lynch | Closet Picks Edition</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/ujVHv-tdoxk</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ujVHv-tdoxk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 20:48:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[On the 80th anniversary of his birth, join Criterion in celebrating the life and art of David Lynch! ❤️ 

Now through January 23, you can shop our special editions of his films — including ERASERHEAD, BLUE VELVET, TWIN PEAKS: FIRE WALK WITH ME, LOST HIGHWAY, MULHOLLAND DR., INLAND EMPIRE, and two documentaries about his work — for 30% off at criterion.com. 

https://www.criterion.com/shop/collection/499-david-lynch]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>When an Actor Didn’t Need Hollywood – Javier Bardem</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZPWZ1OYL2yw</link><author>FilmStack</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZPWZ1OYL2yw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCFOfgEQLHpPuVNP_m-XldTg">Movies - FilmStack</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Javier Bardem calls his career an “accident”. He never planned to be an actor. He never expected to learn English or work in Hollywood. For most of his early career, he assumed he would stay in Spain until Before Night Falls earned him an Oscar nomination. What started as an experiment changed the direction of his career.

Soon after, Bardem became the first Spanish actor to win an Oscar for No Country for Old Men, delivering one of the most iconic villain performances ever. Hollywood took notice, pushing him into major studio films like Skyfall, where he did it again.

But Bardem never abandoned Spanish cinema. Some of his best work came outside Hollywood, in films like The Sea Inside and Biutiful. As his Hollywood momentum grew, that balance became harder to maintain, eventually leading to the worst stretch of his career. It was only when Bardem focused on both Spanish films and Hollywood that everything clicked again, with performances in The Good Boss, Being the Ricardos and Dune.

This is the story of when an actor didn’t need Hollywood, moving in and out of it without ever letting it define him. This is Javier Bardem.

Chapters:
00:00 - The Intro
00:59 - Never The Plan
05:13 - Hello Hollywood
11:59 - Balance

Javier Bardem. Penelope Cruz. Best Spanish Actor. Best Supporting Actor Oscar. No Country For Old Men. Skyfall. Anton Chigurh. Raoul Silva. Dune. Dune Part Two. Stilgar. Before Night Falls. The Sea Inside. Jamón, jamón. Mondays in the Sun. Vicky Cristina Barcelona. Biutiful. Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Men Tell No Tales. Mother! Everybody Knows. F1 2025 Movie. 

If you like this video don't forget to leave a like, and if you're interested in videos about movies and the film industry in general, make sure to subscribe to FilmStack for more great content.

If you have any other ideas for videos, leave a comment and I might make a video with your idea.

Patreon: https://patreon.com/FilmStack
Twitter: https://twitter.com/realFilmStack
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/realfilmstack/

#javierbardem    #actor   #spanish]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Stellan Skarsgård’s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vpw582iA-n4</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vpw582iA-n4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:53:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The actor talks about showing SEVEN SAMURAI to all of his children, celebrates Katrin Cartlidge’s performance in NAKED, and shares why CITY LIGHTS never fails to make him cry.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Rental Family</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kRIaMKwe_8E</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/kRIaMKwe_8E?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:01:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

An American actor in Tokyo struggling to find purpose lands an unusual gig: working for a Japanese "rental family" agency, playing stand-in roles for strangers. He rediscovers purpose, belonging, and the beauty of human connection.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Simon Mayo Interviews Jack O’Connell</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wBnx50NKico</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wBnx50NKico?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:01:24 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>15/01/2026 Box Office Top Ten</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TWED790Wq5s</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/TWED790Wq5s?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:01:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark and Simon Mayo run through this week's box office top 10…

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews 28 Years Later: The Bone Temple</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fLGv3Jc6P9M</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/fLGv3Jc6P9M?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:01:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

As Spike is inducted into Jimmy Crystal's gang on the mainland, Dr. Kelson makes a discovery that could alter the world.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The best/worst dad jokes from the Laughter Lift 16/01/2026</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EMT5lVi_mDc</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EMT5lVi_mDc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:01:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark Kermode and Simon Mayo

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews The Voice of Hind Rajab</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DfWE7Vm1z1Y</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/DfWE7Vm1z1Y?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:01:14 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Red Crescent volunteers receive an emergency call. A 6-year old girl is trapped in a car under IDF fire in Gaza, pleading for rescue. While trying to keep her on the line, they do everything they can to get an ambulance to her.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Star Trek: Deep Space Nine - Season One (part 1) - re:View</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u5ozNRUW7Kw</link><author>RedLetterMedia</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/u5ozNRUW7Kw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:35:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrTNhL_yO3tPTdQ5XgmmWjA">Movies - RedLetterMedia</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Rich and Mike talk about Star Trek Deep Space Nine! Finally! But it's season one you say? You're right! Rarely are the first seasons of shows outright exceptional (with some outright exceptions) most times they're good enough to pass muster, until they find stable footing. Deep Space Nine is no different! Light years ahead of the awkward first season of TNG, DS9 slides right into it's groove early on. While there are lots of isolated TNG-esque one-off story lines and some early character developing episodes, DS9 season one is a solid layer of quality "paste" as Rich Evans so eloquently puts it. Rich and Mark talk briefly about each episode, pausing to pick favorites along these way. Watch them two old, confused, boring, elderly, genXer scumbags wax nostalgic for quaint old television before the time of woke nightmare sauce spilling out of every eyeball. Before shows made it based on viewership ratings and not streaming service fodder for animal troughs of marketable IP's and stock market shareholder data portfolios for investors. In addition to the Matlock reboot for the olds, we've got this over-produced glossy, fast moving, fart-filled, hip gen-zers (not watching Star Trek I can assure you) tiktok framed clips and nightmare fuel. This embarrassing attempt by old cracker boomer producers to create a program to appeal to Z's that not a single one will take the time to watch. out-of-touch,  buzz-worthy hip-hop, busin' zazz dancin' kidz in Starfleet, bouncing pronouns off the shields as they flubba dubb to the latest crunchy zen-dash touch grass brah. Stella zoinks, lady no cap! You going to the no-alcohol Trek bash in Hall H later where WE DANCE with Starfleet costumes and tell each other we're boss-folks and learn about ourselves while respecting each other's rizz? Heck yeah! It's gonna be tripe and no one there will be sus or clutch fringe cringe. Insta-gram it for me brah! I'll be beaming in later after my exams!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>FULL SHOW: Jack O’Connell on 28 YEARS LATER: THE BONE TEMPLE</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dIbCOn1qicM</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/dIbCOn1qicM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Some exciting news—The Take is now on Patreon: www.patreon.com/kermodeandmayo.  Become a Vanguardista or an Ultra Vanguardista to get video episodes of Take Two every week, plus member‑only chat rooms, polls and submissions to influence the show, behind‑the‑scenes photos and videos, the monthly Redactor’s Roundup newsletter, and access to a new fortnightly LIVE show—a raucous, unfiltered lunchtime special with the Good Doctors, new features, and live chat so you can heckle, vote, and have your questions read out in real time.  
The chilling on screen (but charming IRL) Jack O’Connell joins us on the Take this week to talk 28 Years Later: the Bone Temple. Directed by Nia DaCosta, who loyal listeners may remember from our live Christmas Extravaganza, it’s the second installment in a sequel trilogy to Danny Boyle’s zombie smash hit. Jack talks tracksuits, tiaras and being the most villainous actor of the past year—plus lots more on-set insights from the horror-thriller that’s got you all talking. Don;t miss this one!  
Mark reviews Bone Temple too, plus more of this week’s fresh new films. First up, Rental Family—which sees Brendan Fraser’s Philip join a Japanese agency providing fake ‘family for hire’ for its clients’ social and companionship needs. Plus a tougher but important watch, The Voice of Hind Rajab, which replays the tragic death of six-year-old Hind Rajab—killed in Gaza in January 2024—based on real audio of her final recorded calls to the Palestine Red Crescent Society and the efforts of its volunteers to save her life.  
Plus all the usual top quality nonsense on all things film-related and beyond, and your emergency mails of course. Thanks for listening!  

Timecodes with YT clip codes (for Vanguardistas listening ad-free) 

0:00 start
 
09:55 Rental Family review 
 
17:23  Box Office Top 10 
 
44:30   Jack O’Connell interview 
 
59:15    28 Years Later: The Bone Temple review 
 
1:15:14 Laughter Lift 
 
 

You can contact the show by emailing correspondence@kermodeandmayo.com or you can find us on social media, @KermodeandMayo 

Please take our survey and help shape the future of our show: https://www.kermodeandmayo.com/survey  

EXCLUSIVE NordVPN Deal ➼ https://nordvpn.com/take Try it risk-free now with a 30-day money-back guarantee! 

A Sony Music Entertainment production.     

Find more great podcasts from Sony Music Entertainment at sonymusic.com/podcasts and follow us @sonypodcasts   

To advertise on this show contact: podcastadsales@sonymusic.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>CHRIS LOWE - Production Designer</title><link>https://teamdeakins.libsyn.com/chris-lowe-production-designer</link><author></author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/teamdeakins/S2-176_Chris_Lowe_Final_Aputure-SPlea.mp3?dest-id=2018942" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.rogerdeakins.com/">Movies - Team Deakins</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[SEASON 2 - EPISODE 176 - Chris Lowe - Production DesignerIn this episode of the Team Deakins Podcast, we speak with production designer Chris Lowe (BOB MARLEY: ONE LOVE, THE LAST JEDI, IN BRUGES). We worked with Chris on SKYFALL, and we had a great time catching up with him. In addition to production design, Chris has had a long career as an art director, and he helps us understand how the two positions work together on any given project and what each one's responsibilities are. Throughout the episode, Chris also shares his strategies for communicating with directors and producers, creatively adapting to shifting budgets, and delegating duties to members of the art department. We also reflect on why and how the Shanghai skyscraper scene in SKYFALL pivoted from a location to a set, and Chris shares an episode of creative problem solving from THE LAST JEDI involving the Millennium Flacon, Yoda, and a tree. Plus, Chris reveals how he built Bangkok in Prague during the COVID-19 pandemic for THE GRAY MAN.This episode is sponsored by Aputure]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Josh Safdie &amp; Sean Baker | The A24 Podcast</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aPY7bhPj_08</link><author>A24</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/aPY7bhPj_08?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 21:29:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLpd1itfTDtaVLCrM6OgjyE7TY_CwUnnGE">Movies - A24 Podcast</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[SUBSCRIBE: http://bit.ly/A24subscribe

Award-winning filmmakers Josh Safdie and Sean Baker discuss their craft, collaborators and MARTY SUPREME (which Sean has now seen 3x in theaters). 

Topics covered include:
Voice memos as audio documentaries, the difficulty of keeping things small, Sean seeing Marty Supreme three times in theaters, maximalist territory, swimming in bigger lakes, moviemaking as time travel, Jack Fisk set stories, directors’ knee health, Jennifer Venditti’s wildly original casting process, feeling afraid of the script, Sean perfectly timing his edible intake at the Oscars, Darius Khondji as the “Prince of Darkness,” hunting down period accurate Cinemascope lenses, Ronnie Bronstein’s love of Shark Tank, and Marty Supreme’s epic alternate ending.

------

ABOUT A24:
The studio behind EVERYTHING EVERYWHERE ALL AT ONCE, UNCUT GEMS, MIDSOMMAR, MOONLIGHT, BEEF on Netflix, EUPHORIA on Max & more.

Coming Soon: EDDINGTON, THE SMASHING MACHINE, MARTY SUPREME & more

Subscribe to A24's NEWSLETTER:  http://bit.ly/A24signup
Sign up for A24 MEMBERSHIP: aaa24.com
Visit A24 WEBSITE: http://bit.ly/A24filmsdotcom
Like A24 on FACEBOOK: http://bit.ly/FBA24
Follow A24 on TWITTER: http://bit.ly/TweetA24
Follow A24 on INSTAGRAM: http://bit.ly/InstaA24]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Jafar Panahi’s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SqH9WnGf-ns</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/SqH9WnGf-ns?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 20:22:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The writer and director talks about the impact that Vittorio De Sica’s BICYCLE THIEVES has had on his life and how seeing it for the first time revealed the kind of cinema he wanted to make himself.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Lav Diaz’s Closet Picks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wuWY9CPr2hI</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wuWY9CPr2hI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 9 Jan 2026 18:50:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The writer and director of MAGELLAN praises the use of silence and space in LE SAMOURAÏ, talks about how Mike Leigh and Kenji Mizoguchi explore the human condition in their films, and selects his good friend Béla Tarr's WERCKMEISTER HARMONIES.

MAGELLAN opens in theaters today! Head here for tickets and see showtimes: https://bit.ly/49gRZAE]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The best/worst dad jokes from the Laughter Lift 09/01/2026</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fHhpSALuIm0</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/fHhpSALuIm0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 9 Jan 2026 00:01:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark Kermode and Simon Mayo

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Giant</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cB6MKYSfXZo</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/cB6MKYSfXZo?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 9 Jan 2026 00:01:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Inspired by the real-life story of Prince Naseem "Naz" Hamed, a British-Yemeni boxer, and his journey from humble beginnings to becoming a world champion and his training under Brendan Ingle, who played a crucial role in his success.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Becoming Victoria Wood</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-yiXHmbK4BM</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-yiXHmbK4BM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 9 Jan 2026 00:01:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Told in her own words and through the voices of those who knew her best, the film uncovers the formative experiences and personal battles that powered Victoria’s unmatched ability to make the nation laugh.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>09/01/2026 Box Office Top Ten</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9r1Kp31qViI</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9r1Kp31qViI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 9 Jan 2026 00:01:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

Mark and Simon Mayo run through this week's box office top 10…

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mark Kermode reviews Hamnet</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mGuG4iG0zFE</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/mGuG4iG0zFE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 9 Jan 2026 00:01:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[#MarkKermode #SimonMayo #FilmReviews

After losing their son Hamnet to plague, Agnes and William Shakespeare grapple with grief in 16th-century England. A healer, Agnes must find strength to care for her surviving children while processing her devastating loss.

To hear more, follow Kermode and Mayo's Take wherever you get your podcasts: https://podfollow.com/1616559297]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>FULL SHOW: Does HAMNET deserve the hype?</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CGyS-vEZujI</link><author>Kermode and Mayo&apos;s Take</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/CGyS-vEZujI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 8 Jan 2026 12:00:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCErmMCK1sHF-kCtyHpuSXtQ">Movies - Kermode</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Some exciting news—The Take is now on Patreon: www.patreon.com/kermodeandmayo.  Become a Vanguardista or an Ultra Vanguardista to get video episodes of Take Two every week, plus member‑only chat rooms, polls and submissions to influence the show, behind‑the‑scenes photos and videos, the monthly Redactor’s Roundup newsletter, and access to a new fortnightly LIVE show—a raucous, unfiltered lunchtime special with the Good Doctors, new features, and live chat so you can heckle, vote, and have your questions read out in real time.  
It’s a New Year’s correspondence special this week on the Take. Simon and Mark will be breaking open our bursting postbag and cracking into your excellent emergency mails from across the holiday period. We’ll be hearing your top takes on the films that made your festive breaks—and one repentant confession from the poor soul who made the mistake of watching The Lighthouse with their granny...   
We’ve got reviews of the freshest films from 2026’s first week too. First up it’s Becoming Victoria Wood, a documentary looking for the true personality behind the comedy persona of the national treasure. Plus you’ll hear Mark’s verdict on the new British boxing drama GIANT—which follows the true story of ring star Naseem Hamed (Amir El-Masry) and his fractious relationship with trainer Brendan Ingle, played by Pierce Brosnan.  
Not forgetting the much-anticipated Hamnet—the Chloé Zhao-directed biopic of William Shakespeare and his family during a period of personal turmoil and tragedy—based on Maggie O’Farrell’s bestselling novel.  It’s already tipped for awards success—especially for lead performances by Jessie Buckley and Paul Mescal—but do the Good Doctors believe the hype? 

Timecodes with YT clip codes (for Vanguardistas listening ad-free) 

 
Becoming Victoria Wood review – 15:00
BO10 – 31:11
Hamnet review – 55:25
Laughter Lift – 1:10:25
GIANT review – 1:13:50
 

 

You can contact the show by emailing correspondence@kermodeandmayo.com or you can find us on social media, @KermodeandMayo 

Please take our survey and help shape the future of our show: https://www.kermodeandmayo.com/survey  

EXCLUSIVE NordVPN Deal ➼ https://nordvpn.com/take Try it risk-free now with a 30-day money-back guarantee! 

A Sony Music Entertainment production.     

Find more great podcasts from Sony Music Entertainment at sonymusic.com/podcasts and follow us @sonypodcasts   

To advertise on this show contact: podcastadsales@sonymusic.com]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We ❤️ Jim Jarmusch | Closet Picks Edition</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/ATn7YObIedU</link><author>CRITERION</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ATn7YObIedU?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 7 Jan 2026 19:19:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PL7D89754A5DAD1E8E">Movies - Criterion</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[With a 4K edition of DEAD MAN (1995) entering the Criterion Collection and FATHER MOTHER SISTER BROTHER now in cinemas, we look back on the Closet guests who have picked works by Jim Jarmusch, titan of American independent filmmaking.

The films selected here are all available from criterion.com, on 4K, Blu-ray, and DVD: https://www.criterion.com/shop/collection/656-jim-jarmusch]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Half in the Bag: End of 2025 Catch-up (part 2)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0ALpFFlGzn4</link><author>RedLetterMedia</author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0ALpFFlGzn4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 7 Jan 2026 18:38:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrTNhL_yO3tPTdQ5XgmmWjA">Movies - RedLetterMedia</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[(00:00) Keeper and Together
(5:30) Five Nights at Freddy's 2
(16:37) If I Had Legs I'd Kick You
(26:28) Eddington
(27:27) IT: Welcome to Derry
(30:28) What R Next? and Star Trek: Starfleet Academy]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>EMBETH DAVIDTZ - Actor / Director</title><link>https://teamdeakins.libsyn.com/embeth-davidtz-actor-director</link><author></author><category>movies</category><enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/teamdeakins/S2-175_Embeth_Davidtz_Final_Aputure-SPlea.mp3?dest-id=2018942" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 7 Jan 2026 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.rogerdeakins.com/">Movies - Team Deakins</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[SEASON 2 - EPISODE 175 - Embeth Davidtz - Actor / DirectorIn this episode, of the Team Deakins Podcast, we speak with actor and director Embeth Davidtz (DON'T LETS GO TO THE DOGS TONIGHT, MAD MEN, SCHINDLER'S LIST). Embeth's directorial debut, DON'T LETS GO TO THE DOGS TONIGHT (an adaptation of the book of the same name written by Alexandra Fuller), is one of our favourite films from this past year, and we spend most of our conversation learning how Embeth pulled it off. The film is centered around the experiences of a young white child living in Zimbabwe at the end of the Rhodesian Bush War, and Embeth shares how her own childhood memories of South Africa's Apartheid influenced her telling of the story. Among many topics, we discuss: the film's effective use of voiceover, Embeth's approach to directing the lead child actress, managing a monkey break-in on location, the deceptive allure of the Steadicam, how the movie was financed, and whether or not she considered changing the title. We also reflect on the challenges of navigating a career in the entertainment industry, and we learn what Embeth has planned next.Recommended viewing: DON'T LETS GO TO THE DOGS TONIGHTThis episode is sponsored by Aputure]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>